<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><description>I am Amitabh Bachchan</description><title>Amitabh Bachchan's Official Blog</title><generator>Tumblr (3.0; @srbachchan)</generator><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/</link><item><title>DAY 2034</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai               Nov 9,  2013               Sat 7&amp;#160;: 03 PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back from the clime, from the leisure of sanctimonious solitude, from the stillness of silence, from gentle green pastures, churches, temples, palms, vacant drives &amp;#8230; into the hustle and bustle of the cityopolis&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A moment here and travel again to the nostalgia of another - Kolkata&amp;#160;! The opening of the International Film Festival there and the attachment of the several formative years spent in the early 60&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But more of that later .. perhaps after it is all over ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now the promised event at Goa in pictures &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/ff16ccfa1c58f81fc9c6e57e6adf4dec/tumblr_inline_mw00r5ts1m1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/edbd0931a08606333f623bd8f1911aeb/tumblr_inline_mw00rv3DGv1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/867bd843f018d35bcc130eccf93ceb82/tumblr_inline_mw00smJkxJ1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some talk of India and the fascination he had with the &amp;#8216;tika&amp;#8217; on my forehead and whether it was the same as the &amp;#8216;tika&amp;#8217; that married women wore in the parting of their hair &amp;#8230; his very attentive daughter, who was thrilled to be with the tigers in Ranthambore Game Park in Rajasthan ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/325028d08f7b7ad1ee3b7a3c900a211e/tumblr_inline_mw00tiOALY1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/fc65b59f3c1ae82321a53a2921f659bc/tumblr_inline_mw00v0l5bw1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/cd8bc03b3236c01a49bfe4f1c9c67839/tumblr_inline_mw00vhFajX1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/ebdae24f91b9136d26be0f994dea879e/tumblr_inline_mw00w9jSZH1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/8ae5e59133f3f216e96db63599a44aa8/tumblr_inline_mw00wuI3PY1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/68578668e989c8fc319e338b088b7cd6/tumblr_inline_mw00xgNFP51rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;quite a collection this .. the one in the black hat Tarun Tejpal the owner of Tehelka and the organiser of THINK .. to his right the lady in the printed dress is the wife of the great writer Dr V S Naipaul, Nobel Prize winner for Literature, who is seen in grey hair in the reflection along with Farhan Akhtar, Ram Jethmalani the prominent legal brain of the country, Rakesh Mehra director of &amp;#8216;Bhaag Milkha Bhaag&amp;#8217;, Kunal Kohli &amp;#8230; and in the reflection too, barely visible His Highness the Maharaja of Jodhpur, Baapji, as he is fondly called .. on mobile, over the shoulder of Tarun ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/b7926b3cbda37d93e610e667a0a7b334/tumblr_inline_mw02b88caP1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert De Niro in the house .. right in front of the picture, grey hair, hat in hand ..on the edge of the room &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/7dd08d8a2c54a68cd5de3cab635dc552/tumblr_inline_mw02byXj3h1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8060af565d411ca9d839676e04b17149/tumblr_inline_mw02ckNkyn1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8bfb35c96f24feb38b608d3b44c47d0d/tumblr_inline_mw02d6C8Kw1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sunset over the palms ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/41988801e442bc46e1baff710c686d02/tumblr_inline_mw02dsJL9R1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/6580c15deaf2ea6e4bcb7a678496b4f3/tumblr_inline_mw02eplVQw1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;live Twitter being broadcast at the venue &amp;#8230; awkward with all the accolades&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/99ef94f402a1c09639db38e3c6ef1c2b/tumblr_inline_mw02f7oz5S1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8c261c973b912d602c89a9e3c44740d0/tumblr_inline_mw02h7iYZM1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the plane coming in to Goa, my niece Naina sees a unique opportunity as I read the morning papers &amp;#8230; I had not realised what lay behind .. errmm &amp;#8230; needs straightening ..&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My love as ever ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mw02poLK8b1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66464881160</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66464881160</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 19:55:53 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2033</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goa, Goa               Nov 9, 2013              Fri  11:39 PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raman Jetly  for the 9th of November a very happy birthday .. love and happiness always ..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an air of expectancy, of liberation, of cares that need to be left behind, of siesta and the warmth of the sun, of endless beaches roamed carefree, of friendly acquaintance, of music and song, of the breeze that invigorates, of the delight of morsels of the most delightful pallets at quaint eateries, of solace and setting sun and the joy of just being there ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOA&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legacy of the Portuguese .. the architecture and history of their occupation, the emergence of the local and the Goan tongue, Konkan language and dialect and the presence of a nature which endears one to this region &amp;#8230; not just one but many &amp;#8216;one&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8217; from all parts of the world &amp;#8230; this little haven of tranquility &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the THINK Fest that brings me here on invitation. An annual event which brings together many of the trusted and the learned, to share, to express their ideas and thoughts with those that travel from across the globe as audiences, including tonight at my discourse a certain Mr D&amp;#8217;Niro of such universal fame that it was a moment of immense pride to find him seated before me &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A relaxed Robert D&amp;#8217;Niro of so many distinguished films and characters that he played in his illustrious career, and still continues to do so, simple and down to earth, accommodating and friendly &amp;#8230; a joy and honor to meet him and spend some time with him privately &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many from the fraternity that attend too and it is then that we spend time later in happy banter with local dear friends .. to laugh to discuss, to sing and listen to sonorous thoughts in poetry and verse of both languages &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One desires more time &amp;#8230; here &amp;#8230; to just be by the self &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remo, that most talented son of the soil, entertains us on stage later among a rambunctious crowd of people who seek to be pictured for posterity in framed photographs &amp;#8230; the enthusiasm is infectious and many get carried away, as do the organisers who hastily bundle me off to cooler and calmer climes .. into resting room and bed &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would all love for that to happen &amp;#8230; early to bed .. is it not&amp;#160;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily so do I ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvyjt4NdYt1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66386699754</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66386699754</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 00:09:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2032(i)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai              Nov 7/8,  2013               Thu/Fri  2&amp;#160;: 09 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/2da05ca16022987ba137e6541999214f/tumblr_inline_mvwur5KbdB1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/62074c7092e8224015bf95a7e44dbe9f/tumblr_inline_mvwurzdkFP1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked to do an interview for a trade magazine this is how it went&amp;#160;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;First of all yours has been an extraordinary journey up till here. We all see your journey as the most inspiring one ever seen. How do you yourself, view your journey from the time you started till now? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; I cannot endorse your opinion on my journey being extraordinary and least of all, being the most inspiring ever seen. There are many more greater and extremely extraordinary inspiring individuals, whose contribution and commitment to the art of entertainment has been immense. My own journey has been one that has been blessed by the upbringing I received from my parents – a subtle mix of both the West and the East, the opportunities that fortune gave me and the affection of those that came aboard as well wishers. But above all else it has been the benevolence of the Almighty that kept me going&amp;#160;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 2. You have worked with very successful and great directors. Who had the most influence on you as a person and as an actor? Which director made you feel that extracted the best out of you and made you do roles beyond your expectations? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; All my directors have contributed to my stay in this world of cinema. It was they that molded me into what they desired, and what the public eventually saw. I have been lucky and fortunate that I was given an opportunity to be guided and chosen by them. Writers, directors, producers, music directors, technicians, and the hundreds of those that have worked tirelessly behind the screen unnoticed and unrecognized, have all been responsible towards me, in their most magnanimous and creative genius, with their contributions. I am eternally indebted to them and shall always hold them in utmost respect. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 3. Who do you miss more? Yash Chopra, Manmohan Desai, Prakash Mehra or Mukul Anand? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; Each one of these masters has challenged designed created exemplary moments in cinema for film in India. I was just happy and fortunate to have been providentially chosen by them to be a part of their majestic creations. Sadly they have all left us. Who do I miss more&amp;#160;? If you were to God forbid, lose several parts of your body, which would you miss the most&amp;#160;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 4. Had they ever discussed any dream project of theirs with you which you want to take further because every maker discusses something he has in his mind to be made in future with his favorite actor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; I doubt there would be many examples of director – actor relationships where there could never have been talk of several projects that they would have wanted to do together. I would not deny such moments with several of my directors, particularly with the ones you mention. I do not think it prudent to mention talk of those projects, and neither would I wish to dilute the efficacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; of those ideas, by even remotely wanting to take it further in their absence. If they have gone, I would wish their glorious ideas went with them as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 5. Do you feel any limitations with age or do you believe the best is still come?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; I presume you are referring to my age of 71 years, and the limitations it projects in the minds of prospective makers. This is life’s eventuality. One that needs to be understood and accepted. There shall be many projects conceived where an aged individual would never fit in. It would be quite a challenge if it were to be conceived&amp;#160;; just as much as, I would imagine, the challenge of a 21 year old being asked to play 71&amp;#160;!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 6. Can you please put some light on the TV series to be produced by AB Corp.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; The TV serial is being produced by Endemol. We have a small stake in it commercially. The serial is committed to Sony for its broadcast, and we hope to finish the entire shooting of it before the year ends. Anurag Kashyap is the overall creative director, along with his team of very dedicated and sincere assistants. I do not have the liberty to disclose its content, but I can say this that it is fiction based in India, and quite dramatic in its presentation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 7. Do you subscribe to the theory that the 30 years between 1950 to 1980 was the golden period in the 100 years of Indian Cinema or do you have another take on it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; You would have to give me sufficient reason in your belief that the period between 1950 to 1980 were the Golden Years of Indian Cinema, in its 100 year existence, before you ask me to comment on it. I would like to believe that each year has given enough reason in the glorification of film as a medium. There has always been a constant growth, irrespective of adverse circumstance around and about us. Let us laud each year and decade in its most valuable contribution, and let us acknowledge the presence of the new generation, which labors with most capable distinction, in propelling our Industry even further, in to the next hundred.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 8. If you were to do a remake or a sequel what film would you like to do, as a producer or as an actor? Which of your film you think deserves to be remade with modern technology?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; I would personally keep away from such effort, even though I know that I am guilty on one count in this regard. The beauty of reflecting on the limitations of technology many years after the making of a product, is an excitement that can never be replicated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; 9. Are you extremely selective in terms of scripts or directors?  We have heard that you have rejected more than 25 scripts in the past one year?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; ANS//&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; This notion is entirely untrue&amp;#160;! Yes I do look at a script that gives me some meat and challenge, and yes there is always a comfort in working with those you may have worked with before. But then even the ones that you are comfortable with now, did at one time be ‘first time’ &amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt; Thank you,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvwuu4L3vN1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66303457176</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66303457176</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 02:13:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>Thank you AALLLLLLLL … Its 7 MILLION plus !! On...</title><description>&lt;img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/5bb7542cd39bf3b3a85b10e1f8679ffb/tumblr_mvwc89q1Am1ry5nxvo1_500.jpg"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you AALLLLLLLL … Its 7 MILLION plus !! On twitter ..&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66276851588</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66276851588</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 19:30:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2032</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai            Nov  7,  2013             Thu  6&amp;#160;: 52 AM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gyanchand Garhwani &amp;amp; Rajib Mitra&amp;#8230; happy birthday for the 7th of November .. may all your wishes come true &amp;#8230; happiness and joy ever &amp;#8230; Enjoy &amp;#8230; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;‏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;At last after long a restful day so far .. one that began early but has been kind to me since .. there is of course much to catch up on and, much to be prepared for the coming travels ..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The chiming clock in the vicinity had been kept on silent for long, but today for some odd reason I switched the chimer on &amp;#8230; I had forgotten how important it is to be chimed to time &amp;#8230; leaves a sense of rhythm, of moments passing by, of the need to dedication of activity and to which degree &amp;#8230;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Elements so necessary in all of us ..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;More later &amp;#8230;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvwawfdyBU1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66275541502</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66275541502</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 19:01:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2031(i)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai             Nov 6, 2013             Thu  3:01 AM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/73596ef4a52134220f7931929176d3e6/tumblr_inline_mvv2ic0cPf1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile and the world and Ef smile with you, cry and you never cry alone with the Ef about you &amp;#8230; da danaaa&amp;#160;!!! Cute eh&amp;#160;??!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back after two episodes of the KBC in swing, and ready to go back again to do another two. The audience the masses the cheers and the appreciation does it to you. They used to ask Pandit Nehru, Independent India&amp;#8217;s first Prime Minister, how he managed to stay so fresh during electioneering even at the late hours of at times 2-3 am, having been on the road the entire day, and he had responded by saying that &amp;#8216;the cheers of the crowds waiting to hear him speak, wiped away all the fatigue&amp;#8217; &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not in the same bracket as Pt Nehru, but I think in a minuscule way I would tend to agree with his words. You have no idea what an enthused crowd can do to your system&amp;#160;! An unresponsive audience can do just the opposite, and many a times this has been experienced first hand by me. There have been times in life when I have appeared on stage for a concert, in the early years of my association with films, and a capacity hall of 2000 people would have just three individuals in the hall - one, a relative, the other two, ushers&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then you do Wembley Stadium in London with 60,000 screaming fans, or Giants Stadium, NJ, USA filled to the rafters to 70,000 and you never want to get off the stage &amp;#8230;&amp;#160;!! Indeed at the Giants Stadium concert it had been raining till almost 15 mins before the opening, and the organisers had wanted to go for a refund due weather conditions and cancel the show. But in my youthful bravado I told them even if there was to be one person in this vast enclosure, I would perform &amp;#8230; and perhaps the intent to give my best would have been the greatest too&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been many such incidents during the years. Not necessarily due similar circumstances, but the end results have always been the same. Get up, get rid of the circumstance, and do better than what was expected of you &amp;#8230;&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok &amp;#8230; too much self aggrandisement and self praise .. cut it out buddy&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work starts tomorrow morning early &amp;#8230; as in 7 am &amp;#8230; and the challenge of acknowledging the time factor and giving the best to ability, pervades. There is this streak in most humans .. that when faced with adversity, come out shining even brighter. I would wish to emulate that, or at least make an attempt to do so &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day after .. the 8th .. is the THINK Fest in Goa, and they invite me for a conversation with its leader and conceptualiser Tarun Tejpal, of Tehelka fame. This concept has grown in importance and stature through the years where prominent personalities from different walks of life, come along and participate in talks and discussions on topics that deal with every possible subject under the sun. The invitees have been drawn from all over the world and there has been great patronage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, on the 10th, is the Kolkata International Film Festival, which I shall be attending at the most kind invitation of the Chief Minister of Bengal, Honourable Mamata Bannerjee, once a member of Parliament during the time I was there for a short while, representing the same party. Now of course she has broken away from the party, formed her own and came to power, by defeating the powerful Communist Party that ruled Bengal for several years. Last year too she had invited me, and we had all gone together to a glittering function at the Netaji Subhash Stadium, details of that visit had been posted on my Blog last year - Shahrukh and Katrina and Anushka were there too promoting their film &amp;#8216;Jab tak hai Jaan&amp;#8217;, Shahrukh of course being the brand ambassador of Bengal ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KBC is coming to its season end and there are just three more episodes to go before the end .. always a bit nostalgic and sad to stop the work that has occupied your mind and body for so many months. But .. film and Tv serial work shall take over &amp;#8230; &amp;#8216;Bhootnath Returns&amp;#8217; has begun its shoot, and it shall now have priority of work, along with the Tv serial shoot. Most of the other projects - films with R Balki, Shoojit Sircar, Vidhu Vinod Chopra, Sujoy Ghosh, Anuraag Kashyap, Vipul Shah, Abbas Mastan and others have been through those initial discussions and until they start or have been able to deliver firm schedules, it would not be prudent to say any more ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now do I get permission to leave ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/57738fd094d3c0ae413964fdff76fa52/tumblr_inline_mvv4cxUhsg1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bebo, Kareena Kapoor and Imran Khan on set with me at KBC .. came in for the promotion of their film &amp;#8221; Gori tere pyaar mein &amp;#8221; &amp;#8230; cute&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaking a leg with them too on &amp;#8216;Chingam Chabake&amp;#8217; ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/46ba7708a7c25483c0e1c55d0af53ce4/tumblr_inline_mvv4hqWADV1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hah ah haha &amp;#8230; can never match the steps that today&amp;#8217;s generation moves to &amp;#8230; but nice to be able to stand alongside them and watch in wonder ..&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My love ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvv4kkkFWf1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan &lt;/strong&gt;at 4 am&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66219704911</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66219704911</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 03:47:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2031</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YRF Studio, Mumbai        Nov 6, 2013          Wed 10:42 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/e3503684202aeac37f37d224b7bd2b76/tumblr_inline_mvttg9LdJd1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birthday greetings for Lakshmi Jag, though belated, for the 4th of November. Happiness and fulfilment ever. I did send them to you in a response on Twitter, but something has gone wrong. My regrets and apologies. We all love you much and have immense regard. Have a beautiful year and years ahead &amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Also Vishan Lal ji &amp;#8230; birthday greetings for the 1st of November .. its never too late to send you wishes for a bright and prosperous year ahead .. love from all of us ..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At YRF Studio for 2 episodes of KBC .. gruelling always, but work needs to be done, so am at it .. back pain and all ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you later at night ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvttj3HIUx1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66163831608</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66163831608</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 10:51:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2030</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai            Nov 5/6,  2013           Tue/Wed  1&amp;#160;: 13 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An overestimated creation by the Kankana .. BIG B Rocks&amp;#160;??? Naaah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/eb7fbf610364f101c654668f4226f5a4/tumblr_inline_mvt3t3DZgc1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Bhai dooj' today or as it is called in some parts of the country 'Bhau beej' .. a day for the sisters to remember their brothers, in prayer and love and protection ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such beautiful traditions structured by the human, and such disrespect to it when we learn of the atrocities against women, the imbalances in society towards them and their degradation .. simply unacceptable to me to society and to community at large&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A day of relaxed indulgence .. of clearing up the desk and its over burdened surroundings, of responding to the wishes and the greetings from friends and well wishers, from the Ef, from the sets of the contestants at KBC &amp;#8230; such a warm feeling of attachment and gratitude&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Ef that accompany me to destinations, that shower me with all the love you carry for me, and for the constant belief in our association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CD release tonight of three of the most prominent ghazal singers of the country - Anoop Jalota, Pankaj Uddas, Talat Aziz - called Destiny and a warm and pleasant evening of not too long a dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was Rajdeep Sardesai and his programme that he puts together on Sachin Tendulkar, Thank you Sachin &amp;#8230; an interview that he commends to this great son of India&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what a coincidence that as we record in a suburban Hotel, a message from Sachin on my mobile to come over to celebrate his last day in Test Cricket ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow KBC beckons .. these are coming on to the last days for this season, and there is always a sense of nostalgia and a missing that each such moment compels upon you &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon too is the THINK fest in Goa, where they invite me to speak .. intellectually&amp;#160;! But intellect and me do not go together .. so I wonder what it shall be ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But greater wonder a few days after that, when we get invited to the Kolkata International Film Festival again .. always a joy to be back in Cal, as we would address it in those heady days of 1962- 1969 &amp;#8230; the freedom of existence, of liberty to do and behave the way we wanted to, of excesses and theatre and the restaurant hopping on the famed Park Street &amp;#8230; &amp;#8216;those were the days my friend&amp;#8217; .. and the Beatles and so many more such &amp;#8230; unforgettable impressions ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I retire now ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my love to all and again a most prosperous Diwali and New Year ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvt3qcIiGS1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66114549903</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66114549903</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 01:36:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2029</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai           Nov 4/5, 2013            Mon/Tue  12:43 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear me &amp;#8230; I was so keen to write extensively, but the early morning sleep deficit invites me back to bed .. some bad habits never leave ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &amp;#8230; just a few impressions to keep you engaged till I see you all again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/9bb71060e60817d71c87e773c9cedad4/tumblr_inline_mvr888JZJa1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/63b37975f0b54ca37d35965c2aa8e814/tumblr_inline_mvr88oRIT21rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Sunday well wishers and how they wait till it is dark and then the lights come on after the Lakshmi Pooja ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/de624db76fc5953862aada084fa110b2/tumblr_inline_mvr8977fVk1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the prayers done at Prateeksha, and then after some bonus to the staff, and a round of firecrackers &amp;#8230; as the hemisphere lights up ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8c0d2ce32948f30a50657fdca4f57e67/tumblr_inline_mvr89nTefJ1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And at the end of the day a little time for contemplation and thought &amp;#8230; all is never to your satisfaction and desire ever .. there shall be moments to ponder and think what and when and where ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More of all this tomorrow ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and love ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvr8hf72xY1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66017469841</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/66017469841</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 01:21:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2028</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai              Nov 3/4, 2013             Sun/Mon  6 :53 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is quite normal for all the Ef to jump up in great anger as they witness the time of the Blog, but dear ones, it was Diwali and having the guests over for the &amp;#8216;shagun&amp;#8217; and dinner and the evening prayers, and the Sunday well wishers, did become somewhat time consuming ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the joy of course was the coming over of the entire fraternity in their traditional best to bring in the greetings, to join in with us at the house and spend this large amount of time in the glory and the warmth of the festival in celebration. I have just come away at this early hour of the morning to keep up my commitment for the Ef, irrespective of the time for I truly believe there is nothing compelling on me for my time when it comes to communication with the Ef ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really it was wonderful to see all, from ShahRukh to Katrina to Anushka to Ranbir and everyone, all .. relaxed and in comfort of the auspicious moment, in the comfort of each other, of their laughter and camaraderie ..  a warmth in my heart &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must to bed for I work in a few hours &amp;#8230; and then when it is over I shall return and give a more detailed coverage of the day and the evening and the pictures too &amp;#8230; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A most prosperous Diwali again to all .. and Good Night for the 3rd and Good morning for the 4th ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My love &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvptw95GNS1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65953605516</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65953605516</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 07:08:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2027</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai              Nov 2, 2013               Sat  11: 42 PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, all that matters is what you make or believe to be what you determine. Your deeds may be filled with fault and error, disrespect and dishonesty, but eventually you know inside what was right and what wrong. That then is the best judge and the best guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many come during the course of the day by your side, filled with immense respect and emotion. There is admiration and healthy vocal compliment. Such that would drive any sane person to believing in himself or herself as close to divinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rightly perhaps there would be reason enough for them to suppose so. To trust the belief that springs from others. But what really is your own opinion&amp;#160;? For that then shall form the truest form of your own assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are though dampeners to such occurrence. You could be the most loved respected and admired individual outside, in the world of the world, but left within the confines of yourself you could be one that is the worst disrespected, not worthy of any at all and perhaps hated the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that really is the challenge of our times for those that attain recognition and worth through their own means and efforts. Those that respect this achievement need to be recognised and applauded. Those that do not, need to be set free from deliberate and mandatory renown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your own renown is unmentioned within you - let the outside world say what they wish - it is for me the most powerful achievement of a human .. not just because you know that it exists, but that you know that it is right&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diwali comes in tomorrow and the lights in every home beckon the Goddess of wealth, Lakshmi, to enter their homes and bless them, that reside within, to greater prosperity and glory &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May such be the endeavour of each of our Ef .. may such be the demeanour of the Goddess in your own lives and homes &amp;#8230; nothing could give me greater pleasure if this were to fructify ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my love and with my greetings for all for this festival of lights ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mvnfq1s0OI1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65809737953</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65809737953</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:32:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>दिवाली की शुभकामनाएं .. Happy Diwali Wishes !</title><description>&lt;iframe src="//www.tumblr.com/video/srbachchan/65762485524/400" id="tumblr_video_iframe_65762485524" class="tumblr_video_iframe" width="400" height="300" style="display:block;background-color:transparent;overflow:hidden;" allowTransparency="true" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="fbPhotosPhotoCaption" id="fbPhotoSnowliftCaption" data-ft='{"type":45,"tn":"*G"}'&gt;&lt;span class="fbPhotoSnowliftVideoTitle"&gt;दिवाली की शुभकामनाएं .. Happy Diwali Wishes !&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="hasCaption"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65762485524</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65762485524</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 10:52:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2026</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai                Nov 1/2,  2013                Fri/Sat  1&amp;#160;: 27 AM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the discomfort of the body &amp;#8230; when the camera rolls, the body rolls too .. I have just sufficient time to do just this for today .. but hopefully more will follow soon &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/73cf6f9cecb9de2d2b86aa0f0dbce6c3/tumblr_inline_mvlozz7kgr1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/623ccdd4bc7f41c901fc6d2649e9f2f1/tumblr_inline_mvlp0lZ0YZ1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/b0f0965899c0b67985d783797ccf7e70/tumblr_inline_mvlp12T4411rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/3f11487ef86f4775a082085fab37efd9/tumblr_inline_mvlp1isDXQ1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/17a2bac0ed66c9f1735ffe3f92ada175/tumblr_inline_mvlp229WTz1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/e3bb0bb71e3713397ba43a2a685b9e75/tumblr_inline_mvlp2k0UmX1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/0bd64f362f56a5e2ea3e5bd6656953ff/tumblr_inline_mvlp30jDZk1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/c69f5f021fb8a61f82389df1ed2ebb34/tumblr_inline_mvlp45tg1b1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/612a74dc5afacb6003e7fc01f125830c/tumblr_inline_mvlp4ni9w51rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/973319afbd1733d9a0b26e9f8a0f123b/tumblr_inline_mvlp5eDd6L1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4e4c9ade3304ef4fce5459129ba04370/tumblr_inline_mvlp5xNBgS1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats the day for me at a shoot for a small appearance in a film being made by Sanjay Dutt &amp;#8230; a gesture to be alongside him in his hour of trying times ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for the greetings for Aishwarya on her birthday &amp;#8230; It is warmly reciprocated with affection ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love you all &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvlpa5aRLU1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65716357944</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65716357944</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 01:38:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2025</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Location/Tv Serial Shoot, Mumbai    Oct 31, 2013   Thu 6:34 Pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vaijayanti  Ravindra Damle  &amp;#8230; celebrates her birthday on Nov 1, 2013 and we wish her a most prosperous year and years to come ..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai           Oct 31/Nov 1, 2013           Fri  1:15 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The desperate attempts to make me look 20 years younger for the sequence at the shoot, was hilarious .. to say the least&amp;#160;!! How conveniently easy it is to age rapidly, but how inconveniently long it takes to push time back ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After several attempts the results&amp;#160;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/964fb07203c145f1652ee05e0388e194/tumblr_inline_mvjtpduZV01rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now that all have carefully suppressed their giggles and snide asides, it is time for me to seek my time with the pillow ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May I assure you ladies and gentlemen of the jury, that there shall be opportunity for greater stifled laughs by the morrow, when thou shall be subjected to many more examples of my idiocy ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am seeking the elixir of youth, I need to do some basics&amp;#160;: sticking to routine and regimen &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh&amp;#160;! And I almost forgot &amp;#8230; the TUBE was somewhat satisfactory &amp;#8230; somewhat, because the damages of the last visit seemed improved, though there are some permanent reasons for concern ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My love ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvju0haAD71rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65633525779</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65633525779</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 01:26:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2024</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai              Oct 30,  2013              Wed 11:58 PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/3f508e0e8c64793152f089c2a4b9aa11/tumblr_inline_mvhwhjE2q31rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am restricted in movement. And therefore restricted in my write, in my affection and in my conversation in many days with them that speak to me each day. I am restricted in my apology, for apology can never fill the void of absence. I am restricted then and remain so ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the mind is not clear .. if it be not tuned to itself, but to the disturbance caused by elements that take pleasure only in its destruction, then there is reason to be cryptic and short and less expansive .. others may not, but I am not others and shall exercise my rights &amp;#8230; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is never healthy to purge .. respect and your own ethics do their utmost within, to stop and prevent you from damage &amp;#8230; for damage it is .. expounding continuously at matters that bear no respect for condition and cause ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you think of the other, you ease within your own. If you shall drive in the wrong lane or not give sufficient space to the other vehicle, we shall both remain stuck as it were in dense traffic, without moving .. give space to the other, to move to clear the region and the traffic moves with speed and ease &amp;#8230; be adamant, filled with unnecessary ego and adamant composure, and be sure that it shall rob you physically of strength, diminish your power of reason, and leave you with nothing but a distressed signal the entire day ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why ever endeavour to get to a place to withdraw &amp;#8230; what gains shall come your way .. no gains is wrong .. what does one achieve in self destruction .. eating pie is enjoyable ..  humble pie &amp;#8230;&amp;#160;? I wonder ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My love &amp;#8230; to all .. not in concern &amp;#8230; but entirely in understanding ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvhx9kfOnI1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65541384835</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65541384835</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:40:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2023</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai             Oct 29, 2013             Tue 11:49&amp;#160;pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;मंगल भवन अमंगल हारी , द्रवहु सु दसरथ अजिर बिहारी  &amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few shall ever be able to ascertain or even attempt to decipher, what goes on in the minds of those just before they create, perform, enact ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fewer shall ever be able to ascertain or even attempt to decipher, what goes on in the minds of those that are quite unnecessarily taken away from the process of their creativity, by acts baser and completely without context to the evolution at hand &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ones sees and what one does not see is the difference from being normally human to inhumanly normal .. that speech, the delivery, that constant effort to keep attracted with the viewer at hand and at distant hand, the smile of approval or that disapproval of response, the enthusiasm of energy and commitment &amp;#8230; all of this and more, is what reality describes to be one, bestowed with extraordinary creative and conveying skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There shall be many examples that one could search. And there could be many examples that one identifies instantly with, but the factor that encourages and confirms status and dignity, is the factor that you exercise within &amp;#8230; either through restraint, the more mature and dignified - or the more obtuse, self centered and selfish ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both kinds exist &amp;#8230; both perhaps in an abundant number &amp;#8230; but the one that shall require safety and ethics is the former. Abuse entertained and expressed, damages your own body and mind. These are difficult eruptions to give immediate reaction to. They may too not have sufficient ground for expression or reaction, but patience never went wrong ever ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;" beware the fury of a patient man &amp;#8216;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outer shell of deception is a worthwhile asset. That inner wrath contained, eliminates all parameters of angered breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shall take them many lifetimes to truly understand or even practice a semblance of ethic decency &amp;#8230; but if inborn, it is the most wonderful gift of nature to anyone .. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile .. it disturbs the other ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/f948e7c9335236c1692ff701a73a31d9/tumblr_inline_mvg1gfZ6fp1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be indifferent to all else that reeks of poison &amp;#8230; leave it alone &amp;#8230; let it boil in its own stew&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/380e08ed415e21b2026ab0fe8a8b3409/tumblr_inline_mvg1imqvlL1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The older generation spent most of their time in prayer and in action towards it ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/0dfe26d21884ea5ea7e3836eea788e7a/tumblr_inline_mvg1khWCdD1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotating that special reverential religiosity in the incarnation of the bead necklace &amp;#8230; in constant prayer ..&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for now, the generation wears expressions much like this .. in constant conversation with the mobile and its conveyance through the short message service or what is  the &lt;em&gt;sms &amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/0a2922dcbcbb96ea8cb3a3e2a34571dc/tumblr_inline_mvg1tw5oV31rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave you and love you ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvg1v6GoZU1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65449348239</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65449348239</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:24:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2022</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai             Oct 28,  2013             Mon 10&amp;#160;: 28 PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Goveas birthday tomorrow Oct 29 th &amp;#8230; and we all wish him the best there is life .. happiness, fulfilment and the joy of company ..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p2"&gt;Rajiv Ranjan &amp;#8230; happy birthday for the 27th &amp;#8230; belated but filled with love &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;Tanek Ghantsala &amp;#8230; happy belated birthday for the 25 th &amp;#8230; love always&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;Vinod KD &amp;#8230; a very happy belated birthday for the 26th &amp;#8230; enjoy ..!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The race against routine &amp;#8230; against regimen &amp;#8230; depletes one of any enthusiasm that one wishes to show ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But the determination to get back into it, reassures one .. reassures the reason for survival, for effort even if results are not there .. and so one perseveres ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Despite strangulating schedules, it is important to concentrate on that which we decide should be of ultimate importance ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And what is of ultimate importance is the mind and the body. Lose that and lose life. Keep that in form and the rest of the world and its obstacles, shrivel up. Encouraged by persistent desire to shape up, there are activities which we undertake to indeed not fall short at any given time. The eyes and the opinions of others, is prime in our profession. Drop a level in them I feel, is the most lamentable act. To be constantly alive desired and perfect too is a call that can be insurmountable. But then effort would never have existed if we were to give in to such idiocies. Idiocies because .. they have the capacity to be repaired, but left unattended can and shall cause discomfort. Discomfort is discomforting for me - of any kind shape and size. A frayed temper, an unjust decision, a frequent disrobing of a foul tongue &amp;#8230; all cause an embarrassing pain .. mental albeit, but one, that can manifest itself to one that is physical &amp;#8230; and I often wonder where that expression &amp;#8216;a pain in the neck&amp;#8217; originated from&amp;#160;!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I want to be early .. I want to be compartmentalised &amp;#8230; I wish to be in the care of my structure that dresses me now &amp;#8230; and I wish to make it just that little more disciplined than before ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I must rest .. and &amp;#8230; must send to you my love and affection .. it is not a routine that I follow &amp;#8230; it contains ingredients that can never be siphoned off in a sieve ..&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/9a6f2ac59bb2e34bc45ea89224c202c8/tumblr_inline_mve6cmw22L1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mve6d9N6pk1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65353025618</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65353025618</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:07:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2021</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai             Oct 27,  2013             Sun  11&amp;#160;: 39 PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/d389c659dc2ebeb2c601a5a9207b6527/tumblr_inline_mvcepeZDKc1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/78e5f2f4d60bd56ff0a9fa7835f4c632/tumblr_inline_mvceq9Edhy1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/f5fc964ff61611319dbdda9b761e6bfc/tumblr_inline_mvceqptTv91rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the pain, despite the inconsistency, despite the &amp;#8216;aalasya&amp;#8217; - the lethargy of human, despite all else .. the push to gym, come what may .. bear it, struggle with it, allow it to tear into the body, scream out the music with effort .. and conclude with that something satisfaction of fighting an oddity&amp;#160;! The pain killers not withstanding, the body responds and eases some of the concerned areas, and there is a hidden joy in that, but the evidence of its occurrence reemerging does not fade away. Be that as it may, the following day there shall be effort again. Stubbornness &amp;#8230; yes&amp;#160;! At least in some respects, but the ultimate gain shall remain - of having continued even when there was no evidence of any prescribed continuity&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a day of rest that can or may be considered an achievement. Not of any great proportion, but of some value all the same. And it helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/0f1ee24d1e06249b33a6ec09b56dcdbc/tumblr_inline_mvcesgOihM1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A day filled with, among other, the fascination of image. Many of them in different styles and moods, angles, lenses and cameras. Followed by the Sunday meet, the meet for a film magazine in conversation with the young generation in representation by Ranveer, and finally a victory by Chelsea over ManCity .. pretty historic at Stamford Bridge, and Torres giving supreme example of why he is what he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The space in the room of my spend, the area which inspires &amp;#8230; nah &amp;#8230; that is a wrong word .. the area which brings me the solitude for the BlogTwitFBook, is now crammed. The contestants from #KBC bring along their spirit of competition, but also their spirit of giving. They hand make gifts by the dozens and I cannot simply put them away in disrespect. I store them, look at them, admire their affection and effort, respond to them. Yes .. some from the Ef smirk because their replies of my acknowledgement have not begun yet, but they shall &amp;#8230; in time ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with pending work is that if you delay they lay &amp;#8230; longer&amp;#160;! It is what most would educate us with, in life too. &amp;#8221; kaal kare so aaj kare &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;, the famous idiom springs out from the screen .. and a lesson which should have been learnt many moons ago, keeps reminding us. I shall make effort. I shall change. I shall repair. I shall endeavour&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These &amp;#8230; not just wasted words .. but examples to follow, to a better existence, a better being, a better tomorrow ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shall endeavour .. despite the odds &amp;#8230; something shall give ..&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/021bd1dd34590966dd2533b89d0a547c/tumblr_inline_mvceu6ljO71rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so embarrassing to sit by the side of the young and listen to them as being their inspiration and example to follow. No .. no &amp;#8230; no .. they must become examples themselves. I have been faulted so many times. There are many regions and areas which cannot be permitted to just fly by. They all need work to be done on them. It may take time, but never must one imagine the benefit of a secure tomorrow. Nothing is secure, nothing is settled .. it can all, in a moment of desperation disappear. Be wary of such situations &amp;#8230; just be wary, why wait for a situation, and there shall be the fruits of benefit to bear .. I believe so .. and I doubt many would tend to disagree with this ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/ae8169ba4565031e83eb2615d79875ba/tumblr_inline_mvceuywi8n1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to learn more the resilience of the self. Rely on the self, work out the self, conduct the self &amp;#8230; and ye shall get the best results .. others may come in to assist, to manage, to control &amp;#8230; but done in the self carries better result. That satisfaction is beyond all else &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I would like to believe &amp;#8230; and so I do ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My love to all &amp;#8230; and I do this on my own, for, then, it is the best &amp;#8230; of all&amp;#160;!! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvcccefsdQ1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65260945900</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65260945900</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 01:15:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2020</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai                Oct 26/27,  2013               Sat/ Sun  1&amp;#160;: 57 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/6e18cef3d85d8d8834440a5858076ff5/tumblr_inline_mvaoduD5lH1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is indeed the state of your mind &amp;#8230; the state you wish it to be &amp;#8230; the state which often threatens to deflate to defy and to disobey all that you may have wished to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wished a sincere day, one that would keep certain discipline and commitment .. of time and promise. And that was adhered to. Thank you mind. Thank you my thoughts. Thank you my demeanour. I enjoyed every moment of it. For, it kept its word, its regimen and its order&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work it was a smooth run. At the evening later it was chaotic in a good sense. And at the end of the day, it seemed satisfying and content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is bothersome to be content and satisfied. It can be a close associate of a vagrant, but in professionalism and its unified umbilical, satisfaction and contentment must never be entertained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is greater and even more recognition that comes my way. On set at #KBC the award ceremony I could not attend presented its reward among the audience at the game show. It wrote at the base of its stand the best for an anchor at a Tv show for #KBC. The show itself won for the best game broadcast on Indian Tv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looked somewhat this&amp;#160;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/b931176fabf54ae9ea6872db20641b8c/tumblr_inline_mvamxalXRi1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On set there was noble campaign and an effort of voluntary fashion to work on a social cause - &lt;strong&gt;Help to live up to 5. &lt;/strong&gt;Kajol, the lovely ebullient and fun filled best in the line, played to collect funds for helping out children that do not survive beyond the age of 5 yrs &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes there are certain concentrated areas in the country where a child before he reaches the age of 5 dies of diarrhoea, primarily because they do not maintain common but simple hygiene, like washing hands&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/f81d30049edf21898e367a529ab611f5/tumblr_inline_mvan96gg9H1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And during the show we worked on collecting funds, not just from the winnings of the game, but also utilised the moment to create an awareness of the problem - if it could be called that&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the line Ranvir Singh, the new generation artist, who has shown immense presence and performance from his very first film, dropped by to a greeting. We talk tomorrow for a film magazine in conversation with the old and the new generation and their thinking. He shall also be making presence at #KBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/9341fc8f5929065181ff2fa4f97391fb/tumblr_inline_mvao76aNPS1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then a truly proud moment .. a reward at the hands of the Nightingale Lata Mangeshkar ji for my contribution to cinema. A historic moment because they were felicitating 71 years of my life which coincided with 71 years of Lata ji&amp;#8217;s entry into film music and song. After a wait Lata ji called and excused herself from the function because she had suddenly taken ill. But &amp;#8230; the very thought of sharing the stage with her and then to receive this recognition from her hands, was in itself the greatest reward. An honour beyond all else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional head wear of respect, the shawl of reverence and the garland of flowers, along with the priests from SiddhiVinayak and their chants, to the glittering tray replicating the temple and 71 &amp;#8216;modaks&amp;#8217; the religiosity of its temperament on a beautifully decorated tray, were all filled with an emotion difficult to describe ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/2cabea5fd93768864f24d1ea4d487de8/tumblr_inline_mvanwrssCP1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/5c61c5ac7e5a557401ee7d5ab879ef7b/tumblr_inline_mvanxxuLC71rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The respect and the love of the people of the city, of the celebrated school where the function was held, were all a delight - a company that one could never ignore or forget&amp;#160;!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And tomorrow despite the medical condition all along .. a day of rest but filled with many engagements that shall be inevitable &amp;#8230; and hopefully pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was amidst all this of course the #KBC session and its wonders ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/6f9c75cd9dd87d2f4a624dbfa3679bed/tumblr_inline_mvao5vF6WW1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in a days&amp;#8217; work and all with the best smile forward &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must utilize the hours of rest that come my way suddenly &amp;#8230; for, tomorrow is another day &amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/4cd10c9a85cea1faf7fda0096d039ecc/tumblr_inline_mvaof4Qtkd1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amitabh Bachchan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65168763471</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65168763471</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 02:46:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><title>DAY 2019</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jalsa, Mumbai               Oct 25/26,  2013             Fri/Sat  12&amp;#160;: 50 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may will it. You may feel it. You may allow it to ride. But there shall forever be days when you wish you had invented a time stop watch, as one of the contestants on the Hot Seat of KBC desired, to be able to stop the world and say, you would like to get off it for just a while&amp;#160;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happens &amp;#8230; and happens to all of us on the odd days, and today was one such day. Despite the willing of a mental force within to keep driving, nothing moves the way you wish it to. So &amp;#8230; at the end of it all you merely wish that circumstances be permitted to take over, whilst you sat back and watched the world go by in all its temper and wish &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did .. and the results were abhorring. So you breathe and breathe long, put on the silencers to the voices within, sing a song, play a fake violin that strings sad notes and be silent. It works and &amp;#8230; works well&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, night rests, are becoming more and more essential and of immense value. I noticed that after practising what many in the Ef have been suggesting, demanding and pleading for. I stand in appreciation of it and value this unfaltering suggest. I must practice it more often .. and often and often &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/fef2c50494230c6742fffc419c246bfa/tumblr_inline_mv8p1xcxQH1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aamir Khan pays a visit to KBC .. and we talk of Dhoom 3 and the little boy wonder &amp;#8230; Kautilya Pandit .. he is barely over 5 yrs and has the rapid and correct answers to some of the most intriguing questions put to him ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knows the number of Galaxies in the universe and their complicated names. The furthest and nearest stars, the most to the least populated states in India and their correct population to the last digit. Prime Ministers of far off countries, which borders they touch, their names &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just an incredible child&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had him on KBC tonight and he was simply astounding ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/56d32d225f075b551dd9e8559368cc7b/tumblr_inline_mv8p9xPQi41rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/e9d155bd7cc5632fad8d84c725595c0a/tumblr_inline_mv8pb03D5E1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do not miss the exquisite &amp;#8216;bodi&amp;#8217; on the top of his shaven head. He designed it himself and when asked why, he said it was an old tradition .. so correct&amp;#160;!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kautilya Pandit is his name and his geography his politics and his general knowledge is astounding ..&amp;#160;!! What a time we had on set with him ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow its the lovely Kaajol on set playing for a cause, and then another award by Lata Mangeshkar&amp;#8217;s Father&amp;#8217;s Foundation, that honours both her and yours truly. Its 71 years of her presence in the Indian film Industry, and my 71 years of birth&amp;#160;!! Such a unique honour&amp;#160;!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love to all ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/36284c907979ba8e95c68b0825e1e142/tumblr_inline_mv8pkuEft91rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e6cbca7fc6a13400809aaaa3446e3e8/tumblr_inline_mv8plvLWzw1rr19uk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65066505046</link><guid>http://srbachchan.tumblr.com/post/65066505046</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 01:16:49 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
