<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
<channel>
<title>Engadget RSS Feed</title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com</link>
<description>Engadget</description>
<image>
<url>http://www.blogsmithmedia.com/www.engadget.com/media/feedlogo.gif</url>
<title>Engadget</title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com</link>
</image>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 AOL Inc. The contents of this feed are available for non-commercial use only.</copyright>
<generator>Blogsmith http://www.blogsmith.com/</generator><item>
<title><![CDATA[Reggie Watts admits he's an impulse tech buyer, but it's those digital interfaces that still need work]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/reggie-watts-expand-ny-2013/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/rwatts_thumbnail.jpg"/> When Reggie Watts took to the Expand stage, he was wearing a Pebble. The performer said that he's obsessed with the wearables and picked up multiples of the wearable during those early adopter deal days. "If it's something I'm curious about, [something} that provides a service or that I'm interested ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/reggie-watts-expand-ny-2013/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mat Smith]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Here are your five Insert Coin finalists, cast your vote now!]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/insert-coin-finalists/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2012/12/eng-insert-coin-logo-article-1356645135_thumbnail.png"/> It's been a long day of demos, tough questions and talking to potential consumers for our Insert Coin competitors. But the judges and readers have spoken, and we have our five finalists. My Bell, DI Wire, GrowCubes, Smart Power Strip and BlinkScan will be moving on to the next round where they'll be ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/insert-coin-finalists/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Terrence O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[The wearable dilemma: forming habits first, then building ecosystems]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/the-state-of-wearable-tech/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/wearable-tech-panel_thumbnail.jpg"/> "Getting people to want to wear things all the time -- whether it's on or off" is a huge stumbling block said Becky Stern, Director of Wearable Electronics at Adafruit. Sure, smartwatches and activity trackers are becoming increasingly more visible in the tech space, but mainstream adoption is still ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/the-state-of-wearable-tech/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Billy Steele]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 18:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Sony President Phil Molyneux with special guest Spike Lee]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/sony-panel/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/phil-molyneauz-lead-expand_thumbnail.jpg"/>Sony President Phil Molyneux joins us to discuss the company's role in the ever-expanding world of consumer electronics, with a little help from none other than director Spike Lee.

November 9, 2013 5:40:00 PM EST

Follow all of Engadget's Expand coverage live from New York City right here! ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/sony-panel/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 17:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Google's Timothy Jordan: Glass is a complete break from the past]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/timothy-jordan-on-google-glass/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/google-timothy-jordan-expand-ny-1_thumbnail.jpg"/> Many wonder whether Google Glass has legs as a technology. Will we still be using it (and talking about it) years from now? If you ask Google's Senior Developer Advocate Timothy Jordan, absolutely. Speaking at Expand in New York, he described the wearable eyepiece as a fundamental shift in user ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/timothy-jordan-on-google-glass/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Fingas]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 16:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Staying Green]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/green-panel/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/beth-ferguson_thumbnail.jpg"/> Green's been quite the buzzword in consumer electronics and other technologies over the past decade or so. Is it simply a fad, or will today's technologies truly help provide for a more sustainable future? Join panelists from Inhabitat, Voltaic and Sol Design Lab to find out where green tech is ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/green-panel/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 16:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[LeVar Burton on Google Glass: 'It disturbed me']]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/levar-burton-google-glass-expand-2013/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/adam/11e414d63bc08c7d3e98940820935547/-1_thumbnail.jpg"/> "It disturbed me. I was skeptical... [and] I'm a person that's very open to technology."

That's the reaction LeVar Burton, the man best known from Reading Rainbow and Star Trek: The Next Generation, first had when encountering Google Glass backstage at Engadget Expand. Burton, a self-described ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/levar-burton-google-glass-expand-2013/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Volpe]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 15:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Reggie Watts]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/watts-expand/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/reggie-watts-lead-expand_thumbnail.jpg"/> The musician/comedian/TV show co-host joins us on stage to discuss the role technology plays in his creative process. Watts will also be showing off his rig and demoing precisely what it is he does.

November 9, 2013 4:15:00 PM EST

Follow all of Engadget's Expand coverage live from New York City ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/watts-expand/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Pebble CEO Eric Migicovsky]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/pebble-panel/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/eric-pebble-lead_thumbnail.jpg"/> The age of the smartwatch, it seems, is upon us, thanks in no small part to the success of Pebble. What began life as a record-breaking Kickstarter success has grown into a wearable phenomenon. We sit down with the company's CEO to discuss Pebble's successes and where it goes from here.

November 9, ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/pebble-panel/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Russian cosmonauts take the Olympic torch for its first spacewalk ahead of Sochi games]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/russian-olympic-torch-relay-in-space/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/olympic-torch-spacewalk-cosmonaut_thumbnail.jpg"/> Russia has already made Olympic history and the Sochi games don't start until February. Earlier today, two cosmonauts took the ceremonial red and silver-clad torch for its first space relay ahead of the 2014 winter session. Torches were taken into space by astronauts in 1996 and 2000, but neither of ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/russian-olympic-torch-relay-in-space/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Billy Steele]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 15:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Pivothead's new video capture glasses let you mix and match power, storage and wireless add-ons]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/pivothead-smart-prototype/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/adam/5fa24eb2c5375c1ac1ab7dd1cb0ddffa/pinnacle_thumbnail.jpg"/> Pivothead's video-recording specs have undergone only a slight evolution since they launched early last year, gaining live broadcast abilities through the Air Sync add-on. Here at Expand NY, however, we've seen what's next, as the company's been kind enough to bring along a prototype of its next-gen ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/pivothead-smart-prototype/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jamie Rigg]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: All Dressed Up: the State of Wearable Technology]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/wearables-expand/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/becky-stern-expand-lead_thumbnail.jpg"/> Thanks to products like the Pebble Smart Watch and Google Glass, wearables are all the rage this year. We've pulled together a diverse group of companies from different aspects of the space -- including Adafruit, Narrative and Misfit -- to discuss where wearables are and where they're ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/wearables-expand/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 13:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Thinking Ahead: the Future of Consumer Electronics]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/future-panel/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/joi-ito-expand-lead_thumbnail.jpg"/> It's time to look ahead. We've enlisted MIT Media Lab Director Joichi Ito and iO9's Annalee Newitz to help us separate the fads from the future and predict what precisely is on the technological horizon.

November 9, 2013 2:00:00 PM EST

Follow all of Engadget's Expand coverage live from New York ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/future-panel/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: LeVar Burton]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/levar-burton-expand/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/levar-burton-expand-lead_thumbnail.jpg"/> For more than 20 years, LeVar Burton helped kids discover the magic of books through the beloved PBS show Reading Rainbow. Both Burton and the program have returned, albeit in a form more befitting of the early 21st century. The actor-turned-educator joins us on stage to discuss how technology can ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/levar-burton-expand/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 12:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Lunar elevators and asteroid mining: Kickstarting the next chapter of space exploration]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/moonshots-kickstarting-the-next-chapter-of-space-exploration/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/spacepost_thumbnail.jpg"/> Privately funded space missions might sound like the preserve of the financial elite, but the truth is actually a little more pedestrian. Speaking at Expand New York today, Michael Laine (LiftPort) and Chris Lewicki (Planetary Resources) both extolled the virtues of people power, and the critical ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/moonshots-kickstarting-the-next-chapter-of-space-exploration/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Trew]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 12:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[BT Sport steals Sky's crown jewel, gets exclusive rights to the Champions League in 2015]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/bt-sport-champions-league-deal/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/adam/f4bc8d63e606ec8f4716df2e116b6c3f/chelsea_thumbnail.jpg"/> Do you like to spend huge sums on Sky Sports just to catch the big moments in European football? Well, in the biggest thing to happen to UK broadcasting in years, BT Sport has outbid (by a considerable margin) both Sky and ITV for the exclusive rights to show both Champions and Europa League matches ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/bt-sport-champions-league-deal/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Cooper]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 12:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Google Glass Senior Developer Advocate Timothy Jordan]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/google-panel/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/timothy-jordan-expand-lead_thumbnail.jpg"/> Still got lots of questions about Google Glass? Yeah, us too. The wearable's Senior Product Advocate Timothy Jordan will be joining us on stage to discuss hardware as a platform, the company's visions for the technology and why Glass represents Google's future.

November 9, 2013 11:45:00 AM ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/google-panel/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[PlayStation Network friends list's massive boost available now]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/ps4-psn-friends-list-limit/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/adam/f0904b05d0a3f32f06e0ab0c11be40b2/playsation-universe_thumbnail.jpg"/> If you've been brushing up against the PlayStation 3's 100 friend limit for awhile, Sony has good news for you: You can add up to 2,000 friends to your PlayStation Network account right now, almost a week ahead of the PS4's launch. However, until November 15th you can only view your expanded social ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/ps4-psn-friends-list-limit/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy J. Seppala]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Live from Expand: Moonshots: the Independent Space Race]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/moonshots-panel/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/chris-lewicki-expand-lead_thumbnail.jpg"/> The next frontier in space travel? All signs point to private enterprise. In fact, this is arguably the most exciting time for the industry since the early days of the space race. We'll be speaking to some of the folks who are re-framing the way we think of outer space, from the president of ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/moonshots-panel/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 09:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Visualized: Marty McFly impersonator shows off ZBoards' hoverboard-inspired creation]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/Marty-McFly-zboard/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/zboard618pxhedimg_thumbnail.jpg"/>It's Back to the Future-inspired, it's for charity and it's an electric freaking skateboard. What's not to like? Oh, and it's at Expand New York, of course, being demoed by one of ZBoard's cofounders, dressed to the nines in the latest 2015 fashion. It's no Pitbull, but it'll do in a pinch. ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/Marty-McFly-zboard/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 09:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[The Today Show will televise Virgin Galactic's first commercial space flight]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/the-today-show-virgin-galactic/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/virgin_thumbnail.jpg"/> If you can't quite afford the fare to space, at least you'll be watch the future of non-terrestrial tourism on your TV. NBC has won the rights to televise Virgin Galactic's first flight, and plan to make it into a three-hour Today Show special. When Sir Branson and his two children travel beyond the ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/the-today-show-virgin-galactic/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mat Smith]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 08:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Alaska Airlines and US Airways join list of companies allowing almost gate-to-gate gadget use]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/us-airways-alaska-airlines-electronics-fss/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/adam/1dac464d787c678cb06f21bad3a7842e/alaska-airlines_thumbnail.jpg"/> More and more airlines are adopting the FAA's new (and more relaxed) gadget policy, and the latest ones joining the fray are Alaska Airlines and US Airways. Both carriers now allow you to keep your eyes glued to phones or tablets even during takeoff or touchdown. In Alaska Airlines' case, it's even ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/us-airways-alaska-airlines-electronics-fss/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mariella Moon]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 07:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Intel acquires Kno to boost its digital education library]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/intel-acquires-kno/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/kno-galaxy-note-450_thumbnail.jpg"/> Intel has long been cozy with the e-textbook developers at Kno, going so far as to license their hardware and preload their software on its own tablets. The chip giant clearly wants to take that relationship further, however, as it just acquired Kno outright. While Intel isn't providing the terms of ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/intel-acquires-kno/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Fingas]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 06:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[$1.2 million in Bitcoins hijacked in 'social engineering' attack]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/bitcoin-hijack-1-2-million/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/bitcoin-hack-2013-11-08-01_thumbnail.jpg"/> So, you've amassed a fortune in Bitcoins, possibly ill-gotten. If you're storing them on a computer that's exposed to the internet, you may want to rethink that strategy thanks to a huge theft from a digital wallet service called Input.io. 4,100 Bitcoins worth $1.2 million were plundered through two ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/bitcoin-hijack-1-2-million/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Dent]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 05:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Microsoft to kill Xbox Video support for Zune and WP7 in 2014]]></title>
<link>http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/microsoft-xbox-video-zune/?ncid=rss_truncated</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2013/11/xbox-video_thumbnail.jpg"/> Microsoft might have just shared a slew of happy Xbox One news, but it also has something sad to announce: the death of Xbox Video support for Zune. To be precise: Zune's PC client, whatever Zune players are left out there and even Windows Phone 7 devices will no longer be able to play Xbox Video ...]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.engadget.com/2013/11/09/microsoft-xbox-video-zune/</guid>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mariella Moon]]></dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 04:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item></channel></rss>