<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Steve Blank</title>
	<atom:link href="http://steveblank.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://steveblank.com</link>
	<description>Entrepreneurship and Conservation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 01:38:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='steveblank.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://0.gravatar.com/blavatar/c470566538ebdffc3e38025ca6ac5da6?s=96&#038;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs2.wp.com%2Fi%2Fbuttonw-com.png</url>
		<title></title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://steveblank.com/osd.xml" title="Steve Blank" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://steveblank.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>A New Way to Look at Competitors</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/08/a-new-way-to-look-at-competitors/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/08/a-new-way-to-look-at-competitors/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 19:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=15017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every startup I see invariably puts up a competitive analysis slide that plots performance on a X/Y graph with their company in the top right. The slide is a holdover from when existing companies launched products into crowded markets. Most of the time this graph is inappropriate for startups or existing companies creating new markets. Here’s [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=15017&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every startup I see invariably puts up a competitive analysis slide that plots performance on a X/Y graph with their company in the top right.</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/competitive-xy.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-15018" alt="Competitive XY" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/competitive-xy.jpg?w=468&#038;h=334" width="468" height="334" /></a></p>
<p>The slide is a holdover from when existing companies launched products into crowded markets. Most of the time this graph is inappropriate for startups or existing companies creating new markets.</p>
<p>Here’s what you need to do instead.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>The X/Y axis competitive analysis slide is a used by <i>existing</i> companies who plan to <i>enter into an existing market</i>.  In this case the basis of competition on the X/Y axes are metrics defined by the users in the <i>existing market.</i></p>
<p>This slide typically shows some price/performance advantage.  And in the days of battles for <span style="text-decoration:underline;">existing</span> markets that may have sufficed.</p>
<p>But today most startups are trying to ressegment existing markets or create <span style="text-decoration:underline;">new</span> markets. How do you diagram that? What if the basis of competition in market creation is really the intersection of multiple existing markets?  Or what if the markets may not exist and you are creating one?</p>
<p>We need a different way to represent the competitive landscape when you are creating a business that never existed or taking share away from incumbents by resegmenting an existing market.</p>
<p>Here’s how.</p>
<p><b>The Petal Diagram<br />
</b>I’ve always thought of my startups as the center of the universe. So I would begin by putting my company in the center of the slide like this.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-15022" alt="Slide1" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide1.jpg?w=180&#038;h=163" width="180" height="163" /></a>In this example the startup is creating a new category &#8211;  a lifelong learning network for entrepreneurs. To indicate where their customers for this new market would come from they drew the 5 <em>adjacent market segments</em>: corporate, higher education, startup ecosystem, institutions, and adult learning skills that they believed their future customers were in today. So to illustrate this they drew these adjacent markets as a cloud surrounding their company. (Unlike the traditional X/Y graph you can draw as many adjacent market segments as you&#8217;d like.)</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15023" alt="Slide2" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=295" width="300" height="295" /></a>Then they filled in the market spaces with the names of the companies that are representative players in each of the adjacent markets.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/companies-updated.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15112" alt="companies updated" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/companies-updated.jpg?w=300&#038;h=288" width="300" height="288" /></a></p>
<p>Then they annotated the private companies with the amount of private capital they had raised. This lets potential investors understand that other investors were interested in the space and thought it was important enough to invest. (And plays on the &#8220;no VC wants to miss a hot space&#8221; mindset.)</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15031" alt="Slide4" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide4.jpg?w=300&#038;h=292" width="300" height="292" /></a></p>
<p>Finally, you could show the current and projected market sizes of the adjacent markets which allows the startups to have a &#8221;how big can our new market be?&#8221; conversation with investors.  (If you wanted to get fancy, you could scale the size of the &#8220;petals&#8221; relative to market size.)</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15032" alt="Slide5" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide5.jpg?w=300&#038;h=272" width="300" height="272" /></p>
<p><strong>The Petal Diagram drives your business model canvas<br />
</strong>What the chart is saying is, &#8220;we think our customers will come from these markets.&#8221;<strong> </strong> That&#8217;s handy if you&#8217;re using a Lean Startup methodology because the Petal Chart helps you identify your first potential customer segments on the business model canvas.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/add-the-canvas4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15126" alt="add the canvas" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/add-the-canvas4.jpg?w=300&#038;h=249" width="300" height="249" /></a>You use this chart to articulate your first hypotheses of <em>who are customers segments you&#8217;re targeting</em>.  If your hypotheses about the potential customers turn out to be incorrect, and they aren&#8217;t interested in your product, then you go back to this competitive diagram and revise it.</p>
<p><strong>Lessons Learned</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>X/Y competitive graphs are appropriate in an existing market</li>
<li>Mapping potential competitors in new or resegmented markets require a different view &#8211; the Petal diagram</li>
<li>The competitive diagram is how develop your first hypotheses about who your customers are</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: I&#8217;ve heard from a few entrepreneurs who used the diagram had investors tell them &#8220;&#8221;it looks like you&#8217;re being surrounded, how can you compete in that market?&#8221;</p>
<p>Those investors have a bright future in banking rather than venture capital.</p>
<div>Seriously, I would run away fast from a potential investor who doesn&#8217;t or can&#8217;t understand that visualizing the data doesn&#8217;t increase or decrease the likelihood of success. It only provides a better way to visualize potential customer segments.</div><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/venture-capital/'>Venture Capital</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/15017/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/15017/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=15017&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/08/a-new-way-to-look-at-competitors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/competitive-xy.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Competitive XY</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/companies-updated.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">companies updated</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide4.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/slide5.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/add-the-canvas4.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">add the canvas</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lean Goes Better with Coke – the Future of Corporate Innovation</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/07/lean-goes-better-with-coke-the-future-of-corporate-innovation/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/07/lean-goes-better-with-coke-the-future-of-corporate-innovation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Companies versus Startups: Durant versus Sloan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=15006</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In 2012 I got together with Alexander Osterwalder, Henry Chesbrough and Andre Marquis to think about the Lean and the future of corporate innovation. We had some radical thoughts how companies were going to have change to remain competitive in the 21st century in a blog post. What we didn&#8217;t envision was that one creative corporate VP [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=15006&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2012 I got together with <a href="http://www.businessmodelgeneration.com/" target="_blank">Alexander Osterwalder</a>, <a href="http://facultybio.haas.berkeley.edu/faculty-list/chesbrough-henry" target="_blank">Henry Chesbrough</a> and <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/andremarquis" target="_blank">Andre Marquis</a> to think about the Lean and the future of corporate innovation. We had some radical thoughts how companies were going to have change to remain competitive in the 21<sup>st</sup> century in a <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/12/03/the-future-of-corporate-innovation-and-entrepreneurship/" target="_blank">blog post</a>. What we didn&#8217;t envision was that one creative corporate VP would take <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/12/03/the-future-of-corporate-innovation-and-entrepreneurship/">that post</a> and build a world-class corporate innovation program around it.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/david-butler/4/8ba/652" target="_blank">David Butler</a> is the VP of Innovation and Entrepreneurship <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">of</span> at The Coca-Cola Company – responsible for finding breakthrough innovation and building an entrepreneurial culture.  Here’s how he’s shaping the future of corporate innovation.</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coke-logo.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-15010" alt="Coke logo" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coke-logo.png?w=468&#038;h=89" width="468" height="89" /></a>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p><b>Innovation isn’t the destination it’s the Journey.</b> What CEOs, management teams and shareholders care about is <i>growth</i>—revenue growth, greater user adoption, increased market share, bigger margins, etc. So the first step for any corporate  “innovation” organization is to tie the word, “innovation,” to the more tangible concept of “growth.” That single step can create a lot of clarity and direction for the organization.</p>
<p><b>Breakthrough Innovation.”</b> Innovation can create 2 kinds of growth: sustaining innovation (small and incremental growth yet predictable) and disruptive innovation (explosive exponential growth yet highly uncertain). Like most big companies, we’re pretty good at the kind of innovation that creates incremental growth. We know how to fund it, how to staff it, how to measure it, etc.</p>
<p>For the past year or so, we’ve been focused on disruptive “breakthrough” innovation (game-changing, etc.) to create <i>exponential</i> growth.</p>
<p><b>Innovation sounds easy. It never is.</b> In our case, we’re local in over 200 countries with operations in basically every city on the planet. We have a portfolio of more than 500 brands and 4000 products and people invite us into their lives more 1.8 billion times a day. Our market cap is around $170B. For most big, established companies like us, our business models were developed years—even decades ago. We’ve built up strength in executing our business model, not creating new ones. So, if you’re Coca-Cola, where do you begin?</p>
<p><b>It didn’t take us very long to connect the dots between exponential growth, business model innovation and the “Lean Startup” movement.</b> The Lean Startup movement is almost a decade old now and it’s now easier than ever for anyone to learn “Lean Startup” methods and become more entrepreneurial. In fact, I believe the movement is now mainstream—startups, VCs, accelerators, are no longer “new.”</p>
<p>There are co-working spaces in basically every city in the world—from Nepal to New York. Almost every large organization has some kind of incubator or accelerator program. And this has created a global entrepreneurial ecosystem.</p>
<p><b>But</b><b> most big companies are still in the shallow-end of the entrepreneurial ecosystem pool.</b> And this is ironic because big companies have so much to add. Big companies know how to<i> </i>scale—most have a lot to learn about starting (as in Lean Startup) but they know how to leverage assets, use network effects, plan and execute. Big companies with big brands have a lot to learn from startups but together, they can do things neither one of them could do alone. And that has become our vision—<i>to make it easier for starters to be scalers and scalers to be starters</i>.</p>
<p><b>So this is where my head was when I read Steve’s “</b><a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/12/03/the-future-of-corporate-innovation-and-entrepreneurship/" target="_blank"><b>The Future of Corporate Innovation and Entrepreneurship</b></a><b>” post last year.</b> At the time, we were definitely in the shallow-end. Now, a year later, (and A LOT of learning), we’re moving into the deep-end and Steve’s 8 strategies are more relevant than ever. Based on our experience, here’s are our Lessons Learned from Steve’s 8 corporate innovation strategies and then four more from Coke for consideration:</p>
<p><b>Lessons Learned</b></p>
<ol>
<li><b><i>21st century corporate survival requires companies to continually create a new set of businesses by inventing new business models</i></b><b>. </b>What is sometimes missed is the opportunity for big companies to leverage their enormous assets (brands, relationships, routes-to-market, etc.) in developing these new models. Most startups can only dream of the kinds of assets most big companies have.<br />
We believe that <i>using the customer development process</i> to monetize these assets through new business models <i>can create huge competitive advantage</i> and more speed to market for us and other big companies.</li>
<li><b>Most of these new businesses need to be created <i>outside</i> of the existing business units.</b> We’ve found that this can only happen if it’s <i>just on the edge of a business unit</i>. Startups need to be close enough to the BU to validate assumptions and leverage BU resources (people, funding, relationships, etc.) but just far enough out to be able to use different processes and systems to move fast, pivot, etc. But there’s no one-size fits all approach to this—every company will have to figure out what works for them.</li>
<li><b>The exact form of the new business models is not known at the beginning. It only emerges after an intense business model design and search activity based on the customer development process.</b> This is so true but so foreign for most big companies. And why wouldn’t it be? All of their internal systems are designed to keep doing what they’ve always done best. They are also under huge pressure to deliver quarterly earnings for shareholders and meet analysts expectations. Using an alternative process including different systems and metrics is key.</li>
<li><b>Companies will have to maintain a portfolio of new business model initiatives, not unlike a venture capital firm, and they will have to accept that maybe only 1 out 10 initiatives might succeed.</b> We’re hoping for 1 out of 10 but hedging our bets by launching and networking  “Accelerators” around the world in both developing and developed economies—from Bangalore to Buenos Aires. We call this our Accelerator Program but our goal is to create new startups, not really invest in existing startups like most traditional accelerator programs. When we need to mash-up with a startup to do something neither of us could do alone, we’re doing that but or goal is to really build new companies.</li>
<li><strong>T</strong><b>o develop this new portfolio, companies need to provide a stable innovation funding mechanism for new business creation, one that is simply thought of as a cost of doing business. </b>Absolutely, but it’s not just about a new “innovation” fund—that’s almost the easy part. <i>The hard part is designing all of the systems to enable the success of the startups.</i> From Tax to Legal to Finance to HR, designing the new systems requires enormous amount of collaboration, transparency and trust.</li>
<li><b>Many of the operating divisions can and should provide resources to the new businesses inside the company.</b> That’s the only way this works. Everybody has to have “skin-in-the-game.” But again, when you get this right, it can create enormous engagement and excitement inside the Business Unit and across the company.</li>
<li><b>We need a new organizational structure to manage the creation of new businesses and to coordinate the sharing of business model resources.</b> Again, absolutely true. But in our case, creating the new structure and systems has been almost like starting a startup. Pitching to senior management, using minimum viable products (MVPs), validating assumptions through lots and lots of testing, pivoting hard when you need to—all of this is required in setting up the structure and systems to do this inside of a big company.</li>
<li><b>Some of these new businesses might become new resources to the existing operating units in the company or they could grow into becoming the new profit generating business units of the company’s future.</b> We’re betting on the latter. Our goal is to create new, high-growth companies <i>outside</i> of the NARTD industry (non-alcoholic ready-to-drink) through this program. We have literally hundreds of thousands of people focused on our core business. We’re hoping to use this opportunity to leverage our assets in new, fast-growing industries.</li>
<li><b>In building capability, the company should look for “starters,” not “scalers.” </b>Starters have a completely different mindset and skills than scalers have. We found we needed to hire expert starters—people who knew how to bootstrap, build MVPs, find a free or very low-cost way of testing a hypothesis,<b> </b>pitch, pivot, etc. We also learned that creating the same kinds of conditions that enable co-founders to thrive on the “outside” is very important to maintain on the “inside.” We had to design a whole new hiring process, compensation model, operating model, co-working spaces, etc. to find, attract and retain “starters.”</li>
<li><b>But it’s not only about creating new revenue streams—creating new behaviors across the company’s culture is key. </b>Getting everyone on the same page with the same language and familiar with new methods and tools is key to making this stick. So along with our Accelerator Program, we’ve also introduced a new “<i><a href="http://www.coca-colacompany.com/coca-cola-unbottled/startup-weekend-at-coke-building-entrepreneurship-from-the-inside-out">Open Entrepreneurship</a></i>” program to give everyone inside our company the opportunity to learn Lean Startup methods and tools. This is what we mean by making it easier for “scalers” to be “starters.”</li>
<li><b>Finding the balance between transparency and opacity is critical. </b>Inside the company, the person or team or group that’s been asked to lead this effort must be completely transparent—function agnostic, open, inclusive, freely sharing everything. This is so new for everyone involved, that there can’t be any kind of “black box” or “cool club” perception around this or it won’t work. On the flip side, just like it is for every startup, there is so much iteration, learning, testing, etc. going on that even if you wanted to talk about what you’re doing in detail, it would sort of depend on the day as things change so frequently. We’ve found it best to take a “more is more” approach internally and a “less is more” approach externally.</li>
<li><b>Nobody, no matter how smart they are, can do this alone.</b> Forming informal networks, both internally and externally, is key. It’s really important for the co-founders of the internal startups to build relationships across the company. And in the same way it’s equally important for the company to authentically connect with the startup community. Being very open and honest with what they’re trying to do is key. And we’ve found that once we built this bridge, we’ve been able to count on a lot of help from the startup community (and visa versa). And as the relationship grows, so does the trust.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are still early days for us at Coke and we have a lot to learn. But we feel that if we and other big companies can get this right, it could be really big.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/butler-fast-company.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15011" alt="Butler Fast Company" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/butler-fast-company.png?w=468"   /></a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/big-companies-versus-startups-durant-versus-sloan/'>Big Companies versus Startups: Durant versus Sloan</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/15006/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/15006/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=15006&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/07/lean-goes-better-with-coke-the-future-of-corporate-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/coke-logo.png?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Coke logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/butler-fast-company.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Butler Fast Company</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lean LaunchPad for Life Sciences &#8211; Value Proposition and Customers</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/04/lean-launchpad-for-life-sciences-value-proposition-and-customers/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/04/lean-launchpad-for-life-sciences-value-proposition-and-customers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14946</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We’re deep into teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences and Health Care (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists. (The class has talked to 1,440 customers to date.) One of the objectives of the class was to become a Life Science Center of Excellence for the [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14946&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’re deep into <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences</a> and Health Care (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists. (The class has talked to 1,440 customers to date.)<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/shutterstock_81663952.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-14998" alt="shutterstock_81663952" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/shutterstock_81663952.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>One of the objectives of the class was to become a Life Science Center of Excellence for the <a href="http://steveblank.com/category/national-science-foundation/" target="_blank">National Science Foundation Innovation Corps</a>. This meant capturing domain specific commercialization expertise for therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health so others can teach this.</p>
<p><a href="http://wp.me/prGQZ-3NP" target="_blank">Part 1 of this post</a> described the issues in the therapeutics drug discovery pipeline. <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/" target="_blank">Part 2 covered medical devices and digital health</a>. Part 3 described <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship-2/" target="_blank">what we’re going to do about it</a>.  Part 4 <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/10/11/this-will-save-us-years-lean-launchpad-for-life-science/" target="_blank">gave a snapshot</a> of what one our teams found the first week outside the building.</p>
<p>This is an update of our progress.</p>
<div>
<p><b>It Takes A Village<br />
</b>We&#8217;re teaching 110 students in 28 teams across therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health. Teams are made up of clinicians, researchers, and post docs, (some of the team members include the Chief of  UCSF General Surgery, the inventor of Fetal Surgery, etc.)</p>
<p>Each of the four cohorts is taught by an experienced life science venture capitalist. <a href="http://www.emvllp.com/biographies.html" target="_blank">Alan May</a> for devices, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karlhandelsman" target="_blank">Karl Handelsman</a> for therapeutics <a href="http://www.mdv.com/who-we-are/abhas-gupta" target="_blank">Abhas Gupta</a> for digital health and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/t-todd-morrill/3/b42/456" target="_blank">Todd Morrill</a> for diagnostics.</p>
<p>Jerry Engel and Jim Hornthal, both who taught the <a href="http://steveblank.com/category/national-science-foundation/" target="_blank">National Science Foundation I-Corps classes,</a> are the senior instructors. The UCSF Office of Innovation and Technology (<a href="http://profiles.ucsf.edu/erik.lium" target="_blank">Erik Lium</a> and Stephanie Marrus) is the reason the program exists.</p>
<p>Each of the teams is assigned a mentor to match their domainv(Head of device R&amp;D of Phillips, Genetech, Crescendo, CTO of UCSF, venture capitalists from Sofinnova, Burrill, Lightstone, M34, etc.)</p>
<p><b>Class Organization &#8211; Lots of Moving Parts<br />
</b>Our class meets weekly. We first meet as one group and then we break out the therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health into their own cohorts. The teams present what they learned talking to 10-15 customer/week, and get comments, suggestions and critiques from their teaching team.  The instructor then presents  a cohort specific lecture explaining how the business model for their area (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) builds on and/or differs from the canonical business model in the <a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/ep245" target="_blank">online Udacity lectures</a> (which the students had to watch as homework.)</p>
<p>We get back together as one group and the instructors share what they learned as they <i>compare and contrast</i> the differences between therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health.  We’ve recorded these panels for each part of the business model canvas.</p>
<p>The framework of the class looks like this:</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ucsf-summary.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14950" alt="Lean LaunchPad for Life Sciences" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ucsf-summary.jpg?w=468&#038;h=361" width="468" height="361" /></a></p>
<p><b>Life Science/Health Care is not a single Category<br />
</b>One of the reasons I teach is because of how much I learn. One of early surprises of this class for me is finding out that the broad category of “Life Sciences” fails to provide the important nuances of each category to entrepreneurs, investors, educators, policy makers, etc. It turns out that for <i>commercialization,</i> the business model (Customers, Channel, Revenue Model, etc.) for therapeutics, diagnostics, devices, bioinformatics and digital health have very little in common.</p>
</div>
<p>You can get a feel for how different by looking at the first two weeks of lectures &#8211; covering value proposition and customer segment &#8211; from each of the therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health cohorts.</p>
<p>Then at the end of the lectures you can see a &#8220;compare and contrast&#8221; video and a summary of the differences.</p>
<h2><strong>Diagnostics</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Week 1 Todd Morrill I</strong><strong>nstructor </strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877332' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-1-diagnostics" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Week 2 </strong><strong>Todd Morrill Instructor</strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877419' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-2-diagnostics" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<h2><strong>Digital Health</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Week 1 </strong><strong>Abhas Gupta Instructor </strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877369' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-1-digital-health" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Week 2 </strong><strong>Abhas Gupta Instructor</strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877482' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-2-digital-health" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<h2><strong></strong><strong>Devices</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Week 1 </strong><strong>Allan May Instructor </strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877379' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-1-devices" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Week 2 </strong><strong>Allan May</strong><strong> Instructor</strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877489' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-2-devices" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<h2><strong>Therapeutics</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Week 1 </strong><strong>Karl Handelsman Instructor </strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877396' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-1-therapeutics" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Week 2 </strong><strong>Karl Handelsman</strong><strong> Instructor</strong></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27877539' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/ucsf-life-sciences-week-2-therapeutics" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<h2><strong>Life Science and Health Care</strong> Differences</h2>
<p>Once we realized that the four cohorts of therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health were so different we decided to have the instructors compare and contrast <em>how</em> they&#8217;re different for each part of the business model. We&#8217;ll be posting these &#8220;compare and contrast&#8221; videos for every week of the class.</p>
<div class='embed-vimeo' style='text-align:center;'><iframe src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/78022588' width='400' height='300' frameborder='0'></iframe></div>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the video above click <a href="https://vimeo.com/groups/213077/videos/78022588" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p><b>Therapeutics</b> (Starting at 0:30)</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Therapeutics customer</i> = pharma and biotech <span style="text-decoration:underline;">companies</span></li>
<li><i>Therapeutics Pain &amp; gain</i> = be better than what these companies have in their own drug development pipeline</li>
<li><i>Therapeutics </i>Validation =  18 months to a first deal with a potential customer – well before FDA trials, and even before preclinical stage</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Digital Health</b> (Starting at 2:40)</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Digital Health Customer</i> = typically consumer end users</li>
<li><i>Digital Health Pain &amp; gain</i> = product/market fit needs to be a need, and the value proposition must address it.  &#8221;Nice to have’s&#8221; do not equal a customer need.</li>
<li><i>Digital Health Validation</i> = large scale adoption</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Medical Devices</b> (Starting at 6:00)</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Medical Device customers</i> = short term: physicians in private practice and hospital, long term: medical device companies</li>
<li><i>Medical Device Customer Goal</i> – figure out the Minimal Viable Product.  No such thing as a perfect first generation product that targets a specific physician/customer segment.</li>
<li><i>Medical Device Validation</i>= 95% of device startups are acquired by a medical device company, 5% build a large standalone company</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Diagnostics</b> (Starting at 10:45)</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Diagnostic Customers = </i>short term In vitro diagnostics are sold to a hospital laboratory or standalone lab, long-term you’ll be bought by Abbott, Roche, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Lessons Learned</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Each of these Life Science domains has a unique business model</li>
<li>Commercialization of therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health all require the Principal Investigators / founders outside their building talking to customers, partners, regulators</li>
<li>Only the Principal Investigators / founders have the authority and insight to pivot when their hypotheses are incorrect</li>
<li>The Lean Startup process and the Lean LaunchPad class can save <em>years</em> in commercialization in these domains</li>
<li>This can be taught</li>
</ul>
</blockquote><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/life-sciences/'>Life Sciences</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14946/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14946/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14946&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/11/04/lean-launchpad-for-life-sciences-value-proposition-and-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/shutterstock_81663952.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutterstock_81663952</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/ucsf-summary.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lean LaunchPad for Life Sciences</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>300 Teams in Two Years</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/10/26/300-teams-in-two-years/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/10/26/300-teams-in-two-years/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 21:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[National Science Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Industrial Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the start of the third year teaching teams of scientists (professors and their graduate students) in the National Science Foundation Innovation Corps (I-Corps). This month we&#8217;ve crossed ~300 teams in the first two years through the program. I-Corps is the  accelerator that helps scientists bridge the commercialization gap between their research in their labs [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14924&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the start of the third year teaching teams of scientists (professors and their graduate students) in the <a href="http://steveblank.com/category/national-science-foundation/" target="_blank">National Science Foundation Innovation Corps</a> (I-Corps). This month we&#8217;ve crossed ~<a href="http://www.nsf.gov/news/special_reports/i-corps/" target="_blank">300 teams in the first two years</a> through the program.</p>
<p>I-Corps is the  accelerator that helps scientists bridge the commercialization gap between their research in their labs and wide-scale commercial adoption and use.</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/12/20/the-government-starts-an-incubator-the-national-science-foundation-innovation-corps/" target="_blank">I-Corps bridges the gap between public support of basic science and private capital funding</a> of new commercial ventures. It&#8217;s a model for a government program that&#8217;s gotten the balance between public/private partnerships just right.</p>
<p>While a few of the I-Corps teams are in web/mobile/cloud, most are working on advanced technology projects that don&#8217;t make <a href="http://techcrunch.com" target="_blank">TechCrunch</a>. You&#8217;re more likely to see their papers (in material science, robotics, diagnostics, medical devices, computer hardware, etc.) in <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org" target="_blank">Science</a> or <a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/‎" target="_blank">Nature</a>. The program pays scientists $50,000 to attend the program and takes no equity.</p>
<p>Currently there are 11 U.S. universities teaching the Lean LaunchPad curriculum organized as I-Corps &#8220;nodes&#8221; across the U.S.  The nodes are now offering their own regional versions of the Lean LaunchPad class under I-Corps.</p>
<p>The NSF I-Corps uses everything we know about building <a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank">Lean Startups</a> and <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship-2/" target="_blank">Evidence-based Entrepreneurship</a> to connect innovation to entrepreneurship. It&#8217;s curriculum is built on a framework of business model design, customer development and agile engineering &#8211; and its emphasis on evidence, Lessons Learned versus demos, makes it the worlds most advanced accelerator. It&#8217;s success is measured not only by the technologies that leave the labs, but how many U.S. scientists and engineers we train as entrepreneurs and how many of them pass on their knowledge to students. I-Corps is our secret weapon to integrate American innovation and entrepreneurship into every U.S. university lab.</p>
<p>Every time I go to Washington and spend time at the <a href="http://www.nsf.gov" target="_blank">National Science Foundation</a> or <a href="http://www.nih.gov" target="_blank">National Institute of Health</a> I&#8217;m reminded <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/01/14/the-endless-frontier-u-s-science-and-national-industrial-policy-part-1/" target="_blank">why the U.S. leads the world in support of basic and applied science</a>.  It&#8217;s not just the money we pour into these programs (~$125 billion/year), but the people who have dedicated themselves to make the world a better place by <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/03/26/the-national-science-foundation-innovation-corps-what-america-does-best/" target="_blank">advancing science and technology</a> for the common good.</p>
<p>I thought it was worth sharing the progress report from the Bay Area (Berkeley, Stanford, <a href="http://steveblank.com/category/life-sciences/" target="_blank">UCSF</a>) I-Corps node so you can see what just <em>one</em> of the nodes was accomplishing. Multiply this by the NSF regional nodes across the U.S. and you&#8217;ll have a feeling for the scale and breadth of the program.</p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27600542' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>If you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/nsf-i-corps-bay-area-node-2013-update" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p>Glad to a part of it.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Lessons Learned</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. government has built an accelerator for scientists and engineers</li>
<li>It&#8217;s scaled across the U.S.</li>
<li>The program has taught ~300 teams</li>
<li>Balance between public/private partnerships</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the podcast here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14924_1-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> Download the podcast <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/10/26/300-teams-in-two-years/" target="_blank">here</a><br />
BTW, NCIIA is offering other accelerators and incubators a class to learn how to build their own versions of I-Corps <a href="http://nciia.org/LLP" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/national-science-foundation/'>National Science Foundation</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/science-and-industrial-policy/'>Science and Industrial Policy</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14924/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14924/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14924&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/10/26/300-teams-in-two-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" length="3174481" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131026.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Will Save Us Years &#8211; Lean LaunchPad for Life Science</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/10/11/this-will-save-us-years-lean-launchpad-for-life-science/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/10/11/this-will-save-us-years-lean-launchpad-for-life-science/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 21:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14880</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re deep into week 2 of teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences and Health Care (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists. Part 1 of this post described the issues in the drug discovery. Part 2 covered medical devices and digital health. Part 3  described what we’re [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14880&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re deep into week 2 of <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences</a> and Health Care (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists.</p>
<p><a href="http://wp.me/prGQZ-3NP" target="_blank">Part 1 of this post</a> described the issues in the drug discovery. <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/" target="_blank">Part 2 covered medical devices and digital health</a>. Part 3  described <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship-2/" target="_blank">what we’re going to do about it</a>.</p>
<p>This is post is a brief snapshot of our progress.</p>
<p>Vitruvian is one of the 28 teams in the class. The team members are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dr. <a href="http://general.surgery.ucsf.edu/faculty/division-chief/hobart-w-harris,-md,-mph.aspx" target="_blank">Hobart Harris</a>  Chief of  General Surgery, Vice-Chair of the Department of Surgery, and a Professor of Surgery at  UCSF. Dr. Harris is also a Principal Investigator in the UCSF Surgical Research Laboratory at San Francisco General Hospital.</li>
<li>Dr. <a href="http://plastic.surgery.ucsf.edu/faculty/faculty/david-m-young,-md.aspx" target="_blank">David Young</a>,  Professor of Plastic Surgery at UCSF. His area of expertise includes wound healing, microsurgery, and reconstruction after burns and trauma. His research interests include the molecular mechanisms of wound healing and the epidemiology and treatment of soft tissue infections.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=44911534&amp;locale=en_US&amp;trk=tyah&amp;trkInfo=tas%3Asarah%20seegal%2Cidx%3A1-1-1" target="_blank">Sarah Seegal</a> is at One Medical Sarah is interested in increasing the quality and accessibility of healthcare services. Sarah worked with <a href="http://breakthrough.com/">Breakthrough.com</a> to connect individuals with professional therapists for online sessions.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/cindy-chang/a/a66/a22" target="_blank">Cindy Chang</a> is a Enzymologist investigating novel enzymes involved in biofuel and chemical synthesis in microbes at <a href="http://www.ls9.com" target="_blank">LS9</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Vitruvian’s first product, MyoSeal, promotes wound repair via biocompatible microparticles plus a fibrin tissue sealant that has been shown to prevent incisional hernias through enhanced wound healing.  The team believed that surgeons would embrace the product and pay thousands to use it.  In week 2 of the class 14 of their potential customers (surgeons) told the team otherwise.</p>
<p>Watch this 90 second clip and find out how the Lean LaunchPad class saved them years.</p>
<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/76660776" width="468" height="263" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p>(If you can&#8217;t see the clip above click <a href="http://vimeo.com/76660776" target="_blank">here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Lessons Learned</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Get out of the building</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14880_2-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_131011.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131011.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_131011.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span><br />
Download the post <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/10/11/this-will-save-us-years-lean-launchpad-for-life-science/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/life-sciences/'>Life Sciences</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14880/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14880/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14880&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/10/11/this-will-save-us-years-lean-launchpad-for-life-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131011.mp3" length="3079168" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131011.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_131011.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Air Force Academy Gets Lean</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/09/17/14824/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/09/17/14824/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Air Force]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14824</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I can always tell when one of my students has been in the military. They’re focused, they’re world-wise past their years, and they don&#8217;t break a sweat in the fast pace and chaotic nature of the class and entrepreneurship. Todd Branchflower took my Lean LaunchPad class having been entrepreneurial enough to convince the Air Force [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14824&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can always tell when one of my students has been in the military. They’re focused, they’re world-wise past their years, and they don&#8217;t break a sweat in the fast pace and chaotic nature of the class and entrepreneurship. Todd Branchflower took my <a href="http://steveblank.com/2010/12/07/the-lean-launchpad-%E2%80%93-teaching-entrepreneurship-as-a-management-science/" target="_blank">Lean LaunchPad</a> class having been entrepreneurial enough to convince the Air Force send him to Stanford to get his graduate engineering degree.</p>
<p>In class I teased Todd that while the Navy had me present my <a href="http://steveblank.com/secret-history/" target="_blank">Secret History of Silicon Valley</a> talk in front of 4,000 cadets at the <a href="http://www.nps.edu/" target="_blank">Naval Post Graduate School</a>, I had yet to hear from the <a href="http://www.usafa.af.mil/" target="_blank">Air Force Academy</a>.  He promised that one day he would fix that.</p>
<p>True to his word, fast-forward three years and Todd is now <i>Captain </i><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/todd-branchflower/26/103/42b" target="_blank">Todd Branchflower</a>, teaching computer engineering at the Air Force Academy.  He extended an invitation to me to <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/04/29/fly-high/" target="_blank">come out to the Air Force Academy to address the cadets and meet the faculty</a>. Besides the talk I brainstormed with Todd and other faculty on how to integrate the Lean LaunchPad into the Air Force Academy Capstone engineering class (a Capstone class puts together all the pieces that a students has learned in his or her major.)</p>
<p>Here’s Todd’s story of how we got there and progress to date.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p><b>Not That Long Ago<br />
</b>In 2007, I graduated United States Air Force Academy as a computer engineer and entered the <a href="http://ww3.safaq.hq.af.mil" target="_blank">Air Force&#8217;s acquisition corps</a>, excited and confident about my ability to bring technology to bear for our airmen.</p>
<div id="attachment_14823" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/branchflower-graduation.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14823 " alt="Graduation day with classmate Joseph Helton (right), killed in action in Iraq in 2009" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/branchflower-graduation.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Graduation day with classmate Joseph Helton (right), killed in action in Iraq in 2009</p></div>
<p>And I couldn&#8217;t have been put in a better place: testing the Air Force&#8217;s newest network security acquisitions. I was their technical man on the inside &#8211; making sure big defense contractors delivered on their promises. We were modernizing datacenters, buying vulnerability-scanning software, and adding intrusion detection appliances &#8211; all things typical of anyone running an enterprise-scale network.<i>.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/46th-test-sqd.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-14822" alt="46th test sqd" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/46th-test-sqd.jpg?w=194&#038;h=210" width="194" height="210" /></a></i></p>
<p>I was in the thick of it &#8211; chairing telecons, tracking action items, and drafting test plans. I could recite requirements and concepts of operations from memory. I was jetsetting to team meetings and conferences across the country. I was busy.</p>
<p>Sure, I wasn&#8217;t working very closely with the airmen who were going to use the equipment.  But they called into the weekly telecons, right? And they were the ones who had given the program office the requirements from the outset. (Well, their bosses had.) And I&#8217;d distilled those requirements into system characteristics we could measure. Well, more measurable versions of the original requirements. And meeting the requirements was the most important thing, right?</p>
<p><b>Doing it Wrong<br />
</b>Here’s what I learned: I was doing it wrong. The way our process worked, customers were just a stakeholder that provided input &#8211; not drivers of the process. That meant that program offices were only accountable to a list of requirements, which were locked early. Success only consisted of passing tests against these requirements, not delighting our airmen. I began to wonder – how could we learn about user needs earlier?  How could we deliver them solutions more quickly?  More cheaply?</p>
<p>It was only after returning to Stanford and taking the Lean Launchpad class that I became convinced that a radically different, customer-centric approach was the solution. I returned to the Air Force Academy as an instructor in the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, intent on spreading the gospel of Customer Development and Lean.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/academy-ee.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-14821" alt="academy ee" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/academy-ee.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>Our existing Capstone senior engineering design course followed the defense acquisition process; the focus of defense acquisition is to “nail down requirements” early and manage customer expectations to “avoid requirements creep”. I saw this as counter to the joint, iterative discovery process between entrepreneurs and customers I had experienced on my Lean Launchpad team.</p>
<p>I kept in touch with Steve as I started teaching. We discussed how the Lean Launchpad approach might find a place in our curriculum, and how it might be adapted to fit the unique Air Force Academy / military environment. We grew excited about how showing success here might prove a good model for how it could be done in the broader Air Force; how exposing future officers to the Lean philosophy might bring about change from within.</p>
<p>So when I invited Steve out to the Air Force Academy to speak last spring, there was more at stake than the talk.  We set up a meeting with our department head, Col Jeff Butler, and Capstone course director, LtCol Charlie Gaona, to pitch the idea.  They shared our enthusiasm about the impact it could have on our future design projects and how it might bring a change in perspective to our acquisition corps. They gave the go-ahead to send a pilot team through the program in the Fall semester, with the potential for it to be applied across the entire course if we delivered results.</p>
<p>I found a willing co-conspirator in Capt Ryan Silva, a star instructor who mentors a project named <a href="http://falconworks.org/index.php?option=com_k2&amp;view=item&amp;id=12:project-upper-body-motion-tracking-neumimic&amp;Itemid=119" target="_blank">Neumimic</a>, using technology to aid in the rehabilitation of patients with chronic loss of limb motion.  In the first year, they had developed a proof of concept around the Xbox Kinect &#8211; and Ryan had high hopes for the future. But he found some elements of the traditional systems engineering process cumbersome and frustrating to cadets. Ryan signed on to lead our test class.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><b>V-Model of Systems Engineering<br />
</b>The current Capstone class follows the V-Model of Systems Engineering, with teams creating a detailed system design throughout the Fall semester and building their design in the Spring.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/vmodel.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14820" title="The V-model of the Systems Engineering Process (from Wikipedia)" alt="Vmodel" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/vmodel.jpg?w=300&#038;h=167" width="300" height="167" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">There are a series of formal reviews throughout the two semesters, in line with the Air Force acquisitions process.  Requirements and a concept of operations are presented at the first, the System Requirements Review.  Cadets receive instruction on the process in about a quarter of the course lessons.</p>
<p>What we decided to do instead was have semi-weekly informal reviews Lean Launchpad style, focusing on product hypotheses, customer interactions, learning, and validation / refinement.  We emphasize customer interaction via “getting out of the building” and rapid iteration through “cheap hacks”.  We’ve removed most of the structure and firm requirements from the original course in favor of a “whatever it takes” philosophy.  Instruction is presented in tandem with the reviews, focusing on areas we see as problematic.</p>
<div id="attachment_14830" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/glen-house-meeting.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14830" alt="Last year’s team meeting with Dr. Glen House at Penrose-St. Francis Hospital" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/glen-house-meeting.jpg?w=300&#038;h=156" width="300" height="156" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Last year’s team meeting with Dr. Glen House at Penrose-St. Francis Hospital</p></div>
<p><b>Back to the Present<br />
</b>We’re about a quarter of the way through the fall semester. Team Neumimic consists of nine sharp cadets across multiple academic disciplines. Based on initial customer interactions, they divided themselves into two complementary but standalone teams. One will focus on design, execution, and measurement of therapy sessions &#8211; building on the original Xbox Kinect work.  The other will work on adjustable restriction of patient motion &#8211; forcing patients to use the proper muscles for each movement.</p>
<p>Here’s Ryan on the impact of the process change:</p>
<p>&#8220;Last year the team found themselves handcuffed to a process that required a 100% design solution on paper before we could even think about touching hardware&#8230;crazy right?! We spent the entire first semester nailing down requirements for a system that was supposed to meet the needs of stroke and traumatic brain injury patients as prescribed by their occupational therapists. For five months we slogged our way through the process emerged with a complete design for our system, custom-built to meet the needs of patients and doctors alike. Our design was flawless. We had nuts-and-bolts details all the way down to the schematic level. We were ready to build! The fact that we had yet to even see a patient or spend any real time with an occupational therapist had not even registered to us as a problem, until we were invited to watch a therapy session.</p>
<p>Our entire team walked out of the hospital ashen-faced and silent. <i>We knew we had just wasted half the course designing a system that wouldn’t work</i>. We were back to square one. The remainder of the course was spent in a frenzy of phone calls with doctors and therapists paired with many design reviews, but this time with our customers in the room. We were able to iterate a few solutions before we ran out of time, but the customers were thrilled with what they saw. I could only imagine what we could have accomplished if we didn’t waste the first half of the course on a solution that ultimately wasn’t what the customers wanted. I was fired up when Todd approached me with his idea to fundamentally change the way we did business.</p>
<p>So far the results have been incredible compared to last year. <em>The team has learned more about the problem in a month than last year’s team learned in an entire semester</em>. I’m not saying this year’s cadets are any more capable than last year’s; just that I believe this year’s team has been given a better chance to succeed.  They’re freed of a lot of stifling overhead and are embracing a process where requirements are derived from those who will actually use the system&#8230;imagine that! I’m excited to see what the team does with their remaining eight months.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_14819" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/current-team.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14819" alt="Current team members observing Dr. House conduct a therapy session" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/current-team.jpg?w=300&#038;h=170" width="300" height="170" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Current team members observing Dr. House conduct a therapy session</p></div>
<p>But we have experienced challenges in implementing this approach. Here’s what we’ve noticed so far:</p>
<p>In typical Lean Launchpad classes, students apply as teams with their own idea.  There’s also the potential for teams to pursue the opportunity beyond the class if they’re successful. In our Capstone, projects are predetermined and cadets are assigned based on preference and skill set.  Cadets will graduate and be commissioned as officers, doing various jobs throughout the Air Force. It’s highly unlikely they’ll be able to continue their project. These factors might make the initial motivation of our team less than that of other Lean Launchpad teams.  We found that early interactions with customers excited about their work went a long way to remedy this.</p>
<p>We’re offering cadets much less structure than they’re used to. Some cadets are uncomfortable with the ambiguity of the requirements (“What are you looking for?  What do I have to do to get an A?”).  I’d imagine this is typical of most high-performing students.</p>
<p>We’re trusting cadets with more freedom and less oversight than they’re used to.  There’s the potential for our trust to be abused.  I’m hopeful that our cadets rise to this challenge.  I think they’ll feel ownership of the project and empowerment, rather than see an opportunity to shirk responsibilities.</p>
<p>Since this course is a senior design experience, cadets expect to be “using their major”.  There’s the tendency for some to sit on the sideline if the pressing work isn’t directly related to their area of expertise.  It has taken some prodding for cadets to embrace the “hustler” mindset &#8211; to take any job necessary to move the team forward.</p>
<p>These are challenges we can overcome.  I know we’re moving in the right direction.  I know we have the right team and project to be successful.  I know our cadets will make us proud.</p>
<p>Up the hill!</p>
<p>Listen to post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14824_3-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span><br />
Download the post <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/09/17/the-air-force-academy-gets-lean/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/air-force/'>Air Force</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14824/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14824/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14824&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/09/17/14824/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" length="12291949" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/branchflower-graduation.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graduation day with classmate Joseph Helton (right), killed in action in Iraq in 2009</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/46th-test-sqd.jpg?w=277" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">46th test sqd</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/academy-ee.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">academy ee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/vmodel.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The V-model of the Systems Engineering Process (from Wikipedia)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/glen-house-meeting.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Last year’s team meeting with Dr. Glen House at Penrose-St. Francis Hospital</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/current-team.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Current team members observing Dr. House conduct a therapy session</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130917.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Real Learning is Outside the Building, Not Demo Day</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/09/05/why-real-learning-is-outside-the-building-not-demo-day/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/09/05/why-real-learning-is-outside-the-building-not-demo-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14788</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the last three years our Lean LaunchPad / NSF Innovation Corps classes have been teaching hundreds of entrepreneurial teams a year how to build their startups by getting out of the building and testing their hypotheses behind their business model.  While our teams have mentors, socialize a lot and give great demos, the goal of [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14788&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last three years our <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/03/08/a-new-way-to-teach-entrepreneurship-the-lean-launchpad-at-stanford-class-1/" target="_blank">Lean LaunchPad</a> / <a href="http://steveblank.com/category/national-science-foundation/" target="_blank">NSF Innovation Corps</a> classes have been teaching hundreds of entrepreneurial teams a year how to build their startups by <a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank">getting out of the building and testing their hypotheses</a> behind their business model.  While our teams have mentors, socialize a lot and give great demos, the goal of our class final presentations is “<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank" target="_blank">Lessons Learned</a>”  &#8211; about product/market fit, pricing, acquisition/activation costs, pricing, partners, etc.  We think <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/12/20/the-government-starts-an-incubator-the-national-science-foundation-innovation-corps/" target="_blank">teaching teams</a> a formal methodology around the Lean Framework (Business Model design, Customer Development and Agile Engineering) is a natural evolution of how successful incubators/accelerators will build startups.</p>
<p>Here’s the story of one such team; Jonathan Wylie, Lakshmi Shivalingaiah and the <a href="http://www.evokeapp.com" target="_blank">Evoke</a> team.</p>
<p><b>&#8212;&#8211;</b></p>
<p>Imagine if, in the course of ten rollercoaster weeks, your customer segment changed from executives on corporate campuses to moms on playgrounds, a tool that was just part of your product turned into the killer product, and the value of the problem you were solving went from number 47 to customers trying to give you money when you demo’d.  Here’s how that happened.</p>
<p>We came to the <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/03/08/a-new-way-to-teach-entrepreneurship-the-lean-launchpad-at-stanford-class-1/" target="_blank">Lean LaunchPad class</a> wanting to build a mobile/web research management system aimed at helping qualitative researchers better manage the media they captured in the field. We were ready to learn, but pretty confident we would end the journey in the same market space in which we started.  We had a killer team and all the right skillsets.  I was a consultant and ethnographer, another teammate was a market researcher, and two others had the software engineering skills to build what the market needed.  And what the market needed would, of course, be exactly what we had envisioned. After all, there must be a huge number of researchers struggling with the exact same problems we had, right?  Not quite…</p>
<p><b>Out of the Building<br />
</b>In the first 4 weeks, our team got out of the building and spoke with employees at 42 different companies.  We spoke with people at all levels, from front line user experience researchers at large tech firms to the CMO of a fortune 500 consumer goods company. <a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/discover-x-workflow.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-14787" alt="Discover X Workflow" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/discover-x-workflow.jpg?w=270&#038;h=198" width="270" height="198" /></a>From the first 10 interviews, we learned that video is a big problem for researchers who use that medium.  It takes an average of 4 hours to mine every hour of video for the relevant 10 seconds of insight that matters.  Thus, we focused our early minimum viable product on helping researchers save money and time in finding insight in market research videos.</p>
<p><b>Wireframes<br />
</b>We built wireframes as a Minimum Viable Product to elicit feedback and began showing them to customers during our interviews.  At this point, things got real…and a bit ugly.  Given something tangible, customers were able to start gauging their willingness to use and pay.  <a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/discover-x-wireframe.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-14786" alt="Discover X wireframe" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/discover-x-wireframe.jpg?w=300&#038;h=182" width="300" height="182" /></a>Turns out, researchers were “just not that into us.”  We heard consistently that the product looked good and solved a problem, <i>but it was not an important problem</i>.  It was number 47 on their list, and there was no way they could justify paying to solve that problem.</p>
<p><b>First Pivot<br />
</b>As disappointing as this was, we dug deeper with our questioning.  To our surprise, customers started offering ideas on where there might be a true need; one of which was the legal market, specifically the deposition process. We thought this would be perfect for our product. There is a lot of video being recorded, and attorneys need to be able to pull out the insights quickly. After a solid week of speaking with lawyers and attending webinars on real-time deposition software, we had mapped both the technology and the buying relationships.  What we learned was that, we would just be an incremental feature to the incumbents and would need to integrate our solution with theirs. This, combined with regulation from the courts, a 2-year sales cycle, and the realization that e-discovery groups are not early adopters, made this an unattractive market.</p>
<p><b>Technology in search of a market<br />
</b>By this point, we were a technology in search of a market…not a good place to be.   The next customer segment we tried was startup founders.  After all, they are just like us &#8211; researching their markets and needing a way to share insights and keep their teams connected to customers. However, we found that most just assume that what they are building will have a market. The few who did get it felt uncomfortable using video during the interview process.</p>
<p><b>Pivot Two<br />
</b>While at times we felt like we wanted to give up, we began to hear a positive signal in the noise of all the customer rejections.  <a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/evoke-brainstorming.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-14785" alt="Evoke Brainstorming" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/evoke-brainstorming.jpg?w=226&#038;h=300" width="226" height="300" /></a>At first it was faint.  While customers in all three markets were lukewarm for use at work, they got visibly excited telling us that it would definitely solve a problem at home. Say what??  They told us “too bad we weren’t making a consumer product so they could<i> document their kids</i>… they would pay a lot of money for that product.”  Whoah…were <span style="text-decoration:underline;">customers telling us</span> we are a consumer product rather than B-to-B??</p>
<p>We settled on a small-scale experiment to test the consumer market. We decided to speak with 10 parents over the course of a week. If 5 had a similar problem, we would dive deeper. What we got was a landslide of interest.  All 10 parents had the problem.  Even more amazing to us, 9 of them liked our solution!</p>
<p>We learned that parents capture moments with their families to:</p>
<ol>
<li>remember and relive later</li>
<li>share with those closest to them</li>
<li>pass along a memoir to their kids</li>
</ol>
<p>To our surprise, it turns out that none of these are being accomplished well with existing products, and parents are stressed because they feel like they are failing in an important responsibility.</p>
<p><b>Eureka!<br />
</b>Since that initial experiment in class, we’ve validated these findings (and many others) during over 200 hour-long interviews.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14784" alt="1st evoke wireframes" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/1st-evoke-wireframes.jpg?w=468&#038;h=351" width="468" height="351" /></p>
<p>We even partnered with the university on a 112-person design workshop to learn more about how photos and videos fit into people’s lives.  It’s always an incredible experience to be invited into someone’s home to learn about how they capture their most precious family moments.  Sometimes, the learning is immediate and conclusive. Other times, we have to do multiple rounds before we arrive at an answer to an important question.</p>
<p>The result of all this effort is that we have found a large and underserved market in hidden in plain sight, right in the middle of an area that gets a lot of attention – photos and videos!</p>
<p><b>Lessons Learned<br />
</b>There’s no way we would have learned any of this unless we were out of the building and in the trenches, with parents over an extended period.</p>
<p>Knowing our customers and their problems first hand has given us a huge head start and a competitive advantage. Most entrepreneurs seem to just make this stuff up for a pitch deck or to please stakeholders, but the validated learning that we gained through these interviews and other methods of business model experimentation is not something that can be easily replicated.</p>
<p>As for our current status, we are building the product, continuing customer development, exploring and validating other aspects of our business model, and…oh yeah…hitting the pavement to raise our first round of funding!  If you want to talk to us about that, or if you know parents that we should be speaking to, please feel free to reach out.</p>
<p>For all the parents out there, relief (and much more) is on its way… <a href="http://www.evokeapp.com" target="_blank">http://www.evokeapp.com</a></p>
<p>Listen the post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14788_4-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130905.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130905.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130905.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span><br />
Download the audio <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/09/05/why-real-learning-is-outside-the-building-not-demo-day/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14788/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14788/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14788&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/09/05/why-real-learning-is-outside-the-building-not-demo-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130905.mp3" length="9142348" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/discover-x-workflow.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Discover X Workflow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/discover-x-wireframe.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Discover X wireframe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/evoke-brainstorming.jpg?w=226" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Evoke Brainstorming</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/1st-evoke-wireframes.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1st evoke wireframes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130905.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130905.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reinventing Life Science Startups – Evidence-based Entrepreneurship</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship-2/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Industrial Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14659</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What if we could increase productivity and stave the capital flight by helping Life Sciences startups build their companies more efficiently? We’re going to test this hypothesis by teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences and Health Care (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists. [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14659&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What if we could increase productivity and stave the capital flight by helping Life Sciences startups build their companies more efficiently?</p>
<p>We’re going to test this hypothesis by <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences</a> and Health Care (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists.</p>
<p><a href="http://wp.me/prGQZ-3NP" target="_blank">Part 1 of this post</a> described the issues in the drug discovery. <a href="http://steveblank.com/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/" target="_blank">Part 2 covered medical devices and digital health</a>. This post describes what we&#8217;re going to do about it.  And why you ought to take <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">this class</a>.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>When I wrote <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0989200507/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0989200507&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=wwwsteveblank-20">Four Steps to the Epiphany</a> and the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984999302/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=wwwsteveblank-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0984999302">Startup Owners Manual</a>, I believed that Life Sciences startups didn&#8217;t need Customer Discovery. Heck how hard could it be?  You invent a cure for cancer and then figure out where to put the bags of money. (In fact, for oncology, with a successful clinical trial, this is the case.)</p>
<h3><i>Pivots in life sciences companies</i></h3>
<p>But I’ve learned that’s not how it really works. For the last two and a half years, <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/03/26/the-national-science-foundation-innovation-corps-what-america-does-best/" target="_blank">we’ve taught hundreds of teams how to commercialize their science with a version of the Lean LaunchPad class</a> called the <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/06/11/making-a-dent-in-the-universe-results-from-the-nsf-i-corps/" target="_blank">National Science Foundation Innovation Corps</a>.  Quite a few of the teams were building biotech, devices or digital health products.  What we found is that during the class <i>almost all of them pivoted</i> - making substantive changes to one or more of their business model canvas components.</p>
<p>In the real world a big pivot in life sciences far down the road of development is a very bad sign due to huge sunk costs.  But pivoting early, before you raise and spend millions or tens of millions means potential disaster avoided.</p>
<p>Some of these pivots included changing their product/service once the team had a better of understanding of customer needs or changing their position in the value chain (became an OEM supplier to hospital suppliers rather than selling to doctors directly.) Other pivots involved moving from a platform technology to become a product supplier, moving from a therapeutic drug to a diagnostic or moving from a device that required a PMA to one that required a 510(k).</p>
<p>Some of these teams made even more radical changes.  For example when one team found the right customer, they changed the core technology (the basis of their original idea!) used to serve those customers. Another team reordered their device’s feature set based on customer needs.</p>
<p>These findings convinced me that the class could transform how we thought about building life science startups.  But there was one more piece of data that blew me away.</p>
<p><strong>Control versus Experiment &#8211; 18% versus 60%<i><br />
</i></strong>For the last two and a half years, the teams that were part of the National Science Foundation Innovation Corps were those who wanted to learn how to commercialize their science, applied to join the program, fought to get in and went through a grueling three month program.  Other scientists attempting to commercialize their science were free to pursue their startups without having to take the class.</p>
<p>Both of these groups, those who took the Innovation Corps class and those who didn&#8217;t, applied for government peer-reviewed funding through the <a href="http://www.nsf.gov/eng/iip/sbir/phase_I.jsp" target="_blank">SBIR</a> program. The teams that skipped the class and pursued traditional methods of starting a company had an 18% success rate in receiving SBIR Phase I funding.</p>
<p>The teams that took the Lean Launchpad class  &#8211; get ready for this &#8211; <b><span style="text-decoration:underline;">had a 60% success rate</span></b>. And yes, while funding does not equal a successful company, it does mean these teams knew something about building a business the other teams did not.</p>
<p>The 3-person teams consisted of Principal Investigators (PI’s), mostly tenured professors (average age of 45,) whose NSF research the project was based on. The PI’s in turn selected one of their graduate students (average age of 30,) as the entrepreneurial lead. The PI and Entrepreneurial Lead were supported by a mentor (average age of 50,) with industry/startup experience.</p>
<p>This was most definitely not the hoodie and flip-flop crowd.</p>
<p>Obviously there’s lots of bias built into the data &#8211; those who volunteered might be the better teams, the peer reviewers might be selecting for what we taught, funding is no metric for successful science let alone successful companies, etc.  – but the difference in funding success is over 300%.</p>
<p>The funding criteria for these new ventures wasn&#8217;t solely whether they had a innovative technology. It was whether the teams understood how to take that idea/invention/patent and transform it into a company. It was whether after meeting with partners and regulators, they had a plan to deal with the intensifying regulatory environment. It was whether after talking to manufacturing partners and clinicians, they understood how they were going to reduce technology risk. And It was after they talked to patients, providers and payers whether they understood the customer segments to reduce market risk by having found product/market fit.</p>
<p>Scientists and researchers have spent their careers testing hypotheses inside their labs. This class teaches them how to test the critical hypotheses that turn their idea into a business as they deal with the real world of regulation, customers and funding.<span style="text-decoration:underline;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>So after the team at UCSF said they’d like to prototype a class for Life Sciences, I agreed.</p>
<p>Here’s what we’re going to offer.</p>
<h3>The <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/12/20/the-government-starts-an-incubator-the-national-science-foundation-innovation-corps/">Lean LaunchPad</a> Life Sciences and Health Care class</h3>
<p>The goal of the <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/12/20/the-government-starts-an-incubator-the-national-science-foundation-innovation-corps/">Lean LaunchPad</a> Life Sciences class at UCSF is to <i>teach researchers how to move their technology from an academic lab into the commercial world</i>.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/ucsf-logo.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-14748" alt="UCSF Logo" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/ucsf-logo.png?w=300&#038;h=95" width="300" height="95" /></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;re going to help teams:</p>
<ul>
<li>assess regulatory risk before they design and build</li>
<li>gather data essential to customer purchases before doing the science</li>
<li>define clinical utility now, before spending millions of dollars</li>
<li>identify financing vehicles before you need them</li>
</ul>
<p>We’ve segmented the class into four cohorts: therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health.  And we recruited a team of world class Venture Capitalists and entrepreneurs to teach and mentor the class including <a href="http://www.emvllp.com/biographies.html" target="_blank">Alan May</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karlhandelsman" target="_blank">Karl Handelsman</a>, <a href="http://www.mdv.com/who-we-are/abhas-gupta" target="_blank">Abhas Gupta</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/t-todd-morrill/3/b42/456" target="_blank">Todd Morrill</a>.</p>
<p>The course is free to UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford students; $100 for pre-revenue startups; and $300 for industry. &#8211; See more <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare">here</a></p>
<p>The syllabus is <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Class starts Oct 1<sup>st</sup> and runs through Dec 10<sup>th</sup>.</p>
<p>Download the all three parts of the Life Science series <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/lean-launch-pad-for-life-sciences" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='468' height='294' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/D_d96BWHxWA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Listen to the podcast here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14659_5-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130821.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130821.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130821.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span></p>
<p>Download the podcast <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/life-sciences/'>Life Sciences</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/science-and-industrial-policy/'>Science and Industrial Policy</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14659/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14659/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14659&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/21/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130821.mp3" length="7830454" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/ucsf-logo.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">UCSF Logo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reinventing Life Science Startups – Medical Devices and Digital Health</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Industrial Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What if we could increase productivity and stave the capital flight by helping Life Sciences startups build their companies more efficiently? We’re going to test this hypothesis by teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences and Healthcare (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists. In [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14635&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What if we could increase productivity and stave the capital flight by helping Life Sciences startups build their companies more efficiently?</p>
<p>We’re going to test this hypothesis by teaching a <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences</a> and Healthcare (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at UCSF with a team of veteran venture capitalists.</p>
<p>In this three post series, <a href="http://wp.me/prGQZ-3NP" target="_blank">Part 1</a> described the challenges Life Science companies face in Therapeutics and Diagnostics. This post describes the issues in Medical Devices and Digital Health.  Part 3 will offer our hypothesis about how to change the dynamics of the Life Sciences industry with a different approach to commercialization of research and innovation.  And why you ought to take <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">this class</a>.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>Medical devices prevent, treat, mitigate, or cure disease by physical, mechanical, or thermal means (in contrast to drugs, which act on the body through pharmacological, metabolic or immunological means). They span they gamut from tongue depressors and bedpans to complex programmable pacemakers and laser surgical devices. They also diagnostic products, test kits, ultrasound products, x-ray machines and medical lasers.</p>
<p>Incremental advances are driven by the existing medical device companies, while truly innovative devices often come from doctors and academia. One would think that designing a medical device would be a simple engineering problem, and startups would be emerging right and left. The truth is that today it’s tough to get a medical device startup funded.</p>
<h3><b>Life Sciences II &#8211; Medical Devices</b></h3>
<p><i>Regulatory Issues<br />
</i>In the U.S. the FDA <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandTobacco/CDRH/default.htm" target="_blank">Center for Devices and Radiological Health</a> (CDRH) regulates medical devices and puts them into <a href="http://www.fda.gov/MedicalDevices/DeviceRegulationandGuidance/Overview/ClassifyYourDevice/" target="_blank">three “classes” based on their risks</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpcd/315.cfm" target="_blank"><i>Class I</i> devices</a> are low risk and have the least regulatory controls. For example, dental floss, tongue depressors, arm slings, and hand-held surgical instruments are classified as Class I devices. Most Class I devices are exempt Premarket Notification 510(k) (see below.)</p>
<p><i>Class II</i> devices are higher risk devices and have more regulations to prove the device’s safety and effectiveness. For example, condoms, x-ray systems, gas analyzers, pumps, and surgical drapes are classified as Class II devices.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/fda-approvals.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-14640" alt="FDA approvals" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/fda-approvals.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a></p>
<p>Manufacturers introducing Class II medical devices must submit what’s called a <a href="http://www.fda.gov/MedicalDevices/DeviceRegulationandGuidance/HowtoMarketYourDevice/PremarketSubmissions/PremarketNotification510k/default.htm" target="_blank">510(k) </a>to the FDA. The 510(k) identifies your medical device and compares it to an existing medical device (which the FDA calls a “predicate” device) to demonstrate that your device is substantially equivalent and at least as safe and effective.</p>
<p><i>Class III</i> devices are generally the highest risk devices and must be approved by the FDA before they are marketed. For example, implantable devices (devices made to replace/support or enhance part of your body) such as defibrillators, pacemakers, artificial hips, knees, and replacement heart valves are classified as Class III devices. Class III medical devices that are high risk or novel devices for which no “predicate device” exist require clinical trials of the medical device a <a href="http://www.fda.gov/medicaldevices/deviceregulationandguidance/howtomarketyourdevice/premarketsubmissions/premarketapprovalpma/" target="_blank">PMA  (Pre-Market Approval)</a>.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/life-science-decline.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14651" alt="Life Science Decline" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/life-science-decline.png?w=468&#038;h=161"   /></a><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/life-science-decline.png"><br />
</a></p>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandTobacco/CDRH/default.htm">FDA</a> is tougher about approving innovative new medical devices. The number of 510(k)s being required to supply additional information has doubled in the last decade. <i></i></li>
<li>The number of <a href="http://www.fda.gov/medicaldevices/deviceregulationandguidance/howtomarketyourdevice/premarketsubmissions/premarketapprovalpma/default.htm">PMA’s</a> that have received a major deficiency letter has also doubled.<i></i></li>
<li>An FDA delay or clinical challenge is increasingly fatal to Life Science startups, where investors now choose to walk away rather than escalate the effort required to reach approval.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/med-device-pipeline.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14654" alt="med device pipeline" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/med-device-pipeline.jpg?w=468&#038;h=122"   /></a></p>
<p><i>Business Model Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Cost pressures are unrelenting in every sector, with pressure on prices and margins continuing to increase.</li>
<li>Devices are a five-sided market: patient, physician, provider, payer and regulator. Startups need to understand all sides of the market long before they ever consider selling a product.</li>
<li>In the last decade, most device startups took their devices overseas for clinical trials and first getting EU versus FDA approval</li>
<li>Recently, the financing of innovation in medical devices has collapsed even further with most Class III devices simply unfundable.</li>
<li>Companies must pay a  <a href="http://www.irs.gov/uac/Medical-Device-Excise-Tax:-Frequently-Asked-Questions">medical device excise tax</a> of 2.3% on medical device revenues, regardless of profitability delays or cash-flow breakeven.</li>
<li>The U.S. government is the leading payer for most of health care, and under ObamaCare the government’s role in reimbursing for medical technology will increase. Yet two-thirds of all requests for reimbursement are denied today, and what gets reimbursed, for how much, and in what timeframe, are big unknowns for new device companies.</li>
</ul>
<p><i>Venture Capital Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Early stage Venture Capital for medical device startups has dried up. The amount of capital being invested in new device companies is at an 11 year low.</li>
<li>Because device IPOs are rare, and M&amp;A is much tougher, liquidity for investors is hard to find.</li>
<li>Exits have remained within about the same, while the cost and time to exit have doubled.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Life Sciences III &#8211; The Rise of Digital Health<br />
</b>Over the last five years a series of applications that fall under the category of “Digital Health” has emerged. Examples of these applications include: remote patient monitoring, analytics/big data (aggregation and analysis of clinical, administrative or economic data), hospital administration (software tools to run a hospital), electronic health records (clinical data capture), and wellness (improve/monitor health of individuals). A good number of these applications are using Smartphones as their platform.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/digital-health-flow.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14656" alt="digital health flow" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/digital-health-flow.jpg?w=468&#038;h=128"   /></a></p>
<p><i>Business Model Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>A good percentage of these startups are founded by teams with strong technical experience but without healthcare experience. Yet healthcare has its own unique regulatory and reimbursement issues and business model issues that must be understood</li>
<li>Most of these startups are in a multisided market, and many have the same five-sided complexity as medical devices: patient, physician, provider, payer and regulator.  (Some are even more complex in an outpatient / nurse / physical therapy setting.)</li>
<li>Reimbursement for digital health interventions is still a work in progress</li>
<li>Some startups in this field are actually beginning with Customer Development while others struggle with the classic <i>execution </i>versus <i>search</i> problem</li>
</ul>
<p><i>Regulatory Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Digital Health covers a broad spectrum of products, unless the founders have domain experience startups in this area usually discover the <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandTobacco/CDRH/default.htm">FDA</a> and the 510(k) process later than they should.<i> </i></li>
</ul>
<p><i>Venture Capital</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Seed funding is still scarce for Digital Health, but a number of startups (particularly those making physical personal heath tracking devices) are turning to crowdfunding.</li>
<li>Moreover, the absence of recent IPOs and public companies benchmarks creates uncertainty for VCs evaluating later investments too</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Try Something New<br />
</b>The fact that the status quo for Life Sciences is not working is not a new revelation. Lots of smart people are running experiments in search of ways to commercialize basic research  more efficiently.</p>
<p>Universities have set up <a href="http://ctsi.ucsf.edu/about-us">translational R&amp;D centers</a>; (basically university/company partnerships to commercialize research).  The National Institute of Health (NIH) is also setting up <a href="http://www.ncats.nih.gov/research/cts/ctsa/about/about.html">translational centers</a> through its <a href="http://www.ncats.nih.gov/about/about.html">NCATS program</a>.  Drug companies have tried to take research directly out of university labs by licensing patents, but once inside Pharma’s research labs, these projects get lost in the bureaucracy.  Realizing that this is not optimal, drug companies are trying to incubate projects directly with universities and the researchers who invented the technology, such as the recent <a href="http://www.janssenlabs.com" target="_blank">Janssen Labs</a> program.</p>
<p>But while these are all great programs, they are likely to fail to deliver on their promise<i>. The assumption that the pursuit of drugs, diagnostics, devices and digital health is all about the execution of the science is in most cases a mistake</i>.</p>
<p>The gap between the development of intriguing but unproven innovations, and the investment to commercialize those innovations is characterized as “the Valley of Death.”<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/valley-of-death.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14683" alt="valley of death" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/valley-of-death.png?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a></p>
<p>We believe we need a new model to attract private investment capital to fuel the commercialization of clinical solutions to todays major healthcare problems that is in many ways technology agnostic. We need a &#8220;Needs Driven/Business Model Driven&#8221; approach to solving the problems facing all  the stakeholders in the vast healthcare system.</p>
<p>We believe we can reduce the technological, regulatory and market risks for early-stage life science and healthcare ventures, and we can do it by teaching founding teams how to build new ventures with Evidence-Based Entrepreneurship.<b></b></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Part 3 in the next post will offer our hypothesis how to change the dynamics of the Life Sciences industry with a different approach to commercialization of research and innovation. And why you ought to take <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">this class</a>.</p>
<p>Listen to the post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14635_6-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span></p>
<p>Download the post <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/life-sciences/'>Life Sciences</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/science-and-industrial-policy/'>Science and Industrial Policy</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14635/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14635/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14635&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/20/reinventing-life-science-startups-medical-devices-and-digital-health/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" length="11126691" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/fda-approvals.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FDA approvals</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/life-science-decline.png?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Life Science Decline</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/med-device-pipeline.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">med device pipeline</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/digital-health-flow.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">digital health flow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/valley-of-death.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">valley of death</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130820.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reinventing Life Science Startups–Therapeutics and Diagnostics</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/19/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/19/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 13:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Industrial Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14621</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of Light, it was the season of Darkness, it was the spring of hope, it [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14621&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em>It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of Light, it was the season of Darkness, it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair, we had everything before us, we had nothing before us, we were all going direct to Heaven, we were all going direct the other way.</em></p>
<p align="center">Charles Dickens</p>
<p>Life Science (therapeutics- drugs to cure or manage diseases, diagnostics- tests and devices to find diseases, devices to cure and monitor diseases; and digital health –health care hardware, software and mobile devices and applications streamline and democratize the healthcare delivery system) is in the midst of a perfect storm of decreasing productivity, increasing regulation and the flight of venture capital.</p>
<p>But what if we could increase productivity and stave the capital flight by helping Life Sciences startups build their companies more efficiently?</p>
<p>We’re going to test this hypothesis by <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">teaching a Lean LaunchPad class for Life Sciences</a> and Healthcare (therapeutics, diagnostics, devices and digital health) this October at <a href="http://www.ucsf.edu/research" target="_blank">UCSF</a> with a team of veteran venture capitalists and angels.</p>
<p><b>It was the best of times and the worst of times<br />
</b>The last 60 years has seen remarkable breakthroughs in what we know about the biology underlying diseases and the science and engineering of developing commercial drug development and medical devices that improve and save lives. Turning basic science discoveries into drugs and devices seemed to be occurring at an ever increasing rate.</p>
<p>Yet during those same 60 years, rather than decreasing, the cost of getting a new drug approved by the FDA has <a href="http://www.maodl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JackScannellNatureMar2012.pdf" target="_blank">increased 80 fold</a>.  Yep, it cost 80 times more to get a successful drug developed and approved today than it did 60 years ago.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/overall-efficiency.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14611" alt="Overall efficiency" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/overall-efficiency.jpg?w=468&#038;h=488" width="468" height="488" /></a></p>
<p>75% or more of all the funds needed by a Life Science startup will be spent on clinical trials and regulatory approval. Pharma companies are staggering under the costs.  And medical device innovation in the U.S. has gone offshore primarily due to the toughened regulatory environment.</p>
<p>At the same time, Venture Capital, which had viewed therapeutics, diagnostics and medical devices as hot places to invest, is fleeing the field. In the last six years <a href="http://211.144.68.84:9998/91keshi/Public/File/49/30-5/pdf/nbt.2209.pdf" target="_blank">half the VC’s in the space have disappeared</a>, unable to raise new funds, and the number of biotech and device startups getting first round financing has dropped by half. For exits, acquisitions are the rule and IPOs the exception.</p>
<p>While the time, expense and difficulty to exit has soared in Life Sciences, all three critical factors have been cut by orders of magnitude in other investment sectors such as internet or social-local-mobile.  And while the vast majority of Life Science exits remain below $125M, other sectors have seen exit valuations soar.  It has gotten so bad that pension funds and other institutional investors in venture capital funds have told these funds to stay away from Life Science – or at the least, early stage Life Science.</p>
<p>WTF is going on?  And how can we change those numbers and reverse those trends?</p>
<p>We believe we have a small part of the answer.  And we are going to run an experiment to test it this fall at <a href="http://www.ucsf.edu" target="_blank">UCSF</a>.</p>
<p>In this three post series, the first two posts are a short summary of the complex challenges Life Science companies face; in Therapeutics and Diagnostics in this post and in Medical Devices and Digital Health in Part 2.  Part 3 explains our hypothesis about how to change the dynamics of the Life Sciences industry with a different approach to commercialization of research and innovation.  And why you ought to take <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">this class</a>.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<h3>Life Sciences I—Therapeutics and Diagnostics</h3>
<p><b>It was the Age of Wisdom – Drug Discovery<br />
</b>There are two types of drugs. The first, called small molecules (also referred to as New Molecular Entities or NMEs), are the bases for <a href="http://www.drugbank.ca/drugs" target="_blank">classic drugs such as aspirin</a>, <a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/statins.html" target="_blank">statins</a> or high blood pressure medicines. Small molecules are made by reactions between different organic and/or inorganic chemicals. In the last decade computers and synthesis methods in research laboratories enable chemists to test a series of reaction mixtures in parallel (<a href="https://www.google.com/url?url=http://scholar.google.com/scholar_url%3Fhl%3Den%26q%3Dhttp://www.researchgate.net/publication/6771160_From_in_vivo_to_in_silico_biology_and_back/file/72e7e51ade2a533381.pdf%26sa%3DX%26scisig%3DAAGBfm0lSCjjPrzqRwJ3jEiA1rqJFmqvOQ%26oi%3Dscholarr&amp;rct=j&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=HzYNUsyZDq2uiQfqoYDIAQ&amp;ved=0CCsQgAMoADAA&amp;q=in+vivo+versus+in+silico&amp;usg=AFQjCNHtmAIQW-T7dbW4K6nSKn_EXmQv-w" target="_blank">with wet lab analyses</a> still the gold standard.) Using high-throughput screening to search for small molecules, which can be a starting point (or lead compound) for a new drug, scientists can test thousands of candidate molecules against a database of millions in their libraries.</p>
<p>Ultimately the <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandTobacco/CDER/" target="_blank">FDA Center for Drug Evaluation and Research</a> (CDER) is responsible for the approval of small molecules drugs.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-discovery-pipeline.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14625" alt="Drug discovery pipeline" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-discovery-pipeline.jpg?w=468&#038;h=105" width="468" height="105" /></a></p>
<p>The second class of drugs created by biotechnology is called <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandTobacco/CBER/ucm133077.htm" target="_blank">biologics</a> (also referred to as New Biological Entities or NBEs.) In contrast to small molecule drugs that are chemically synthesized, most biologics are proteins, nucleic acids or cells and tissues. Biologics can be made from human, animal, or microorganisms &#8211; or produced by recombinant DNA technology. Examples of biologics include: vaccines, cell or <a href="http://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/handbook/therapy/genetherapy" target="_blank">gene therapies</a>, therapeutic protein hormones, <a href="http://pathmicro.med.sc.edu/mobile/m.immuno-13.htm" target="_blank">cytokines</a>, tissue growth factors, and <a href="http://www.cancerresearchuk.org/cancer-help/about-cancer/treatment/biological/types/about-monoclonal-antibodies" target="_blank">monoclonal antibodies</a>.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandTobacco/CBER/" target="_blank">FDA Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research</a> (CBER) is responsible for the approval of biologicals.</p>
<p><b>It was the Season of Light<br />
</b>The drug development pipeline for both small molecules and biologics can take 10-15 years and cost a billion dollars. The current process starts with testing thousands of compounds which will in the end, produce a single drug.</p>
<p>In the last few decades scientists searching for new drugs have had the benefit of new tools &#8212; <a href="http://seqcore.brcf.med.umich.edu/doc/educ/dnapr/sequencing.html" target="_blank">DNA sequencing</a>, <a href="http://www.wwpdb.org" target="_blank">3D protein database</a> for <a href="http://www.mpb.unige.ch/current-year/14F001/3D_theory.pdf" target="_blank">structure data</a>, <a href="http://www.broadinstitute.org/bbbc/linked_files/Zhang_JBiomolScr_1999.pdf" target="_blank">high throughput screening</a> for “hits”, computational drug design, etc. &#8212; which have sped up their search dramatically.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-funnel.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14627" alt="Drug funnel" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-funnel.jpg?w=468&#038;h=138" width="468" height="138" /></a></p>
<p>The problem is that the probability that a small molecule drug gets through clinical trials is <span style="text-decoration:underline;">unchanged</span> after 50 years. In spite of the substantial scientific advances and increased investment, over the last 20 years the FDA has approved an average of <a href="http://www.fda.gov/drugs/developmentapprovalprocess/druginnovation/default.htm" target="_blank">23 new drugs</a> a year. (To be fair, this is indication-dependent. For example, in oncology, things have gotten significantly better. In most other areas, particularly <a href="http://www.wwctrials.com/uploads/tx_wctpostersandpresentations/JCS_Dec_2011__Vol.3_Issue_6__Worldwide_Clinical_Trials_Death_of_CNS_Drug_Development.pdf" target="_blank">drugs for the central nervous system</a> and metabolism, they have not.)</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drugs-approved.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14613" alt="drugs approved" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drugs-approved.png?w=300&#038;h=171" width="300" height="171" /></a></p>
<p><b>It was the Season of Despair<br />
</b>With the exception of <a href="http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/factsheet/Therapy/targeted" target="_blank">targeted therapies</a>, the science and tools haven’t made the drug discovery pipeline more efficient. Oops.</p>
<p>There are lots of reasons why this has happened.</p>
<p><b></b><i>Regulatory and Reimbursement Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Drug safety is a high priority for the FDA. To avoid problems like Vioxx, Bexxar etc., the regulatory barriers (i.e. proof of safety) are huge, expensive, and take lots of time. That means the <a href="http://www.tipharma.com/fileadmin/user_upload/Theses/PDF/Jacoline_Bouvy_T6-202.pdf#page=72">FDA has gotten tougher</a>, requiring more clinical trials, and the stack of <a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/WhatWeDo/History/CentennialofFDA/CentennialEditionofFDAConsumer/ucm093787.htm">regulatory paperwork</a> has gotten higher.</li>
<li>Additional trials to demonstrate both clinical efficacy (if not superiority) and cost outcomes effectiveness are further driving up the cost, time and complexity of clinical trials.</li>
</ul>
<p><i>Drug Discovery Pipeline Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>The belief was that basic research + <a href="http://www.bio-itworld.com/BioIT_Article.aspx?id=86836" target="_blank">mass screening</a> would make the drug discovery pipeline more efficient. That’s hasn&#8217;t happened. There’s still a debate about why <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-throughput_screening">high throughput computer automated screening</a> - going from “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hit_to_lead">hits to leads</a>” – isn’t producing better than the manual animal-based screening it replaced. <i></i></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20130567" target="_blank">Biologics have a 2 ½ times higher success</a> rate in clinical trials than small molecules.</li>
</ul>
<p><i>Drug target Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>In a perfect world the goal is to develop a drug that will go after a single <a href="http://www.dddc.ac.cn/pdtd/" target="_blank">target</a> (a protein, enzyme, DNA/RNA, etc. that will undergo a specific interaction with chemicals or biological drugs) that is linked to a disease.</li>
<li>Unfortunately most diseases don’t work that simply. There are a few diseases that do, (i.e. <a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/druginfo/meds/a682611.html" target="_blank">insulin</a> and diabetes, <a href="http://www.cancer.gov/newscenter/qa/2001/gleevecqa" target="_blank">Gleevec</a> -<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philadelphia_chromosome" target="_blank">Philadelphia Chromosome</a> and chronic myeloid leukemia), but most <a href="http://www.bayerpharma.com/en/research-and-development/technologies/small-and-large-molecules/index.php" target="_blank">small molecule drugs</a> rarely act on a single target (<a href="http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/understandingcancer/targetedtherapies/htmlcourse/page1/AllPages" target="_blank">target-based therapy in oncology</a> being the bright spot.)</li>
<li>To get FDA approval new drugs have to be proven better than existing ones.  Most of the low-hanging fruit of easy drugs to develop are already on the market.</li>
</ul>
<p><i>Venture Capital Issues</i></p>
<ul>
<li>For the last two decades, biotech venture capital and corporate R&amp;D threw dollars into interesting science (find a new target, publish a paper in <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org" target="_blank">Science</a>, <a href="http://www.nature.com/nature" target="_blank">Nature</a> or <a href="http://www.cell.com/‎" target="_blank">Cell</a>, get funded.) The belief was that once a new target was found, finding a drug was a <i>technology</i> <i>execution </i>problem.  And all the new tools would accelerate the process.  It often didn&#8217;t turn out that way, although there are important exceptions.</li>
<li>Moreover, the prospect of the FDA also <a href="http://www.raps.org/focus-online/news/news-article-view/article/2847/iom-workshop-report-calls-for-fda-to-assess-products-based-on-cost-effectiveness.aspx" target="_blank">evaluating drugs for their cost-effectiveness</a> is adding another dimension of uncertainty as the market opportunity at the end of the funnel needs to be large enough to justify venture investment</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-dev-pipeline-funded.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14645" alt="drug dev pipeline funded" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-dev-pipeline-funded.jpg?w=468&#038;h=159"   /></a>In Part 2 of this series, we describe the challenges new Medical Device and Digital Health companies face.  Part 3 will offer our hypothesis how to change the dynamics of the Life Sciences industry with a different approach to commercialization of research and innovation in this sector.  And why you ought to take <a href="http://ita.ucsf.edu/entrepreneurship-center/education/courses/lean-launchpad-life-science-healthcare" target="_blank">this class</a>.<br />
Listen to the post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14621_7-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130819.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130819.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130819.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span><br />
Download the post <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/08/19/reinventing-life-science-startups-therapeutics-and-diagnostics/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/life-sciences/'>Life Sciences</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/science-and-industrial-policy/'>Science and Industrial Policy</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14621/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14621/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14621&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/19/reinventing-life-science-startups-evidence-based-entrepreneurship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130819.mp3" length="11549272" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/overall-efficiency.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Overall efficiency</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-discovery-pipeline.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Drug discovery pipeline</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-funnel.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Drug funnel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drugs-approved.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drugs approved</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/drug-dev-pipeline-funded.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drug dev pipeline funded</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130819.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130819.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to get meetings with people too busy to see you</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/12/how-to-get-meetings-with-people-too-busy-to-see-you/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/12/how-to-get-meetings-with-people-too-busy-to-see-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family/Career/Culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Asking, “Can I have coffee with you to pick your brain?” is probably the worst possible way to get a meeting with someone with a busy schedule.  Here’s a better approach. &#8212;&#8212; Jason, an entrepreneur I’ve known for over a decade, came out to the ranch today. He was celebrating selling his company and just [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14576&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Asking, “Can I have coffee with you to pick your brain?” is probably the worst possible way to get a meeting with someone with a busy schedule.  Here’s a better approach.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Jason, an entrepreneur I’ve known for over a decade, came out to the ranch today. He was celebrating selling his company and just beginning to think through his next moves. Since he wasn’t from Silicon Valley, he decided to use his time up here networking with other meetings with VC’s and company executives.</p>
<p>I get several hundred emails a day, and a good number of them are “I want to have coffee with you to bounce an idea off.” Or, “I just want to pick your brain.” I now have a filter for which emails get my attention, so I was curious in hearing what Jason, who I think of as pretty good at networking, was asking for when he was trying to set up meetings.</p>
<p>“Oh, I ask them if I can have coffee to bounce an idea off of them.”…Sigh.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/foot-in-the-door.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-14581" alt="foot in the door" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/foot-in-the-door.jpg?w=150&#038;h=89" width="150" height="89" /></a></p>
<p>I realized most entrepreneurs don&#8217;t know how to get meetings with people too busy to see you.</p>
<p><b>Perfect World<br />
</b>Silicon Valley has a <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/09/15/the-pay-it-forward-culture/">“pay-it-forward” culture</a> where we try to help each other without asking for anything in return. It’s a culture that emerged in the 60’s semiconductor business when competitors would help each other solve bugs in their chip fabrication process. It continued in the 1970’s with the emergence of the Homebrew Computer Club, and it continues today.  Since I teach, I tend to prioritize my list of meetings with first my current students, then ex-students, then referrals from VC firms I’ve invested in, and then others.  But still with that list, and now with a thousand plus ex-students, I have more meeting requests than I possibly can handle. (One of the filters I thought would keep down the meetings is have meetings at the ranch; an hour from Stanford on the coast, but that hasn&#8217;t helped.)</p>
<p>So I’ve come up with is a method to sort out who I take meetings with.</p>
<p><b>What are you offering?<br />
</b>I’m not an investor, and I’m really not looking for meetings with entrepreneurs for deal flow. I’m having these meetings because someone is asking for something from me – my time &#8211; and they think I can offer them advice.</p>
<p>If I’d had infinite time I’d take every one of these “can I have coffee” meetings. But I don’t.  So I now prioritize meetings with a new filter: Who is offering me something in return.</p>
<p>No, not offering me money.  Not for stock.  But who is offering to <i>teach me something I don’t know</i>.</p>
<p>The meeting requests that now jump to the top of my list are the few, very smart entrepreneurs who say, “I’d like to have coffee to bounce an idea off of you and <span style="text-decoration:underline;">in exchange I’ll tell you all about what we learned about xx.”</span></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-14582" alt="get into my head" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/get-into-my-head-e1375787209538.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></p>
<p>This offer of teaching me something changes the agenda of the meeting from a one-way, you’re learning from me, to a two-way, we’re learning from each other.</p>
<p>It has another interesting consequence for those who are asking for the meeting – it forces them to think about what is it they know and what is it they have learned – and whether they can explain it to others in a way that’s both coherent and compelling.</p>
<p><b>Irony – it’s Customer Discovery<br />
</b>While this might sound like a, “how to get a meeting with Steve” post, the irony is that this “ask for a two-way meeting” is how we teach entrepreneurs to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0989200507/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0989200507&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=wwwsteveblank-20" target="_blank">get their first customer discovery meetings</a>; don’t just ask for a potential customers time, instead offer to share what you’ve learned about a technology, market or industry.</p>
<p>It will increase your odds in any situation you’re asking for time from very busy people – whether they are VC’s, company executives or retired entrepreneurs.</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li><b>Lessons Learned</b></li>
<li>Wanting to have coffee is an ask for a favor</li>
<li>Offering to share knowledge is a different game</li>
<li>Try it, your odds of getting a meeting will increase</li>
<li>And the meetings will be more productive</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to this post here: <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14576_8-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130812.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130812.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130812.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> download the podcast <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/08/12/how-to-get-meetings-with-people-too-busy-to-see-you/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/familycareerculture/'>Family/Career/Culture</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14576&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/12/how-to-get-meetings-with-people-too-busy-to-see-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130812.mp3" length="5127889" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/foot-in-the-door.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">foot in the door</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/get-into-my-head-e1375787209538.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">get into my head</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130812.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130812.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Kevin O&#8217;Connor, and FindTheBest Got Lean</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/05/how-kevin-oconnor-and-findthebest-got-lean/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/05/how-kevin-oconnor-and-findthebest-got-lean/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14554</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When we started E.piphany there was an equally scrappy startup called DoubleClick (later acquired by Google for $3.1 billon). Over the years Kevin O&#8217;Connor, former CEO and founder of DoubleClick and I got to know each other.  It&#8217;s been fun watching a 20th Century entrepreneur learn new tricks as he builds his next startup, FindTheBest using Lean Methodology.  Here&#8217;s Kevin&#8217;s [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14554&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When we started <a href="http://steveblank.com/category/epiphany/" target="_blank">E.piphany</a> there was an equally scrappy startup called <a href="http://www.google.com/doubleclick/" target="_blank">DoubleClick</a> (later acquired by Google for $3.1 billon). Over the years Kevin O&#8217;Connor, former CEO and founder of DoubleClick and I got to know each other.  It&#8217;s been fun watching a 20th Century entrepreneur learn new tricks as he builds his next startup, FindTheBest using Lean Methodology.  Here&#8217;s Kevin&#8217;s story to date.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kevin_oconnor_headshot.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-14566" alt="kevin_oconnor_headshot" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kevin_oconnor_headshot.jpg?w=150&#038;h=134" width="150" height="134" /></a></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>You might say Steve and I have lived parallel lives. We’re both serial entrepreneurs. We’ve both used a combination of luck, hard work, and mild insanity to get where we are today. We’ve both published bestselling books.*<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/map_of_innovation_kevin_oconnor.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-14560" alt="map_of_innovation_kevin_oconnor" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/map_of_innovation_kevin_oconnor.png?w=118&#038;h=207" width="118" height="207" /></a></p>
<p>* Okay: my book sold way less copies than Steve’s.</p>
<p>Steve and I have long held similar beliefs about how to run start-ups, even if we’ve used different names to describe the key principles. He came down a few weeks ago to visit our company, <a href="http://www.findthebest.com/" target="_blank">FindTheBest</a>, where we <a href="http://blog.findthebest.com/2013/07/12/ftbu-a-fireside-chat-with-steve-blank/" target="_blank">chatted about his lean start-up concept</a> and held a Q&amp;A for the FindTheBest team and others in the Santa Barbara tech community. Here’s how our company is following the Steve Blank blueprint.</p>
<p>1. <strong>An Untested Hypothesis</strong><br />
<i>Lean Start-up Connection: </i><a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank"><i>Business Model Canvas</i></a></p>
<p>By 2009, I was fed up. I remember trying to search for the best college for my son and the top ski resort for a family vacation, only to find scam sites promoting a &#8220;top 10&#8243; list or &#8220;featured&#8221; options, meaning they were getting paid to promote them. Visiting each official site took too long, and the information wasn’t always easy to compare (ex: &#8220;Net Cost of Attendance” vs. &#8220;Resident Tuition per Semester”).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s when it hit me: what if there was a site where you get all the best information in one place, and have access to great research tools to help make a decision? What if you could think like an expert on any topic in a matter of minutes, instead of after hours of inefficient web browsing? Granted, the idea was a little crazy. To really be a game-changer, FindTheBest would have to compete against the thousands of niche sites that focus exclusively on a single market.</p>
<p>When we started building the site, we had to assume a lot. We figured our key partners would include consumers (to contribute data much like Wikipedia’s users), manufacturers (to keep their product information updated) and the US government (to supply datasets to power our content). We assumed our customers would be any smart Internet users looking to make a decision—granted, an extremely broad customer segment. We guessed that these customers would find value in the ability to make quick decisions on complicated topics. We hoped to start acquiring customers mostly through responsible, focused SEO, where we would target a variety of high-value search terms and provide relevant, useful content to users.</p>
<p>From day one, we knew our biggest cost would be hiring more employees, but we didn’t know exactly how much it would cost to enter each new market (ex: smartphones, then mountain bikes, then business schools, etc.). By leaning on our technology, we knew we could build cheaply, we just didn’t know how cheaply. We resolved to build out the first dozen comparisons before we started calculating an exact cost per new market.</p>
<p>Regarding revenue, we made a big bet on “purchase intent.” We looked at social sites—like Facebook and Twitter—with huge user bases, but comparably small revenue. We then looked at wildly profitable ventures—like Google or Kayak—noting that their users were much more likely to make purchases. When you enter a search query for “car insurance,” or submit details for a trip to London, you’re much more likely to end up spending money. We hypothesized that FindTheBest, with its focus on making big decisions, would attract the same purchase-minded users found on Google or Kayak.</p>
<p>We didn&#8217;t need to spend months researching; we just needed to create a viable product to test these hypotheses against. As we went out and started building, many people thought we were insane, stupid, or both. In fact, some probably still do.</p>
<div id="attachment_14562" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/dog_breeds_early_findthebest_screenshot.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14562  " alt="Our First FIndtheBest Wireframe" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/dog_breeds_early_findthebest_screenshot.png?w=300&#038;h=155" width="300" height="155" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A very early FindTheBest screenshot</p></div>
<p>2. <strong>Validation</strong><br />
<i>Lean Start-up Connection: </i><a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank"><i>Customer Development</i></a></p>
<p>Over the next couple of years, several of our hypotheses were confirmed. Thousands, then millions of new customers were coming to the site through SEO, just like we’d guessed with our customer acquisition hypothesis. Our assumptions about cost also proved correct—we were entering new markets incredibly cheaply. Here, we even beat our most optimistic assumptions.</p>
<p>Once we built out a sales team, revenue also started to grow nicely. We’ve confirmed our ability to harness purchase intent, like Google and Kayak before us, verifying our revenue stream hypothesis.</p>
<p>That said, a few of our hypotheses were proven at least partially wrong. First, our assumption that consumers would be a key supplier of content (like Wikipedia contributors) was wrong. While user adds and edits grew at a small rate, it wasn&#8217;t nearly enough to support the hundreds of topics on the site. Visitors loved using the site to research new topics, but were less likely to add their own listings or consistently update old content. Our customers had identified a flaw in our original plan. We realized our internal team would need to be bigger, and adjusted our business model canvas accordingly .</p>
<p>Additionally, our value proposition needed adjustment. We had focused on <i>quick </i>decisions, when really, users wanted a sophisticated research tool for making carefully considered decisions. As a result, we’ve had to adjust our positioning and messaging to better capture the value users see in our product. We’re now promoting FindTheBest as a research hub that helps you think like an expert, much closer to what users were telling us in feedback surveys.</p>
<p>3. Staying Agile<br />
<i>Lean Start-up Connection: </i><i><a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank">Agile Development</a></i></p>
<p>At FindTheBest, we constantly practice a &#8220;test-fail-learn-test-succeed-scale&#8221; approach, which is simply another way of describing the philosophy of &#8220;agile development.&#8221; We&#8217;re happy to fail, as long as we do so quickly, learn the appropriate lesson, and move to a new hypothesis. Once we find one that works, we scale the hell out of it.</p>
<p>For example, we tested out two features early on that didn&#8217;t end up as popular as we&#8217;d wanted: video guides (a how-to video about researching the topic) and green guides (an environmental report on which products and services were most eco-friendly). Each time, we hoped to capture a new audience by appealing to a specific subset of Internet users. We rolled them out on a limited number of pages to test. Once we saw that these new guides weren&#8217;t attracting significant visits or creating increased interaction, we quickly ended the projects.</p>
<p>On the flip side, we&#8217;ve had many major successes that have helped inform our product’s direction. Sister sites <a href="http://www.findthedata.org/" target="_blank">FindTheData</a> (a site for researching huge datasets on topics like crime, salaries, and government spending) and <a href="http://www.findthecompany.com/" target="_blank">FindTheCompany</a> (a tool for finding key information on millions of companies and organizations) have grown user bases of several million visitors per month. We&#8217;ve found that people love our platform and use our technology for doing research in a variety of different ways.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p>At just 3 years in, FindTheBest is real-time proof of Steve Blank&#8217;s <a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank">lean start-up blueprint</a>. Even as we make the transition from startup to established company (which I call “company puberty”), we&#8217;ll continue to test our hypotheses, seek customer feedback, and test before we scale.</p>
<p>Hopefully we&#8217;ll find that FindTheBest will have a bigger exit than DoubleClick &#8211; this time as a Lean Startup.<br />
Listen to this post here: <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14554_9-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fclearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3">clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> Download the podcast <a href="http://www.clearshore.net/2013/08/05/how-kevin-oconnor-and-findthebest-got-lean/" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14554/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14554/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14554&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/08/05/how-kevin-oconnor-and-findthebest-got-lean/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3" length="9398386" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3" length="9398386" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3" length="9398386" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3" length="9398386" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kevin_oconnor_headshot.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kevin_oconnor_headshot</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/map_of_innovation_kevin_oconnor.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">map_of_innovation_kevin_oconnor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/dog_breeds_early_findthebest_screenshot.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Our First FIndtheBest Wireframe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130805.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building Great Founding Teams</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/29/building-great-founding-teams/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/29/building-great-founding-teams/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family/Career/Culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That he which hath no stomach to this fight, let him depart&#8230;We few, we happy few, we band of brothers. William Shakespeare, Henry Vth There’s been a lot written about the individual characteristics of what makes a great founder, but a lot less about what makes a great founding team and how that’s different from [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14313&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><q cite="http://quotationsbook.com/quote/3024/"><em><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=680NlRI3v2I" target="_blank">That he which hath no stomach to this fight, let him depart&#8230;We few, we happy few, we band of brothers</a></em>.</q></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">William Shakespeare, Henry Vth</p>
</div>
<p>There’s been a lot written about the individual characteristics of what makes a great <i>founder</i>, but a lot less about what makes a great <i>founding</i> <i>team</i> and how that’s different from a great <em>founding</em>  <i>CEO</i></p>
<p><i><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/founders1.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-14317" alt="founders" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/founders1.jpg?w=270&#038;h=257" width="270" height="257" /></a></i></p>
<p>I think we’ve been imprecise in defining three different roles. In doing so we&#8217;ve failed to help founders understand what it takes to build a great founding team.</p>
<p>Here are my definitions.</p>
<p><b>Founders &#8211; the idea<br />
</b><i>A Founder</i> is the one with the original idea, scientific discovery, technical breakthrough, insight, problem description, passion, etc. A founder typically recruits co-founders and then becomes part of the founding team involved in day-to-day company operations. (However, in some industries such as life sciences, founders may be tenured professors who are not going to give up their faculty positions, so they often become the head of a startup’s scientific advisory board, but aren’t part of the founding team.)</p>
<p>A couple of caveats about founders with “ideas.”  It&#8217;s important to differentiate between ideas that have been or can be patented and ideas thought up late night in a dorm-room. One of the hardest concepts for my students to grasp is that “<i>an idea is not a company</i>.”  The reality is that in most cases, without the company to commercialize it, the idea is worthless (except to a <a href="https://www.eff.org/issues/resources-patent-troll-victims">patent troll</a>.)</p>
<p>Even if they become part of the founding team, it’s not a given that the founder, having come up with the idea has a &#8220;guaranteed&#8221; leadership role (CEO or VP) in the new company. For some entrepreneurs this idea that the founder is not necessarily the CEO, is a surprise. When I hear, &#8220;What do you mean I&#8217;m not CEO? It&#8217;s my idea!&#8221; I get nervous that the founder is clueless about what makes the founding CEO special, and what else it actually takes to build a company. (Read on to see the difference in the roles.)</p>
<p><b>Founding Team – the rock on which to build the company<br />
</b>The <i>founding team </i>includes the founder and a few other co-founders with complementary skills to the founder. <i>This is the group who will build the company</i>. Its goal is to take the original idea and <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/03/05/search-versus-execute/" target="_blank">search for a repeatable and scalable business model</a>- first by finding product/market fit, then by testing all the parts of the business model (pricing, channel, acquisition/activation, partners, costs, etc.)</p>
<p>In web/mobile startups the canonical view is the founding team consists of a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/04/10/dave-mcclure-on-500-startups-if-sequoia-is-the-yankees-were-the-oakland-as/">hacker, a hustler, and a designer</a>. In other domains, the skill sets differ, but the key idea is that you want a team with <i>complementary</i> skills.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/band-of-brothers.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-14319" alt="Band of Brothers" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/band-of-brothers.jpg?w=300&#038;h=168" width="300" height="168" /></a></p>
<p>There’s no magic number about the “right” number of founders for a founding team, but two to four seems to be the sweet spot. One of the biggest mistakes in assembling a founding team is not thinking through the need for skills but instead settling for who’s around. The two tests of whether someone belongs on a founding team are: “Do we have a company without them?” and, “Can we find someone else just like them?” If both answers are no, you’ve identified a co-founder.  If any of the answers are “Yes,” then hire them a bit later as an early employee.</p>
<p>Key attributes of an entrepreneur on a founding team are <i>passion, determination, resilience, tenacity, agility and curiosity</i>. It helps if the team has had a history of working together, but what is essential is mutual respect. And what is critical is trust. You need to be able to trust your co-founders to perform, to do what they say they will, and to have your back.</p>
<p>Most startups that fail over team issues fail because co-founders hadn’t dated first, (spent time together in a <a href="http://startupweekend.org" target="_blank">Startup Weekend</a>, worked together in an <a href="http://www.techstars.com" target="_blank">incubator</a>, etc.) but instead jumped into bed to start a company.</p>
<p>Everyone has ideas. It&#8217;s the courage, passion and tenacity of the founding team that turn ideas into businesses.</p>
<p><b>Founding CEO – Reality Distortion Field and </b><b>Comfort in Chaos</b><br />
Idealistic founders trying to run a venture with collective leadership, without a single person in charge, find that’s the fastest way to go out of business. <a href="http://steveblank.com/2009/04/10/good-enough-decision-making/" target="_blank">Speed, tempo and fearless decision-making</a> are a startups strategic advantage. More often than not, conditions on the ground will change so rapidly that the need for immediate decisions overwhelms a collective decision process.</p>
<p>The founding <i>team CEO</i> is the first among equals in the founding team. Ironically they are almost never the most intelligent or technically astute person on the team. What sets them apart from the rest of the team is that they can project a fearless <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field"><i>reality distortion field</i></a> that they use to <em>recruit, fund raise, pivot and position</em> the company. They are the ultimate true believers in the company and have the <em>vision, passion and skill to communicate</em> why this seemingly crazy idea will work and change the world.</p>
<p>In addition, the founding CEO <a href="http://steveblank.com/2009/05/18/founders-and-dysfunctional-families/" target="_blank">thrives operating in chaos and uncertainty</a>. They deal with the daily crisis of product development and acquiring early customers.  And as the reality of product development and customer input collide, the facts change so rapidly that the original well-thought-out product plan becomes irrelevant. While the rest of the team is focused on their specific jobs, the founding CEO is trying to solve a complicated equation where almost all the variables are unknown – unknown customers, unknown features that will make those customers buy, unknown pricing, unknown demand creation activities that will get them into your sales channel, etc.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re biased for action and they don&#8217;t wait around for someone else to tell them what to do. Great founding CEO&#8217;s live for these moments.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cRj01LShXN8"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14545" alt="Henry V" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/henry-v.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a></p>
<p><strong>FIgure out who you are<br />
</strong>Many founding teams fail because they&#8217;ve never had the conversation about founder, founding team and founding CEO.  Spend the time and take stock of who&#8217;s on the journey with you.</p>
<p><b>Lessons Learned</b></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Founder, Founding team, Founding CEO all have word &#8220;founder&#8221; in them but have different roles</li>
<li><i>Founder</i> has the initial idea. May or may not be on the founding team or have a leadership role</li>
<li>Founding <i>team</i> – complementary skills – builds the company</li>
<li>Founding <i>CEO</i> – reality distortion field and comfort in chaos – leads the company</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to this post here: <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14313_10-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fclearshore_steveblank_130729.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130729.mp3">clearshore_steveblank_130729.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> Download the podcast <a href="http://www.clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/familycareerculture/'>Family/Career/Culture</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14313/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14313/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14313&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/29/building-great-founding-teams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130729.mp3" length="8119447" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/founders1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">founders</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/band-of-brothers.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Band of Brothers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/henry-v.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Henry V</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130729.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile= http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/clearshore_steveblank_130729.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An MVP is not a Cheaper Product, It’s about Smart Learning</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/22/an-mvp-is-not-a-cheaper-product-its-about-smart-learning/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/22/an-mvp-is-not-a-cheaper-product-its-about-smart-learning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14288</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A minimum viable product (MVP) is not always a smaller/cheaper version of your final product. Defining the goal for a MVP can save you tons of time, money and grief. Drones over the Heartland I ran into a small startup at Stanford who wants to fly Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (drones) with a Hyper-spectral camera over [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14288&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A minimum viable product (MVP) is not always a smaller/cheaper version of your final product. Defining the goal for a MVP can save you tons of time, money and grief.</p>
<p><b>Drones over the Heartland<br />
</b>I ran into a small startup at Stanford who wants to fly Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (drones) with a <a href="http://www.microimages.com/documentation/Tutorials/hyprspec.pdf" target="_blank">Hyper-spectral camera</a> over farm fields to collect <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperspectral_imaging" target="_blank">hyper-spectral images</a>. These images would be able to tell farmers how healthy their plants were, whether there were diseases or bugs, whether there was enough fertilizer, and enough water. (The camera has enough resolution to see individual plants.) Knowing this means farms can make better forecasts of how much their fields will produce, whether they should treat specific areas for pests, and put fertilizer and water only where it was needed.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/drone-over-farm.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-14291" alt="drone over farm" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/drone-over-farm.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>(Drones were better than satellites because of higher resolution and the potential for making more passes over the fields, and better than airplanes because of lower cost.)</p>
<p>All of this information would help farmers increase yields (making more money) and reduce costs by using less water and fertilizer/chemicals but only applying where it was needed.</p>
<p>Their plan was to be a data service provider in an emerging business called “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_agriculture" target="_blank">precision agriculture</a>.” They would go out to a farmer fields on a weekly basis, fly the drones, collect and process the data and then give it to the farmers in an easy understandable form.</p>
<p><b>Customer Discovery on Farms<br />
</b>I don’t know what it is about Stanford, but this was the fourth or fifth startup I’ve seen in precision agriculture that used drones, <a href="http://bluerivert.com" target="_blank">robotics</a>, high-tech sensors, etc.  This team got my attention when they said, “Let us tell you about our conversations with potential customers.”  I listened, and as they described their customer interviews, it seemed like they had found, that – yes, farmers do understand that not being able to see what was going on in detail on their fields was a problem – and yes, &#8211; having data like this would be great – in theory.</p>
<p>So the team decided that this felt like a real business they wanted to build.  And now they were out raising money to build a prototype minimum viable product (MVP.) All good.  Smart team, real domain experts in hyper-spectral imaging, drone design, good start on customer discovery, beginning to think about product/market fit, etc.</p>
<p><b>Lean is Not an Engineering Process<br />
</b>They showed me their goals and budget for their next step. What they wanted was a happy early customer who recognized the value of their data and is willing to be an evangelist.  Great goal.</p>
<p>They concluded that the only way to get a delighted early customer was to build a minimum viable product (MVP). They believed that the MVP needed to, 1) demonstrate a drone flight, 2) make sure their software could stitch together all the images of a field, and then 3) present the data to the farmer in a way he could use it.</p>
<p>And they logically concluded that the way to do this was to buy a drone, buy a <a href="http://www.spectralcameras.com/aisa" target="_blank">hyper-spectral camera</a>, buy the software for image processing, spend months of engineering time integrating the camera, platform and software together, etc.  They showed me their barebones budget for doing all this. Logical.</p>
<p>And wrong.</p>
<p><b>Keep Your Eyes on the Prize<br />
</b>The team confused the goal of the MVP, (seeing if they could find a delighted farmer who would pay for the data) with the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">process</span> of getting to the goal.  They had the right goal but the wrong MVP to test it.  Here’s why.</p>
<p>The teams’ hypothesis was that they could deliver actionable data that farmers would pay for.  Period.  Since the startup defined itself as a <i>data services </i>company, at the end of the day, the farmer couldn&#8217;t care less whether the data came from satellites, airplanes, drones, or magic as long as they had timely information.</p>
<p>That meant that all the work about buying a drone, a camera, software and time integrating it all was wasted time and effort &#8211; now. They did <span style="text-decoration:underline;">not</span> need to test any of that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">yet</span>. (There’s plenty of existence proofs that <a href="http://www.dji-innovations.com/" target="_blank">low cost drones can be equipped to carry cameras</a>.) They had defined the wrong MVP to test first. What they needed to spend their time is first testing is <i>whether farmers cared about the data.</i></p>
<p>So I asked, “Would it be cheaper to <i>rent</i> a camera and plane or helicopter, and fly over the farmers field, hand process the data and see if that’s the information farmers would pay for?  Couldn’t you do that in a day or two, for a tenth of the money you&#8217;re looking for?”  Oh…</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shortcut.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14293 aligncenter" alt="Shortcut" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shortcut.jpg?w=300&#038;h=266" width="300" height="266" /></a>They thought about it for a while and laughed and said, “We’re engineers and we wanted to test all the cool technology, but you want us to test whether we first have a product that customers care about and whether it’s a business.   We can do that.”</p>
<p>Smart team.  They left thinking about how to redefine their MVP.</p>
<p><b>Lessons Learned</b></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>A minimum viable product is not always a smaller/cheaper version of your final product</li>
<li>Think about cheap hacks to test the goal</li>
<li>Great founders keep their eye on the prize</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14288_11-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130722.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130722.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130722.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> Or download the podcast <a href="http://clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14288/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14288/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14288&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/22/an-mvp-is-not-a-cheaper-product-its-about-smart-learning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130722.mp3" length="6765691" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/drone-over-farm.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drone over farm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shortcut.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Shortcut</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130722.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130722.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Computer May Already be Hacked – NSA Inside?</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/15/your-computer-may-already-be-hacked-nsa-inside/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/15/your-computer-may-already-be-hacked-nsa-inside/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secret History of Silicon Valley]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In a time of universal deceit &#8211; telling the truth is a revolutionary act. George Orwell In Russia, President Putin’s office just stopped using PC’s and switched to typewriters.  What do they know that we don’t? Perhaps it’s Intel NSA inside. &#8212;&#8212;&#8212; For those of you who haven’t kept up, the National Security Agency (NSA’s) Prism [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14203&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">In a time of universal deceit &#8211; telling the truth is a revolutionary act.<br />
<em>George Orwell</em></p>
<p>In Russia, President Putin’s office just <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/kremlins-response-to-snowdens-revelations-of-nsa-surveillance-switch-to-typewriters/2013/07/11/52e1e074-ea3e-11e2-818e-aa29e855f3ab_story.html" target="_blank">stopped using PC’s and switched to typewriters</a>.  What do they know that we don’t?</p>
<p>Perhaps it’s <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?NR=1&amp;feature=endscreen&amp;v=VRcAdXd-TRU" target="_blank"><del>Intel</del></a> NSA inside.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">For those of you who haven’t kept up, the National Security Agency (NSA’s) <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/us-intelligence-mining-data-from-nine-us-internet-companies-in-broad-secret-program/2013/06/06/3a0c0da8-cebf-11e2-8845-d970ccb04497_print.html" target="_blank">Prism</a> program has been <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/nsa" target="_blank">in the news</a>. Prism provides the NSA with access to <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jun/06/us-tech-giants-nsa-data" target="_blank">data on the servers of Microsoft, Google, Facebook</a>, etc, extracting audio and video chats, photographs, e-mails, documents, etc.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Prism is just a part of the NSA’s larger <a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/secret-prism-success-even-bigger-data-seizure" target="_blank">mass electronic surveillance</a> program that <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/for-nsa-chief-terrorist-threat-drives-passion-to-collect-it-all/2013/07/14/3d26ef80-ea49-11e2-a301-ea5a8116d211_story.html" target="_blank">covers every possible path</a> someone might use to communicate; tapping raw data as it flows through fiber optic cables and <a href="http://publicintelligence.net/binney-nsa-declaration/" target="_blank">Internet peering points</a>, copying the addressees <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/04/us/monitoring-of-snail-mail.html" target="_blank">on all letters you physically mail</a>, all credit card purchases, <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/interactive/2013/jun/27/nsa-inspector-general-report-document-data-collection" target="_blank">your phone calls</a> and your location (courtesy your smart phone.)<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide03.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14205 aligncenter" alt="Slide03" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide03.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>All hell broke loose when <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden" target="_blank">Edward Snowden</a> leaked all this to press.</p>
<p>Given my talks on <a href="http://steveblank.com/secret-history/" target="_blank">the Secret History of Silicon Valley</a> I was interviewed on NPR about the disclosure that the NSA said they had a new capability that tripled the amount of Skype video calls being collected through Prism. Like most Americans I said, &#8220;I didn&#8217;t remember getting the memo that the <a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/fourth_amendment" target="_blank">4th amendment</a> to our constitution had been cancelled.&#8221;</p>
<p>But while the interviewer focused on the Skype revelation, I thought the most interesting part was the other claim, “that the National Security Agency already <i><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jul/11/microsoft-nsa-collaboration-user-data" target="_blank">had pre-encryption stage access to email on Outlook</a>.</i>”  Say what??  They can see the plaintext on my computer before I encrypt it? That defeats any/all encryption methods. How could they do that?</p>
<p><b>Bypass Encryption<br />
</b>While most outside observers think the NSA’s job is cracking encrypted messages, as the Prism disclosures have shown, the actual mission is simply to read all communications. Cracking codes is a last resort.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14207 aligncenter" alt="Slide04" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide04.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></p>
<p>The NSA has a history of figuring out how to get to messages <em>before or after</em> they are encrypted. Whether it was by putting <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keystroke_logging" target="_blank">keyloggers</a> on keyboards and recording the keystrokes or detecting the images of the characters as they were being drawn on a CRT.</p>
<p>Today every desktop and laptop computer has another way for the NSA to get inside.</p>
<p><b>Intel Inside<br />
</b>It’s inevitable that complex microprocessors have bugs in them when they ship. When the first microprocessors shipped the only thing you could hope is that the bug didn&#8217;t crash your computer. The only way the chip vendor could fix the problem was to physically revise the chip and put out a new version. But computer manufacturers and users were stuck if you had an old chip. After a particularly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentium_FDIV_bug" target="_blank">embarrassing math bug in 1994</a> that cost Intel $475 million, the company decided to fix the problem by allowing it’s microprocessors to load fixes automatically when your computer starts.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14220 aligncenter" alt="Slide05" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide05.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></p>
<p>Starting in 1996 with the Intel P6 (Pentium Pro) to today’s P7 chips (Core i7) these processors contain instructions that are reprogrammable in what is called microcode. Intel can fix bugs on the chips by reprogramming a microprocessors microcode with a patch. This patch, called a <a href="http://www.ing-steen.se/share/unix/kernel/microcode/microcode.pdf" target="_blank"><i>microcode update</i></a>, can be loaded into a processor by using special CPU instructions reserved for this purpose. These updates are not permanent, which means each time you turn the computer on, its microprocessor is reset to its built-in microcode, and the update needs to be applied again (through a computer&#8217;s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS" target="_blank">BIOS</a>.).</p>
<p>Since 2000, Intel has put out 29 <a href="http://www.intel.com/content/dam/www/public/us/en/documents/specification-updates/2nd-gen-core-desktop-specification-update.pdf" target="_blank">microcode updates</a> to their processors. The microcode is distributed by 1) Intel or by 2) Microsoft integrated into a BIOS or 3) as part of a <a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2493989" target="_blank">Windows update</a>. Unfortunately, the microcode update format is undocumented and the code is <a href="ipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Hash_Algorithm" target="_blank">encrypted</a>. This allows Intel to make sure that 3<sup>rd</sup> parties can’t make unauthorized add-ons to their chips. But it also means that no one can look inside to <a href="http://inertiawar.com/microcode/archive/" target="_blank">understand the microcode</a>, which makes it is impossible to know whether anyone is loading a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backdoor_(computing)" target="_blank">backdoor</a> into your computer.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><b>The Dog That Never Barked<br />
</b>The NSA has been incredibly <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/interactive/2013/jun/20/exhibit-b-nsa-procedures-document" target="_blank">thorough</a> in nailing down <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/for-nsa-chief-terrorist-threat-drives-passion-to-collect-it-all/2013/07/14/3d26ef80-ea49-11e2-a301-ea5a8116d211_story.html" target="_blank">every possible way</a> to tap into communications. Yet the one company’s name that hasn&#8217;t come up as part of the surveillance network is Intel. Perhaps they are the only good guys in the entire Orwellian mess.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide07.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14222 aligncenter" alt="Slide07" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide07.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Or perhaps the NSA, working with Intel and/or Microsoft, have wittingly have put backdoors in the microcode updates. A <a href="http://cm.bell-labs.com/who/ken/trust.html" target="_blank">backdoor</a> is is a way of gaining illegal remote access to a computer by getting around the normal security built-in to the computer. Typically someone trying to sneak malicious software on to a computer would try to install a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rootkit" target="_blank">rootkit</a> (software that tries to conceal the malicious code.) A rootkit tries to hide itself and its code, but security conscious sites can discover rootkits by tools that check kernel code and data for changes.</p>
<p>But what if you could use the <a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpls/abs_all.jsp?arnumber=4531160" target="_blank">configuration and state of microprocessor hardware in order to hide</a>? You&#8217;d be invisible to all rootkit detection techniques that checks the operating system. Or what if you can make the microprocessor random number generator (the basis of encryption) not so random for a particular machine? (<a href="http://rense.com/politics2/crypto.htm" target="_blank">The NSA&#8217;s biggest coup was</a> inserting backdoors in crypto equipment the Swiss sold to other countries.)</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>Rather than risk getting caught messing with everyone’s updates, my bet is that the NSA has <a href="http://inertiawar.com/microcode/" target="_blank">compromised the microcode update signing keys</a>  giving the NSA the ability to selectively target specific computers. (Your operating system ensures security of updates by checking downloaded update packages against the signing key.) The NSA then can send out backdoors disguised as a Windows update for “security.&#8221; (Ironic but possible.)</p>
</div>
<p>That means you don&#8217;t need backdoors baked in the hardware, don&#8217;t need Intel&#8217;s buy-in, don&#8217;t have discoverable rootkits, and you can target specific systems without impacting the public at large.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Two Can Play the Game<br />
</strong>A few months ago these kind of discussions <a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpls/abs_all.jsp?arnumber=4531160&amp;tag=1" target="_blank">would have been theory</a> at best, if not paranoia. <a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide09.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14224 aligncenter" alt="Slide09" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide09.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a>The Prism disclosures prove otherwise &#8211; the National Security Agency has decided it needs the ability to capture all communications in all forms. Getting inside of a target computer and weakening its encryption or having access to the plaintext of encrypted communication seems likely. Given the technical sophistication of the other parts of their surveillance net, the surprise would be if they <em>haven&#8217;t</em> implemented a microcode backdoor.</p>
<p>The downside is that 1) backdoors can be hijacked by others with even worse intent. So if NSA has a microcode backdoor &#8211; who else is using it? and 2) What other pieces of our infrastructure, (routers, smartphones, military computers, satellites, etc) use processors with uploadable microcode?</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>And that may be why the Russian president is now using a typewriter rather than a personal computer.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/special/politics/prism-collection-documents/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14210 aligncenter" alt="Putin's Typewriter" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shutterstock_71071150.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" width="300" height="200" /></a><span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>Update</strong></span>: I asked Intel:</p>
<ul>
<li>Has Intel received any <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_security_letter" target="_blank">National Security Letters</a>?</li>
<li>If you had received a National Security Letter would you be able to tell us that you did?</li>
<li>has Intel ever been <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/16/us/double-secret-surveillance.html?_r=0" target="_blank">contacted by anyone in the U.S. government</a> about Microcode Updates or the signing keys?</li>
<li>Does anyone outside of Intel have knowledge of the Microcode Updates format or the signing keys?</li>
<li>Does anyone outside of Intel have access to the Microcode Updates or the signing key</li>
</ul>
<p>Intel&#8217;s response from their Director of Corporate and Legal Affairs (<em>italics </em>mine):</p>
<p>&#8220;First, I have no idea whether we’ve ever received a National Security Letter <em>and don’t intend on spending any time trying to find out.  It’s not something we would talk about in any case</em>, regardless of the subject of your blog.</p>
<div lang="EN-US">
<div>Second, the questions related microcode and the speculative portion of your blog related to our encryption of microcode and the key all seem to focus around one question:  Do <em>we</em> have backdoors available as a result of our microcode download encryption scheme?</div>
<div>The answer is NO.  Only Intel has that knowledge.&#8221;</div>
</div>
<p><strong><span style="color:#ff0000;">Update 2</span></strong>:  A much better description of the problem was actually presented a year ago at Defcon</p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/13791171' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>if you can&#8217;t see the presentation above click <a href="http://es.slideshare.net/endrazine/defcon-hardware-backdooring-is-practical" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p>Listen to the post here:<span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14203_12-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> Or download the podcast <a href="http://clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/secret-history-of-silicon-valley/'>Secret History of Silicon Valley</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14203/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14203/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14203&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/15/your-computer-may-already-be-hacked-nsa-inside/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" length="10566403" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide03.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide04.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide05.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide07.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/slide09.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slide09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shutterstock_71071150.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Putin&#039;s Typewriter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130715.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don’t Give Away Your Board Seats</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/09/dont-give-away-your-board-seats/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/09/dont-give-away-your-board-seats/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 13:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I had a group of ex-students out to the ranch who were puzzling over a dilemma – they’ve been working hard on their startup, were close at finding product/market fit and had been approached by Oren, a potential angel investor. Oren had been investing since he left Google four years ago and was insisting on [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14178&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had a group of ex-students out to the ranch who were puzzling over a dilemma – they’ve been working hard on their startup, were close at finding product/market fit and had been approached by Oren, a potential angel investor. Oren had been investing since he left Google four years ago and was insisting on not only a board seat, but he wanted to be chairman of the board. The team wasn&#8217;t sure what to do.</p>
<p>I listened for a while as they went back and forth about whether he should be chairman. Then I asked, “Why should he even be on your board at all?”  I got looks of confusion and then they said, “We thought all investors get a board seat. At least that’s what Oren told us.”</p>
<p>Uh oh.  Red flags just appeared in front of my eyes. I realized it was time for the board of directors versus advisors talk.</p>
<p><b>Roles for Financial Investors<br />
</b>I pointed out that there are four roles a financial investor can take in your company: a board member, a board observer (a non-voting attendee of board meetings,) an advisory board member, or no active role. I explained that as a non-public company there was no legal requirement for any investor to have a board seat. Period. That said, professional venture capital firms that lead a Series investment round usually make their investment contingent on a board seat. And it sounded like if successful, their startup was going to need additional funding past an angel round to scale.</p>
<p>In the last few years, it’s become more common for angel investors to ask for a board seat, but I suggested they really want to think hard about whether that’s something they need to do now.</p>
<p>“But how do we get the advice we need? We’re getting to the point that we have lots of questions about strategic choices and relationships. Isn’t that what a board is for?  That’s what we learned in business school.”</p>
<p><b>What’s a board for?<br />
</b>I realized that while my students had been through the theory it was time for some practice. So I told them, “At the end of the day your board is not your friend. You may like them and they might like you, but they have a fiduciary duty to the shareholders, not the founders. (And they have a fiduciary responsibility to their own limited partners.) That means the board is your boss, and they have an obligation to optimize results for the company. You may be the ex-employees one day if they think you’re holding the company back.”<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/board-fight.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-14187" alt="Board Fight" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/board-fight.png?w=160&#038;h=180" width="160" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>I let that sink it for a bit and then asked, “How long have you worked with Oren?”</p>
<p>I kind of expected the answer, but still was a bit disappointed. “Well we met him twice, once over coffee and then over lunch.”</p>
<p>“You want to think hard about appointing someone to be your boss just because they’re going to write you what in the scheme of things will be a small check.”</p>
<p>Now they looked really confused. “But we need people with great advice who we can help us with our next moves.”</p>
<p><b>Advisory Board<br />
</b>“Do you know what an advisory board is?” I asked.  From the look on their faces, I realized they didn’t so I continued, “Advisors are just like they sound. They provide advice, introductions, investment, and visual theater &#8211; (proof that you can attract A+ talent.) An advisor that provides a combination of at least two of these is useful.”</p>
<p>A “board” of advisors is not a formal legal entity like a board of directors. That means that they can’t fire you or have any control of your company. While some founders like to meet their advisors in quarterly advisory board meetings, most companies don’t really have their advisory board meet as group. You can connect with them with them on an “as needed” basis. While you traditionally compensate advisors by giving them stock, I suggest you ask them to match any grant with an equal investment in the company – so they have “skin in the game.”</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shutterstock_704584871.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-14190" alt="shutterstock_70458487" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shutterstock_704584871.jpg?w=150&#038;h=106" width="150" height="106" /></a>Equally important is that an advisory board is a great farm team for potential outside board members. It allows you to work with them over an extended period of time and see the quality of their advice and how it’s delivered. If they are world-class contributors, when you raise a Series A round and you need to bring in an outside board member, picking someone you’ve worked with on your advisory board is ideal.”</p>
<p>Finally I suggested that Oren’s request to be chairman of a five-person startup seemed to be coming from someone looking to upgrade their resume, not to optimize their startup.</p>
<p><b>No Outsiders Until a Series A<br />
</b>As we wrapped up, I offered that there was no “right answer” (see <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/accelerators/2013/06/17/brad-feld-start-building-your-board-early/" target="_blank">Brad Feld&#8217;s post</a>) but they should think about their board strategy as a balance between the amount of control given to outsiders versus the great advice outsiders can bring. I suggested that if they could pull it off they might want to consider keeping the board to the two founders for now, surrounded by great advisors which may include their seed investors. Then when they got a Series A, they&#8217;ll probably add one or two professional VC’s on the board with one great advisor as an outside board member.</p>
<p>As they left they were going through the experienced execs they knew who they were going to take out for coffee.</p>
<p><strong>Lessons Learned</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Your board of directors is your boss</li>
<li>Your advisory board is your friend</li>
<li>Not all investors get board seats, it&#8217;s your choice</li>
<li>Date advisors, marry board members</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the post here <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14178_13-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span><br />
or download the podcast <a href="http://clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/venture-capital/'>Venture Capital</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14178/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14178&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/07/09/dont-give-away-your-board-seats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3" length="7685204" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/board-fight.png?w=267" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Board Fight</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/shutterstock_704584871.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutterstock_70458487</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Defense of Unreasonableness &#8211; Saving the California Coast</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/28/in-defense-of-unreasonableness-saving-the-california-coast/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/28/in-defense-of-unreasonableness-saving-the-california-coast/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[California Coastal Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14117</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night Alison and I along with others were honored for environmental leadership by the California League of Conservation Voters. Here are the remarks I made. &#8212;&#8212; Alison and I both grew up on the East Coast but we’ve been fortunate to live in California for 30 years.  One of the things we love most about living here [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14117&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/clcv-enviro-awards.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-14124" alt="CLCV Enviro Awards" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/clcv-enviro-awards.png?w=266&#038;h=270" width="266" height="270" /></a>Last night Alison and I along with others were honored for environmental leadership by the <a href="http://www.ecovote.org" target="_blank">California League of Conservation Voters</a>. Here are the remarks I made.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Alison and I both grew up on the East Coast but we’ve been fortunate to live in California for 30 years.  One of the things we love most about living here is how beautiful the natural landscapes are and how close nature is to urban areas.  When we had kids, we began to think about our role in protecting these California landscapes for future generations.</p>
<p>Alison got a head start on me by joining the board of the <a href="http://www.calparks.org" target="_blank">State Parks Foundation</a>. I soon followed by joining the board of <a href="http://www.audubon.org" target="_blank">Audubon</a>, <a href="http://www.openspacetrust.org" target="_blank">Peninsula Open Space Trust</a> and the <a href="http://www.ecovote.org" target="_blank">California League of Conservation Voters</a>. And 6 ½ years ago I was appointed to the <a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/whoweare.html" target="_blank">California Coastal Commission</a>.</p>
<p>As you know, for the last 35 years we’ve been running a science experiment on the California Coast: How would the <a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/coastact.pdf" target="_blank">Coastal Ac</a><a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/coastact.pdf" target="_blank">t</a> affect California’s coastal economy?</p>
<p>The results are now in.</p>
<p>California has some of the most expensive land in the country and as we all know, our economy is organized to extract the maximum revenue and profits from any asset. Visitors are amazed that there aren’t condos, hotels, houses, shopping centers and freeways, wall-to-wall, for most of the length of our state’s coast.<a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/shutterstock_127554866.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-14136" alt="shutterstock_127554866" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/shutterstock_127554866.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>It was the Coastal Act that saved California from looking like the coast of New Jersey.</p>
<p>In 1976 the voters of California wisely supported the Coastal Act and the creation of a <a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/whoweare.html" target="_blank">California Coastal Commission</a> with 2 goals.</p>
<p>First, to maximize public access and public recreational opportunities in the coastal zone while preserving the  rights of private property owners, and</p>
<p>Second, to assure priority for coastal-dependent and coastal-related development over other development on the coast.</p>
<p>For the last three decades, the <a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/" target="_blank">Coastal Commission</a> has upheld these directives while miraculously managing to avoid <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulatory_capture" target="_blank">regulatory capture</a>. It was able to do so because of three forces that sustained it: 1) an uncompromising executive director, 2) a majority of commissioners who looked past local parochial interests and voted for the interests of all Californians, and 3) an environmental community that acted as a tenacious watchdog.</p>
<p>The Commission has been able to stave off the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons" target="_blank">tragedy of the commons</a> for the California coast. Upholding the Coastal Act meant the Commission took unpopular positions upsetting developers who have fought with the agency over seaside projects, homeowners who strongly feel that private property rights unconditionally trump public access, and local governments who believe they should have the final say in what’s right for their community, regardless of its impact on the rest of the state.</p>
<p>During the last three decades, <a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/pd-bio-comments.pdf" target="_blank">Peter Douglas</a> ran the Coastal Commission. Unlike <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Moses">Robert Moses</a> who built modern New York City’s or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baron_Haussmann">Baron Haussmann</a> who built 19<sup>th</sup> century Paris in concrete and steel, the legacy of Peter Douglas is all the things you <i>don’t see</i> in the 1,100 miles of the California coast: wetlands that have not been filled, public access that has not been lost, coastal views that have not been blocked by hotels or condominiums. Douglas did this by standing up to developers, speakers of the state assembly, governors, and others who wanted him to be “reasonable” and to come to a “compromised solution”.</p>
<p>I was appointed to the Coastal Commission by a governor hoping to find a candidate with “green enough” credentials who would be &#8220;reasonable&#8221; and understand how “compromises” are made in California politics.</p>
<p>And for the first few years, I was reasonable.  New development, sure &#8211;just avoid the wetland.  More condos&#8212;OK but watch out for the <a href="http://www.coastal.ca.gov/pubs-subject.html#ESHA" target="_blank">Environmentally Sensitive Habitat Areas</a> (ESHA).</p>
<p>I’m a slow learner but over the last few years, I realized that the coast of California exists as it is because the Commission had an <em>unreasonable</em> leader, who refused the political allure of “compromise” and who managed to keep the commission independent despite enormous pressure. And we as commissioners had to stand up to those pressures and be at times unreasonable in order to not compromise the essence of the Coastal Act.</p>
<p>Unfortunately <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/04/09/us/peter-douglas-defender-of-california-coast-dies-at-69.html?_r=0" target="_blank">Peter Douglas is gone</a> and <i>his unbending vision to save the coast is fading</i>. Some current commissioners seem to want the Commission to be<i> </i>reasonable, and understand the reality of politics. In fact, some may even want a new “reasonable” executive director who will turn the commission into just another regulatory organization driven by the people they are supposed to regulate.</p>
<p>Sadly, even today with the results of an independent commission in front of us, some of our appointing authorities haven’t understood the gift that has been handed them – 100’s of miles of Pacific coastline, much of it unspoiled and accessible to all. And unlike other regulatory agencies, the unspoiled California Coast is finite, and bad decisions are virtually impossible to turn back once a development decision is implemented.</p>
<p>Over the last few years I learned that unless there is a vigilant and engaged public, lobbyists and developers will take over the commission using “<a href="http://www.utsandiego.com/news/2013/may/27/needed-a-sensible-choice-for-the-coastal/" target="_blank">reasonableness</a>” and “fair compromise” as their watch words. It is up to individuals and our environmental organizations to become more active on coastal issues.</p>
<p>As Peter Douglas used to say, the coast is never saved, rather it is being saved every day,&#8221; as an ongoing process.</p>
<p>Unless we insist that our elected officials appoint people who are willing to prioritize the principals of the Coastal Act over both their own careers and the notion of being “reasonable” within the larger ecosystem of day-to-day California Politics, our children may one day look back at pictures of the California coast and wistfully say, “Look what our parents lost.”</p>
<p>Today it was with a feeling of a mission yet to be accomplished, I let the governor know that I am resigning from the Coastal Commission. My work on innovation, job creation and entrepreneurship for the Federal Government is taking an increasing amount of my time.</p>
<p>I’ve had a great time at the Commission. I’ve learned a lot from my fellow commissioners and hope I’ve done my part for my fellow Californians. I’d like to thank my alternate <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/jim-wickett/16/907/562" target="_blank">Jim Wickett</a> on the Commision who has also dedicated his time and uncompromising votes towards carrying out the Coastal Act.</p>
<p>Most of all, I’m proud to have been “<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R2lE3fgj7QA&amp;list=PL2575F9DE5B5F45C1" target="_blank">unreasonable</a>” and “<a href="http://www.westsideobserver.com/2012/soccer.html" target="_blank">uncompromising</a>” in defense of the California Coast. To be anything less risks the loss of what the Coastal Act and Peter Douglas has uniquely brought to all Californians.</p>
<p>Thank you for this award, and I very much appreciate all the support you have provided to me to be able to make my contribution to the California Coast and the Environment.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-14140" alt="Poppies full size" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/poppies-full-size.jpg?w=468&#038;h=285" width="468" height="285" /></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/california-coastal-commission/'>California Coastal Commission</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/conservation/'>Conservation</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14117/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14117/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14117&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/28/in-defense-of-unreasonableness-saving-the-california-coast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/clcv-enviro-awards.png?w=295" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CLCV Enviro Awards</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/shutterstock_127554866.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutterstock_127554866</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/poppies-full-size.jpg?w=468" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Poppies full size</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strangling Innovation: Tesla versus &#8220;Rent Seekers&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/24/tesla-versus-rent-seekers/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/24/tesla-versus-rent-seekers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Companies versus Startups: Durant versus Sloan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Industrial Policy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14018</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The greatest number of jobs is created when startups create a new market &#8211; one where the product or service never existed before or is radically more convenient. Yet this is where startups will run into anti-innovation opponents they may not expect. These opponents have their own name –  “rent seekers” – the landlords of [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14018&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The greatest number of jobs is created when startups create a new market &#8211; one where the product or service never existed before or is radically more convenient. Yet this is where startups will run into <i>anti-innovation</i> opponents they may not expect. These opponents have their own name –  “rent seekers” – the landlords of the status-quo.</p>
<p>Smart startups prepare to face off against rent seekers and map out creative strategies for doing so&#8230;. First, however, they need to understand what a rent seeker is and how they operate&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>Recently, the New York and North Carolina legislatures considered a new law written by <a href="http://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/totals.php?id=D000000080&amp;cycle=2012" target="_blank">Auto Dealer lobbyists</a> that would make it illegal for <a href="http://www.teslamotors.com">Tesla</a> to sell cars directly to consumers. This got me thinking about the legal obstacles that face innovators with new business models.</p>
<p>Examples of startups challenging the status quo include: <a href="http://www.lyft.me">Lyft</a>, <a href="https://squareup.com" target="_blank">Square</a>, <a href="https://www.uber.com">Uber</a>, <a href="https://www.airbnb.com">Airbnb</a>, <a href="http://www.spacex.com">SpaceX</a>, <a href="http://www.zillow.com/">Zillow</a>, <a href="http://bitcoin.org/en/" target="_blank">Bitcoin</a>, <a href="http://www.legalzoom.com" target="_blank">LegalZoom</a>, food trucks, <a href="http://www.publiccharters.org/About-Charter-Schools/What-are-Charter-Schools003F.aspx">charter schools</a>, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course">massively open online courses</a>. Past examples of startups that succeeded in redefining current industries include <a href="http://www.craigslist.org/about/sites">Craigslist,</a> <a href="https://signup.netflix.com">Netflix</a>, Amazon, <a href="http://www.ebay.com">Ebay</a> and <a href="https://www.paypal.com">Paypal</a>.</p>
<p>While <a href="http://www.teslamotors.com">Tesla</a>, <a href="http://www.lyft.me">Lyft</a>, <a href="https://www.uber.com">Uber</a>, <a href="https://www.airbnb.com">Airbnb</a>, et al are in very different industries, they have two things in common: 1) they’re disruptive business models creating new markets and upsetting the status quo and 2) the legal obstacles confronting them <i>weren’t from direct competitors</i>, but from groups commonly referred to as “rent seekers.”</p>
<p><b>Rent Seekers<br />
</b><a href="http://blog.bearing-consulting.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/The.Political.Economy.of_.the_.Rent-Seeking.Society.pdf" target="_blank"><i>Rent seekers </i></a>are individuals or organizations that have succeeded with existing business models and look to the government and regulators as their first line of defense against innovative competition. They use government regulation and lawsuits to keep out new entrants with more innovative business models. They use every argument from public safety to lack of quality or loss of jobs to lobby against the new entrants. Rent seekers spend money to increase their share of an existing market instead of creating new products or markets. The key idea is that rent seeking behavior creates <i>nothing of value</i>.</p>
<p>These barriers to new innovative entrants are called <i>economic rent. </i>Examples of economic rent include state automobile franchise laws, taxi medallion laws, limits on charter schools, auto, steel or sugar tariffs, patent trolls, bribery of government officials, corruption and regulatory capture. They’re all part of the same pattern &#8211; they add no value to the economy and prevent innovation from reaching the consumer.</p>
<p><strong>No regulation?<br />
</strong>Not all government regulation is rent or rent seeking. Not all economic rents are bad. Patents for example, provide protection for a limited time only, to allow businesses to recoup R&amp;D expenses as well as make a profit that would often not be possible if completely free competition were allowed immediately upon a products’ release. But <a href="https://www.eff.org/issues/resources-patent-troll-victims" target="_blank">patent trolls</a> emerged as rent seekers by using patents as legalized extortion of companies.</p>
<p><b>How do Rent Seekers win?<br />
</b>Instead of offering better products or better service at lower prices, rent seekers <a href="http://www.opensecrets.org/lobby/" target="_blank">hire lawyers and lobbyists</a> to influence politicians and regulators to pass laws, write regulations and collect taxes that block competition. The process of getting the government to give out these favors is <em>rent-seeking</em>.</p>
<p>Rent seeking lobbyists go directly to legislative bodies (Congress, State Legislatures, City Councils) to persuade government officials to enact laws and regulations in exchange for campaign <a href="http://www.opensecrets.org/industries/" target="_blank">contributions</a>, appeasing influential voting blocks or <a href="http://www.opensecrets.org/revolving/" target="_blank">future jobs in the regulated industry</a>. They also <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2013/06/04/taking-patent-trolls-protect-american-innovation" target="_blank">use the courts to tie up and exhaust a startups</a> limited financial resources.</p>
<p>Lobbyists also work through regulatory bodies like <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/johncassidy/2013/05/tom--wheeler-federal-communications-commission.html" target="_blank">FCC</a>, <a href="http://www.thenation.com/blog/172147/secret-money-lobbyists-fight-sec-disclosure-rule" target="_blank">SEC</a>, <a href="http://www.ftc.gov" target="_blank">FTC</a>, Public Utility, Taxi, or Insurance Commissions, School Boards, etc.   Although most regulatory bodies are initially set up to protect the public’s health and safety, or to provide an equal playing field, <a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/2566926?uid=3739256&amp;uid=2129&amp;uid=2&amp;uid=70&amp;uid=4&amp;sid=21102323655501" target="_blank">o</a><a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/2566926?uid=3739256&amp;uid=2129&amp;uid=2&amp;uid=70&amp;uid=4&amp;sid=21102323655501" target="_blank">ver time</a> the very people they’re supposed to regulate <a href="http://qje.oxfordjournals.org/content/106/4/1089.short" target="_blank">capture the regulatory agencies</a>. Rent Seekers take advantage of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulatory_capture" target="_blank">regulatory capture</a> to protect their interests against the new innovators.</p>
<p><strong>PayPal &#8211; Dodging Bullets<br />
</strong>PayPal consistently walked a fine line with regulators. Early on the company shutdown their commercial banking operation to avoid being labeled as a commercial bank and <a href="http://www.business.auburn.edu/~barthjr/publications/Bank%20Regulation%20in%20the%20United%20States.pdf" target="_blank">burdened by banks&#8217; federal regulations</a>. PayPal worried that complying with state-by-state laws for <a href="http://www.moneytransmitterlaw.com" target="_blank">money transmission</a> would also be too burdensome for a startup so they first tried to be classified as a <a href="http://corporate.findlaw.com/law-library/trust-companies.html" target="_blank">chartered trust company</a> to provide a benign regulatory cover, but failed. As the company grew larger, incumbent banks forced PayPal to register in each state. The banks lobbied <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2002/feb/12/business/fi-paypal12" target="_blank">regulators in Louisiana</a>, <a href="http://news.cnet.com/N.Y.-subpoenas-PayPal-over-gambling/2100-1017_3-943533.html" target="_blank">New York</a>, California, and Idaho and soon they were issuing injunctions forcing PayPal to delay their IPO. Ironically, once PayPal complied with state regulations by registering as a &#8220;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Money_transmitter" target="_blank">money transmitter</a>&#8221; on a state-by-state basis, it created a barrier to entry for future new entrants.</p>
<p><b>U.S. Auto Makers &#8211; Death by Rent Seeking<br />
</b>The U.S. auto industry is a textbook case of rent seeking behavior. In 1981 unable to compete with the quality and price of Japanese cars, the domestic car companies convinced the U.S. government to restrict the import of  “foreign” cars. The result? Americans paid <a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/2534518?uid=3739256&amp;uid=2129&amp;uid=2&amp;uid=70&amp;uid=4&amp;sid=21102323655501" target="_blank">an extra $5 billion for cars</a>. Japan overcame these barriers by using their import quotas to ship high-end, high-margin luxury cars, establishing manufacturing plants in the U.S. for high-volume lower cost cars and by continuing to innovate. In contrast, U.S. car manufacturers raised prices, pocketed the profits, bought off the unions with unsustainable contracts, ran inefficient factories and stopped innovating. The bill came due two decades later as the American auto industry spiraled into bankruptcy and its market share plummeted from 75% in 1981 to 45% in 2012.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-14097" alt="unplug tesla" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/unplug-tesla.jpg?w=150&#038;h=118" width="150" height="118" /></p>
<p><b>Innovation in the Auto Industry<br />
</b>According to the Gallup Poll American consumers view <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/1654/honesty-ethics-professions.aspx" target="_blank">car salesman as dead last in honesty and ethics</a>. Yet when Tesla provided consumers with a direct sales alternative, the rent seekers &#8211; the <a href="http://www.nada.org" target="_blank">National Auto Dealers Association</a> turned its lobbyists loose on State Legislatures robbing consumers in North Carolina, New York and Texas of choice in the marketplace.</p>
<p>In these states it appears innovation be damned if it gets in the way of a rent seeker with a good lobbyist.</p>
<p>Much like Paypal, it&#8217;s likely that after forcing Tesla to win these state-by-state battles, the auto dealers will have found that they dealt themselves the losing hand.</p>
<p><b>Rent seeking is bad for the economy<br />
</b>Rent seeking strangles innovation in its crib. When companies are protected from competition, they have little incentive to cut costs or to pay attention to changing customer needs. The resources invested in rent seeking are a form of economic waste and reduce the wealth of the overall economy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.econlib.org/library/Enc/bios/Schumpeter.html" target="_blank">Schumpeter&#8217;s</a> theory of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creative_destruction" target="_blank">creative destruction</a> - that entry by entrepreneurs was the <a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w3223" target="_blank">disruptive force that sustained economic growth</a> even as it destroyed the value of established companies &#8211; didn&#8217;t take into account that countries with lots of rent-seeking activity (pick your favorite nation where bribes and corruption are the cost of doing business) or dominated by organized interest groups tend to be the economic losers. <em>As rent-seeking becomes more attractive than innovation, <a href="http://www.vietfin.net/wp-content/uploads/Why-is-rent-seeking-so-costly-to-society-1993.pdf" target="_blank">the economy falls into decline</a></em>.</p>
<p>Startups, investors and the public have done a poor job of calling out the politicians and regulators who use the words &#8220;innovation means jobs&#8221; while supporting rent seekers.</p>
<p><b>What does this mean for startups?<br />
</b>In an existing market it’s clear who your competitors are. You compete for customers on performance, ease of use, or price. However, for startups creating a new market &#8211; one where either the product or service never existed before or the new option is radically more convenient for customers -  the idea that rent seekers even exist may come as a shock. “Why would anyone not want a better x, y or z?” The answer is that if your startup threatens their jobs or profits, it doesn&#8217;t matter how much better life will be for consumers, students, etc. Well organized incumbents will fight if they perceive a threat to the status quo<i>.</i></p>
<p>As a result disrupting the status quo in regulated market can be costly. On the other hand, being a private and small startup means you have less to lose when you challenge the incumbents.</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/impossible.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-14101" alt="impossible" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/impossible.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" width="300" height="199" /></a>If you’re a startup with a disruptive business model here’s what you need to do:</p>
<p><i>Map the order of battle</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Laughing at the dinosaurs and saying, “They don’t get it” may put you out of business. Expect that existing organizations will defend their turf ferociously i.e. movie studios, telecom providers, teachers unions, etc.</li>
<li>Understand who has political and regulator influence and where they operate</li>
<li>Figure out an “under the radar” strategy which doesn&#8217;t attract incumbents lawsuits, regulations or laws when you have limited resources to fight back</li>
</ul>
<p><i>Pick early markets where the rent seekers are weakest and scale</i></p>
<ul>
<li>For example, pick target markets with no national or state lobbying influence. i.e. Craigslist versus newspapers, Netflix versus video rental chains, Amazon versus bookstores, etc.</li>
<li>Go after rapid scale of passionate consumers who value the disruption i.e. Uber and Airbnb, Tesla</li>
<li>Ally with some larger partners who see you as a way to break the incumbents lock on the market. i.e. <a href="http://www.palantir.com">Palantir</a> and the intelligence agencies <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2012/08/palantir/" target="_blank">versus the Army</a> and <a href="http://www-01.ibm.com/software/city-operations/defense-national-security/index.html">IBM’s i2</a>, / Textron Systems <a href="http://www.overwatch.com">Overwatch</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>AirBnb &#8211; Damn the torpedoes full speed ahead</strong><br />
For example, Airbnb, thrives even though almost all of its “hosts” are not paying local motel/hotel taxes nor paying tax on their income, and many hosts are violating local zoning laws. Some investors and competitors may be concerned about regulatory risk and liability.  AirBNB’s attitude seems to be “build the business until someone stops me, and change or comply with regulations later.”  This is the same approach that allowed Amazon to ignore local sales taxes for the last two decades.</p>
<p><i>When you get customer scale and raise a large financing round</i>, take the battle to the incumbents. Strategies at this stage include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hire your own lobbyists</li>
<li>Begin to build your own influence and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_action_committee">political action groups</a></li>
<li>Publicly shame the incumbents as rent seekers</li>
<li>Use competition among governments to your advantage, eg, if  New York or North Carolina doesn’t want Tesla, put the store in New Jersey, across the river from Manhattan, increasing New Jersey&#8217;s tax revenue</li>
<li>Cut deals with the rent seekers. i.e. revenue/profit sharing, two-tier hiring, etc.</li>
<li>Buy them out i.e. guaranteed lifetime employment</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Lessons Learned</b></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li><i>Rent seekers </i>are organizations that have lost the ability to innovate</li>
<li>They<i> </i>look to the government to provide their defense against innovation</li>
<li>Map the order of battle</li>
<li>Pick early markets and scale</li>
<li>With cash, take the battle to the incumbent</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the post here: <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14018_14-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> or download the Podcast <a href="http://clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/big-companies-versus-startups-durant-versus-sloan/'>Big Companies versus Startups: Durant versus Sloan</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/marketing/'>Marketing</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/science-and-industrial-policy/'>Science and Industrial Policy</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14018/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14018/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14018&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/24/tesla-versus-rent-seekers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>57</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" length="14075382" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/unplug-tesla.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unplug tesla</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/impossible.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">impossible</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130624.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lean LaunchPad Educators Class</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/18/the-lean-launchpad-educators-class/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/18/the-lean-launchpad-educators-class/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lean LaunchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=14007</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is nothing more powerful than an idea whose time has come Victor Hugo The Lean LaunchPad entrepreneurship curriculum has caught fire. This week 100 educators from around the world will come to Stanford to learn how to teach it. &#8212;&#8211; Life is full of unintended consequences. Ten years ago I started thinking about why [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14007&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><i>There is nothing more powerful than an idea</i><i> whose time has come</i></p>
<p align="center">Victor Hugo</p>
<p>The Lean LaunchPad entrepreneurship curriculum has caught fire. This week 100 educators from around the world will come to Stanford to learn how to teach it.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>Life is full of unintended consequences.</p>
<p>Ten years ago I started thinking about why startups are different from existing companies.  I wondered if business plans and 5-year forecasts were the right way to plan a startup.  I asked, “Is execution all there is to starting a company?”</p>
<p>It dawned on me that the plans were a symptom of a larger problem: we were <i>executing business <span style="text-decoration:underline;">plans</span> when we should first be searching for business <span style="text-decoration:underline;">models</span>.</i> We were putting the plan before the planning.</p>
<p>So what would a search process for a business model look like? I read a ton of existing literature and came up with a formal methodology for search I called <a href="http://steveblank.com/2012/03/29/nail-the-customer-development-manifesto/" target="_blank">Customer Development</a><i>.</i> I wrote a book about this called the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0976470705/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=wwwsteveblank-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0976470705">Four Steps to the Epiphany</a>.</p>
<p><b>Teaching “Search versus Execution”<br />
</b>In 2003 U.C. Berkeley asked me to teach a class in Customer Development at Haas business school. In 2004 I funded IMVU, a startup by Will Harvey and Eric Ries. As a condition of my investment I insisted Will and Eric take my class at Berkeley. Having Eric in the class was the best investment I ever made. Eric’s insight was that traditional product management and Waterfall development should be replaced by Agile Development. While I had said startups were “Searching” for a business model, I had been a bit vague about what exactly a business model looked like. For the last two decades there was no standard definition. That is until Alexander Osterwalder wrote <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0470876417?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=wwwsteveblank-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0470876417">Business Model Generation</a>.</p>
<p>Finally we had a definition of what it was startups were searching for. Business model design + customer development + agile development is the <i>process</i> that startups use to <i>search</i> for a business model. It’s called the Lean Startup. The sum of these parts is now the cover story of the <a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank">May 2013 Harvard Business Review</a>. Bob Dorf and I wrote a book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984999302/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=wwwsteveblank-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0984999302">The Startup Owners Manual</a> that put all these pieces together.</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/idea-whos-time-has-come.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-14079" alt="Idea who's time has come" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/idea-whos-time-has-come.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>But then I realized rather than just writing about it, or lecturing on Customer Development, we should have a hands-on <i>experiential</i> class. So my book and Berkeley class turned into the Lean LaunchPad class in the Stanford Engineering school. The class emphasizes experiential learning, a flipped classroom and immediate feedback as a way to engage students with real world entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>Students learn by proposing and immediately testing hypotheses. They get out of the classroom and talk to customers, partners and competitors and encounter the chaos and uncertainty of commercializing innovations and creating new ventures.</p>
<p>Then in July 2011, the National Science Foundation <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/03/08/a-new-way-to-teach-entrepreneurship-the-lean-launchpad-at-stanford-class-1/">read my blog posts</a> on the Lean LaunchPad class.  They said scientists had already made a career out of hypotheses testing, and the Lean LaunchPad was simply a scientific method for entrepreneurship. They asked if I could adapt the class to teach scientists who want to commercialize their basic research. The result was the <a href="http://www.nsf.gov/news/special_reports/i-corps/" target="_blank">NSF Innovation Corps</a>, my Lean LaunchPad class now taught at 11 major universities to 400 teams/year. <a href="http://arpa-e.energy.gov" target="_blank">ARPA-E</a> joined the program this year, and in the fall we&#8217;ll teach a Life Science version of the class at <a href="http://www.ucsf.edu" target="_blank">UCSF</a>. And other countries are adopting the class to commercialize their nations scientific output.</p>
<p><b>Unexpected Consequences<br />
</b>One of the most surprising things that came out of the National Science Foundation classes was the reaction of the principal investigators (these were the tenured professors who leading their teams in commercializing their science.)  A sizable number of them went back to their schools and asked, “How come we don’t offer this class to our students?”</p>
<p>While I had open-sourced all my lectures and put them online via <a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/ep245" target="_blank">Udacity</a>, I was getting requests to teach other educators how teach the class.  I wasn&#8217;t sure how to respond, until Jerry Engel, the National Faculty Director of the NSF Innovation Corps suggested we hold an educators class.  So we did. The Lean LaunchPad Educators program is a 3-day program designed for experienced entrepreneurship faculty.  It is a hands-on program where you experience the process, and be given the tools to create, a curriculum and course plan you can put to immediate use.</p>
<p>We offered the first class in August and had 50 attendees, the January class had 70, and the one being held this week we had to cap at 100.</p>
<p>As part of each of the classes we open source our educators guide <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/sblank/lean-launchpad-educators-handbook-sept-2013">here</a></p>
<iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/26203066' width='468' height='384'></iframe>
<p>and all our other tools for educators <a href="http://steveblank.com/slides/">here</a>.</p>
<p><b>Where are we in Entrepreneurial Education?<br />
</b>Entrepreneurial education is in the middle of a major transition.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurship educators are realizing that curricula oriented around business plans and “execution” fail to prepare students for the realities of building or working in startups. Startups are a fundamentally a different activity than managing a business and &#8220;search versus execute&#8221; require very different skills. Therefore entrepreneurial education must teach how to search the uncertainties and unknowns.</p>
<p>Educators are now beginning to build curricula that embrace <i>startup </i>management tools built around “searching for a business model” rather than the “execution of a business model” tools needed in larger companies.</p>
<p>But we&#8217;re just beginning the transition. Like other revolutionary changes there are the early adopters and others who adopt later. For the Lean LaunchPad classes we’ve seen adoption fall into five categories:</p>
<ol>
<li>Those who get how teaching students how to &#8220;search versus execute&#8221; changes our curriculum.
<ul>
<li>They say, &#8220;Here&#8217;s how <i>we are going to add value</i> to what you started.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Those who get how teaching students how to &#8220;search versus execute&#8221; changes our curriculum.
<ul>
<li>They say, &#8220;We&#8217;re teaching the Lean Launchpad class as is. Thanks!&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Those who get that there is a major shift in entrepreneurial education occurring and we understand business model design + customer development + agile engineering is at it&#8217;s core
<ul>
<li>They say, &#8220;We are going to rename each of these components so we can take credit for them at our business school.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Those who are not changing anything
<ul>
<li>They say, &#8220;We don&#8217;t buy it.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Those who really don&#8217;t understand the key concepts but we need to be &#8220;buzzword compliant&#8221; to seem relevant
<ul>
<li>They say, &#8220;We&#8217;re throwing Lean on top of our &#8220;how to write a business plan&#8221; and other standard classes.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>The good news is that it’s the marketplace that will eventually drive all schools to adopt experiential classes that teach Lean principles. We&#8217;re incredibly proud of those educators who already have.<br />
<i>There is nothing more powerful than an idea</i><i> whose time has come</i></p>
<p>The next Lean LaunchPad Educators Class will be held in New York, September 25-27<sup>th</sup>. Info <a href="http://nciia.org/LLP" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll also offer a version for incubators and accelerators in New York, September 22-24<sup>th</sup>. info@kandsranch.com</p>
<p><b>Lessons Learned</b></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Entrepreneurial education is in the middle of a major transition</li>
<li>Transition from startups are a smaller version of a large company, teaching execution</li>
<li>To teaching that startups search for a business model</li>
<li>Business model design + customer development + agile development is the <i>process</i> that startups use to <i>search</i> for a business model</li>
<li>Lean LaunchPad is an experiential class that teaches students how to search
<ul>
<li>It’s part of a broader new entrepreneurial curriculum</li>
<li>We teach this in the Lean LaunchPad Educators Class</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the post here: <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-14007_15-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130618.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130618.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130618.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> or download the Podcast <a href="http://clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development/'>Customer Development</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/lean-launchpad/'>Lean LaunchPad</a>, <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/teaching/'>Teaching</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14007/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/14007/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=14007&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/18/the-lean-launchpad-educators-class/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130618.mp3" length="9637491" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/idea-whos-time-has-come.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Idea who&#039;s time has come</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130618.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130618.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fund Raising is a Means Not an End</title>
		<link>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/11/fund-raising-is-a-means-not-an-end/</link>
		<comments>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/11/fund-raising-is-a-means-not-an-end/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 13:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[steveblank]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steveblank.com/?p=13960</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Not all that glitters is gold William Shakespeare For many entrepreneurs “raising money” has replaced “building a sustainable business” as their goal.  That’s a big mistake. When you take money from investors their business model becomes yours. &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211; One of my ex students came out to the ranch to give me an update on his [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=13960&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">Not all that glitters is gold<br />
<i>William Shakespeare</i></p>
<p>For many entrepreneurs “raising money” has replaced “building a sustainable business” as their goal.  That’s a big mistake. When you take money from investors their business model becomes yours.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>One of my ex students came out to the ranch to give me an update on his startup. When I asked, “What are you working on?” the first words out of his mouth was his fund raising progress.  Sigh… What I should have been hearing is the search for the business model, specifically the progress on product/market fit, but I hear the fund raising story first at least 90% of the time.  It never makes me happy.</p>
<p><a href="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/shutterstock_2694848.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-13963" alt="shutterstock_2694848" src="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/shutterstock_2694848.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a>Entrepreneurs need to think about 1) <i>when</i> to raise money, 2) <i>why</i> to raise money and 3) <i>who</i> to take money from, 4) the <i>consequences</i> of raising money.</p>
<p>It all starts with understanding what a startup is.</p>
<p><b>What’s a Startup? </b>Just as a reminder, a startup is <i>a temporary organization designed to search for a repeatable and scalable business model</i>.  It’s worth parsing this sentence:</p>
<p>•  <b>Temporary Organization:</b><i> </i>The goal of a startup is not to remain a startup. The goal is to scale.  (If you don’t have scale as a goal then you shouldn’t be raising money from angel or venture investors, you should be getting a commercial or government small business loan.)</p>
<p>•  <b>Search.</b> Although you believe your idea is the most brilliant innovation ever thought of, the odds are that you are wrong. If you raise millions of dollars on day one, simply executing the idea means you’re going to waste all those dollars attempting to scale a bad idea.</p>
<p>•  <b>Repeatable:</b><i> </i>Startups may get orders that come from board members’ customer relationships or heroic, single-shot efforts of the CEO. These are great, but they are not repeatable by a sales organization. What you are searching for is not the one-off revenue hits but rather a repeatable pattern that can be replicated by a sales organization selling off a pricelist or by customers coming to your web site.</p>
<p>•  <b>Scalable:</b> The goal is not to get one customer but many – and to get those customers so each additional customer adds incremental revenue <i>and</i> profit. The test is:<i> </i>If you add one more sales person or spend more marketing dollars, does your sales revenue go up by more than your expenses?</p>
<p>•  <b>Business model</b>: A business model answers the basic questions about your <span style="text-decoration:underline;">entire</span> business: Who are the customers? What problems do they want solved? Does our product or service solve a customer problem (product-market fit)? How do we attract, keep and grow customers? What are revenue strategy and pricing tactics? Who are the partners? What are the resources and activities needed to make this business happen? And what are its costs?</p>
<p><b>Who to take money from?<br />
</b>First, decide <a href="http://steveblank.com/2011/09/01/why-governments-don%E2%80%99t-get-startups/" target="_blank">what type of startup</a> you are.  If you’re a lifestyle entrepreneur or a small business, odds are the return you can provide is not what traditional angel or venture investors are looking for.  These types of startups are better suited to raising money from friends, family, commercial and government small business loans, etc.</p>
<p>If you’re a scalable startup, you want to spend small amounts of money (seed capital) as you run experiments testing your hypotheses. Why small amounts? No startup ever spends less then it raises. And at this early stage you’ll be giving up a larger percentage of your firm to investors. A seed round can come from friends, family, Kickstarter, angels – and most importantly, early customers<i>.</i></p>
<p>These sources are a lot more forgiving of iterations and pivots than later-stage venture-capital funds.</p>
<p><b>When to raise money<br />
</b>In a <a href="https://archive.harvardbusiness.org/cla/web/pl/product.seam?c=25903&amp;i=25905&amp;cs=f85785d3580feb87e2bce1535af10c2f" target="_blank">Lean Startup</a>, the goal is to <i>preserve your cash until you find a repeatable and scalable business model</i>. In times of unlimited cash (internet bubbles, frothy venture climates) you can fix your mistakes by burning more dollars. In normal times, when there aren’t dollars to undo mistakes, you use <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Four-Steps-Epiphany-Steven-Blank/dp/0976470705">Customer Development</a> to find product-market fit.  It’s only after you have found product-market fit (value proposition – customer segment in the language of the business model canvas) that you spend like there is no tomorrow.<b></b></p>
<p>Don’t confuse “raising money” with “building a sustainable business.” In a perfect world, you would never need investors and would fund the company from customer revenue.  But to achieve scale, startups need risk capital.</p>
<p>Raise as much money as you can <em>after</em> you have tangible evidence you have product/market fit, not before.</p>
<p><b>The consequences of raising venture money<br />
</b>The day you raise money from a venture investor, you’ve also just agreed to their business model.<b></b></p>
<p>Here’s a simple test: If you’re the founder of a startup, go to a whiteboard and diagram how a VC fund works.  How do the fund and the partners make money? What is an IRR? How long is a fund’s life? How much will they invest in the life of your company? How much do they need to own at a liquidity event?  What’s a win for them? Why?</p>
<p>There are two reasons to take venture money. The first is to scale like there is no tomorrow. You invest the dollars to create end-user demand and drive those customers into your sales channel.</p>
<p>The second is the experience, pattern recognition and contacts that great investors bring to the table.</p>
<p>Just make sure it’s the right time.</p>
<p><b>Lessons Learned</b></p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Fund raising is a means not an end</li>
<li>Preserve your cash until you find a repeatable and scalable business model
<ul>
<li>Focus on product – market fit</li>
<li>Run small experiments testing your hypotheses</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Raise as much money as you can <em>after</em> you have tangible evidence you have product/market fit</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Listen to the post here: <span style='text-align:left;display:block;'><p>				<object id='wp-as-13960_16-flash' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' data='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' width='290' height='24'>
					<param name='movie' value='http://s0.wp.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf' />
					<param name='FlashVars' value='bg=0xF8F8F8&amp;leftbg=0xEEEEEE&amp;lefticon=0x666666&amp;rightbg=0xCCCCCC&amp;rightbghover=0x999999&amp;righticon=0x666666&amp;righticonhover=0xFFFFFF&amp;text=0x666666&amp;slider=0x666666&amp;track=0xFFFFFF&amp;border=0x666666&amp;loader=0x9FFFB8&amp;soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Ftraffic.libsyn.com%2Falbedrio%2Fsteveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3' />
					<param name='quality' value='high' />
					<param name='menu' value='false' />
					<param name='bgcolor' value='#FFFFFF' />
					<param name='wmode' value='opaque' />
					Download: <a href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3">steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3</a><br />
				</object></p></span> Download the Podcast <a href="http://clearshore.net" target="_blank">here</a></p><br />Filed under: <a href='http://steveblank.com/category/venture-capital/'>Venture Capital</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/steveblank.wordpress.com/13960/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/steveblank.wordpress.com/13960/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=steveblank.com&#038;blog=6599589&#038;post=13960&#038;subd=steveblank&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steveblank.com/2013/06/11/fund-raising-is-a-means-not-an-end/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3" length="7685204" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb078b89e9979442056262311f9d21c2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Blank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/shutterstock_2694848.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutterstock_2694848</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://steveblank.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://traffic.libsyn.com/albedrio/steveblank_clearshore_130611.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
